<archimate:ApplicationService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="e-Signature Creation"
    id="id-55a94fda3d494ccfaa5d599a6a27f63e"
    documentation="Definition: e-Signature Creation ABB is an Application Service that enables the process of signing data, in electronic form by a natural person&#xA;&#xA;Source: eIDAS - REGULATION (EU) No 910/2014 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 23 July 2014 on electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the internal market and repealing Directive 1999/93/EC. &#xA;&#xA;Source reference: http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv%3AOJ.L_.2014.257.01.0073.01.ENG&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: An ‘electronic signature’ means data in electronic form which is attached to or logically associated with other data in electronic form and which is used by the signatory to sign.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The following implementation is an example on how this specific Architecture Building Block (ABB) can be instantiated as a Solution Building Block (SBB): CEF eSignature DSS - DSS (Digital Signature Services) is an open-source software library for electronic signature creation and validation. DSS supports the creation and verification of interoperable and secure electronic signatures in line with European legislation. In particular, DSS aims to follow the eIDAS Regulation and related standards closely. DSS can be re-used in an IT solution for electronic signatures to ensure that signatures are created and verified in line with European legislation and standards. DSS allows re-use in a variety of different ways: in an applet, in a stand-alone application or in a server application. DSS can also be used as a reference implementation for IT solutions which do not directly re-use it. CEF eSignature's DSS open-source library delivers the following benefits to its users: •&#x9;Open-source software under LGPL 2.1, a non-viral open source license; •&#x9;Interoperability of the e-signatures; •&#x9;Supports both e-signatures and e-seals; •&#x9;Validation of countersignatures and multiple signatures; •&#x9;Alignment with the eIDAS Regulation and related standards; •&#x9;Supports EU standards on: o&#x9;Signature formats and packaging methods;  o&#x9;Signature validation procedures; •&#x9;Validation relying on Member States' trusted lists: o&#x9;Status of trust service providers/trust service, compensation of information, path validation. https://ec.europa.eu/cefdigital/wiki/display/CEFDIGITAL/eSignaturefile:///C:/Users/bocquilp/Downloads/DSS(ServiceOfferingDescription)%20(v0.03)%20(5).pdf&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Dimension: Structural IoP&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Technical view - application&#xA;&#xA;Viewpoint: Interoperability Security viewpoint&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Saliency: The e-Signature Creation Service ABB  is salient for technical interoperability because it provides the functionalities required for e-signature creation service.&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/E-SignatureCreationApplicationService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:E-SignatureCreationApplicationService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/E-SignatureCreationApplicationService&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: TechnicalApplication&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/E-SignatureCreationApplicationService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:E-SignatureCreationApplicationService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:synonym"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="e-Signature Creation ABB is an Application Service that enables the process of signing data, in electronic form by a natural person"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="eIDAS - REGULATION (EU) No 910/2014 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 23 July 2014 on electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the internal market and repealing Directive 1999/93/EC. "/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv%3AOJ.L_.2014.257.01.0073.01.ENG"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The following implementation is an example on how this specific Architecture Building Block (ABB) can be instantiated as a Solution Building Block (SBB): CEF eSignature DSS - DSS (Digital Signature Services) is an open-source software library for electronic signature creation and validation. DSS supports the creation and verification of interoperable and secure electronic signatures in line with European legislation. In particular, DSS aims to follow the eIDAS Regulation and related standards closely. DSS can be re-used in an IT solution for electronic signatures to ensure that signatures are created and verified in line with European legislation and standards. DSS allows re-use in a variety of different ways: in an applet, in a stand-alone application or in a server application. DSS can also be used as a reference implementation for IT solutions which do not directly re-use it. CEF eSignature's DSS open-source library delivers the following benefits to its users: •&#x9;Open-source software under LGPL 2.1, a non-viral open source license; •&#x9;Interoperability of the e-signatures; •&#x9;Supports both e-signatures and e-seals; •&#x9;Validation of countersignatures and multiple signatures; •&#x9;Alignment with the eIDAS Regulation and related standards; •&#x9;Supports EU standards on: o&#x9;Signature formats and packaging methods;  o&#x9;Signature validation procedures; •&#x9;Validation relying on Member States' trusted lists: o&#x9;Status of trust service providers/trust service, compensation of information, path validation. https://ec.europa.eu/cefdigital/wiki/display/CEFDIGITAL/eSignaturefile:///C:/Users/bocquilp/Downloads/DSS(ServiceOfferingDescription)%20(v0.03)%20(5).pdf"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:iopSaliency"
      value="The e-Signature Creation Service ABB  is salient for technical interoperability because it provides the functionalities required for e-signature creation service."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="An ‘electronic signature’ means data in electronic form which is attached to or logically associated with other data in electronic form and which is used by the signatory to sign."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:iopDimension"
      value="Structural IoP"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Technical view - application"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:viewpoint"
      value="Interoperability Security viewpoint"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/E-SignatureCreationApplicationService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="TechnicalApplication"/>
</archimate:ApplicationService>
