<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="ePayment"
    id="id-f832d16752684180a2f5f578a6e74325"
    documentation="Definition: ePayment within the context of IT interoperability refers to the digital payment system implemented in a digital public service by the European Commission. It enables users to make secure and convenient electronic payments for various services provided by the Commission. This system ensures seamless integration and compatibility with different IT systems, allowing users to make payments electronically without any technical barriers or compatibility issues. By leveraging ePayment, the European Commission aims to enhance the efficiency, accessibility, and user experience of its digital public services while promoting interoperability across different platforms and systems.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: ePayment, within the context of IT interoperability, refers to the electronic payment system implemented in a digital public service provided by the European Commission. It is a secure and efficient method of making financial transactions electronically, allowing users to pay for various services or products online.&#xA;&#xA;The ePayment system is designed to ensure seamless interoperability between different IT systems, enabling users to make payments using various electronic methods such as credit/debit cards, online banking, mobile wallets, or other digital payment solutions. It aims to provide a standardized and user-friendly payment experience across different digital platforms and services offered by the European Commission.&#xA;&#xA;One of the primary objectives of ePayment is to enhance the accessibility and convenience of digital public services by eliminating the need for physical cash transactions or traditional payment methods. By offering a range of electronic payment options, users can easily and securely make payments from anywhere, at any time, using their preferred payment method.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the security and privacy of users' financial information, the ePayment system incorporates robust encryption and authentication mechanisms. It adheres to industry standards and best practices to protect sensitive data during transmission and storage. Additionally, it complies with relevant data protection regulations, safeguarding users' personal and financial information.&#xA;&#xA;The ePayment system also focuses on promoting interoperability among different digital platforms and services within the European Commission's digital ecosystem. It enables seamless integration with other IT systems, allowing users to make payments across various digital channels without the need for separate registrations or authentication processes. This interoperability ensures a consistent and unified payment experience for users, regardless of the specific digital service they are utilizing.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the ePayment system supports multi-currency transactions, accommodating users from different countries within the European Union. It provides real-time currency conversion and ensures transparent and fair exchange rates, facilitating cross-border payments and enhancing the accessibility of digital public services for all EU citizens.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, ePayment within the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission is a digital payment system that enables secure, convenient, and standardized electronic transactions for various digital public services. It ensures the interoperability of different IT systems, promotes accessibility, and adheres to stringent security and privacy standards. By offering multiple payment options and supporting multi-currency transactions, ePayment aims to enhance the user experience and facilitate seamless financial transactions within the European Commission's digital ecosystem.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of ePayment within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission could be the implementation of an online tax payment system. This system would allow individuals and businesses to conveniently pay their taxes electronically, ensuring seamless interoperability between different IT systems.&#xA;&#xA;Another example could be the integration of ePayment within an online procurement platform. This platform would enable suppliers to submit electronic invoices and receive payments electronically, streamlining the procurement process and promoting interoperability between various IT systems involved in the procurement cycle.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, ePayment could be utilized in the context of a digital public service for issuing and managing licenses or permits. Citizens or businesses could apply for and pay for licenses or permits online, eliminating the need for manual paperwork and enabling interoperability between different IT systems involved in the licensing process.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, ePayment could be integrated into a digital public service for social welfare benefits. This would allow beneficiaries to receive their payments electronically, ensuring efficient and secure transfer of funds while promoting interoperability between the IT systems of different government agencies involved in the administration of social welfare programs.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of ePayment within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission can enhance efficiency, convenience, and security in various areas such as tax payments, procurement, licensing, and social welfare benefits administration.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-API Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EPaymentBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:EPaymentBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EPaymentBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: ePayment Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EPaymentBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EPaymentBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="ePayment Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:EPaymentBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of ePayment within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission could be the implementation of an online tax payment system. This system would allow individuals and businesses to conveniently pay their taxes electronically, ensuring seamless interoperability between different IT systems.&#xA;&#xA;Another example could be the integration of ePayment within an online procurement platform. This platform would enable suppliers to submit electronic invoices and receive payments electronically, streamlining the procurement process and promoting interoperability between various IT systems involved in the procurement cycle.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, ePayment could be utilized in the context of a digital public service for issuing and managing licenses or permits. Citizens or businesses could apply for and pay for licenses or permits online, eliminating the need for manual paperwork and enabling interoperability between different IT systems involved in the licensing process.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, ePayment could be integrated into a digital public service for social welfare benefits. This would allow beneficiaries to receive their payments electronically, ensuring efficient and secure transfer of funds while promoting interoperability between the IT systems of different government agencies involved in the administration of social welfare programs.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of ePayment within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission can enhance efficiency, convenience, and security in various areas such as tax payments, procurement, licensing, and social welfare benefits administration."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="ePayment, within the context of IT interoperability, refers to the electronic payment system implemented in a digital public service provided by the European Commission. It is a secure and efficient method of making financial transactions electronically, allowing users to pay for various services or products online.&#xA;&#xA;The ePayment system is designed to ensure seamless interoperability between different IT systems, enabling users to make payments using various electronic methods such as credit/debit cards, online banking, mobile wallets, or other digital payment solutions. It aims to provide a standardized and user-friendly payment experience across different digital platforms and services offered by the European Commission.&#xA;&#xA;One of the primary objectives of ePayment is to enhance the accessibility and convenience of digital public services by eliminating the need for physical cash transactions or traditional payment methods. By offering a range of electronic payment options, users can easily and securely make payments from anywhere, at any time, using their preferred payment method.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the security and privacy of users' financial information, the ePayment system incorporates robust encryption and authentication mechanisms. It adheres to industry standards and best practices to protect sensitive data during transmission and storage. Additionally, it complies with relevant data protection regulations, safeguarding users' personal and financial information.&#xA;&#xA;The ePayment system also focuses on promoting interoperability among different digital platforms and services within the European Commission's digital ecosystem. It enables seamless integration with other IT systems, allowing users to make payments across various digital channels without the need for separate registrations or authentication processes. This interoperability ensures a consistent and unified payment experience for users, regardless of the specific digital service they are utilizing.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the ePayment system supports multi-currency transactions, accommodating users from different countries within the European Union. It provides real-time currency conversion and ensures transparent and fair exchange rates, facilitating cross-border payments and enhancing the accessibility of digital public services for all EU citizens.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, ePayment within the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission is a digital payment system that enables secure, convenient, and standardized electronic transactions for various digital public services. It ensures the interoperability of different IT systems, promotes accessibility, and adheres to stringent security and privacy standards. By offering multiple payment options and supporting multi-currency transactions, ePayment aims to enhance the user experience and facilitate seamless financial transactions within the European Commission's digital ecosystem."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="ePayment within the context of IT interoperability refers to the digital payment system implemented in a digital public service by the European Commission. It enables users to make secure and convenient electronic payments for various services provided by the Commission. This system ensures seamless integration and compatibility with different IT systems, allowing users to make payments electronically without any technical barriers or compatibility issues. By leveraging ePayment, the European Commission aims to enhance the efficiency, accessibility, and user experience of its digital public services while promoting interoperability across different platforms and systems."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-API Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
