<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Credential"
    id="id-00bc3c11dd93474eb265d045f7cb7d8f"
    documentation="Definition: A credential is a piece of any document that details a qualification, competence, or authority issued to an individual by a third party with a relevant or de facto authority or assumed competence to do so.&#xA;&#xA;Source: WikiPedia&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Credential&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: A credential, in the context of information technology (IT), refers to a piece of information or a set of data that is used to authenticate and verify the identity of an individual or entity in order to grant them access to certain resources, systems, or services. It is a crucial component of the authentication process and plays a vital role in ensuring the security and integrity of digital systems.&#xA;&#xA;Credentials are typically associated with user accounts and are used to establish trust and authorization within a system. They can take various forms, including usernames, passwords, personal identification numbers (PINs), security tokens, digital certificates, biometric data, or any combination of these factors. The specific type of credential used depends on the level of security required and the nature of the system or service being accessed.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, credentials are governed by various regulations and standards aimed at protecting personal data and ensuring privacy. For instance, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) sets guidelines for the collection, storage, and processing of personal information, including credentials. Organizations operating within the European Union (EU) are required to adhere to these regulations to safeguard user data and prevent unauthorized access.&#xA;&#xA;The management and storage of credentials are of utmost importance in the European IT context. Organizations must implement robust security measures to protect credentials from unauthorized access, theft, or misuse. This includes employing encryption techniques, secure storage mechanisms, and strong access controls. Additionally, regular audits and vulnerability assessments are conducted to identify and mitigate any potential risks or vulnerabilities in the credential management system.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the European IT context emphasizes the principle of data minimization, which means that organizations should only collect and store the minimum amount of personal data necessary for the intended purpose. This principle applies to credentials as well, where organizations should only request and retain the essential information required for authentication and authorization, while ensuring that the data is adequately protected.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, within the European IT context, a credential is an element or component of information used to authenticate and verify the identity of individuals or entities. It is governed by regulations and standards aimed at protecting personal data and ensuring privacy. Robust security measures and data minimization principles are essential to safeguard credentials and maintain the integrity of digital systems.&#xA;&#xA;Example: Credentials are an essential element or component of information in various applications within the European IT context. They serve as proof of identity, qualifications, and permissions, enabling individuals to access systems, resources, and services. Here are a few examples of how credentials are applied:&#xA;&#xA;1. User Authentication: In the European IT context, credentials are widely used for user authentication. When individuals log in to online platforms, websites, or applications, they are typically required to provide their credentials, such as a username and password. These credentials verify their identity and grant them access to the desired resources or functionalities.&#xA;&#xA;2. Digital Certificates: Digital certificates are a form of credentials used to establish trust and secure communication over networks. Within the European IT context, digital certificates are commonly employed for secure email communication, website authentication (HTTPS), and electronic signatures. These credentials are issued by trusted certification authorities and contain information about the certificate holder, ensuring the authenticity and integrity of digital transactions.&#xA;&#xA;3. Professional Certifications: Credentials play a crucial role in the European IT industry for validating an individual's professional qualifications and expertise. Various organizations and institutions offer certifications in specific IT domains, such as programming languages, network administration, cybersecurity, and project management. These credentials serve as tangible evidence of an individual's skills and knowledge, enhancing their employability and professional growth.&#xA;&#xA;4. Access Control Systems: Credentials are extensively used in access control systems to regulate physical and logical access to buildings, data centers, networks, and sensitive information. Within the European IT context, organizations employ credentials such as smart cards, RFID tags, or biometric data (fingerprint, iris scan) to grant authorized personnel access to restricted areas or confidential data. These credentials ensure that only authorized individuals can enter or access specific resources, enhancing security and privacy.&#xA;&#xA;5. API Authentication: In the European IT context, credentials are also utilized for authenticating and authorizing access to Application Programming Interfaces (APIs). APIs enable different software systems to interact and exchange data. To ensure secure and controlled access, developers often need to obtain credentials, such as API keys or tokens, which authenticate their applications and grant them specific permissions to access and utilize the API's functionalities.&#xA;&#xA;These examples illustrate how credentials serve as vital components of information within the European IT context, enabling secure access, validating qualifications, establishing trust, and enhancing overall information security.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/CredentialBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:CredentialBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/CredentialBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Credential Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/CredentialBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/CredentialBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:CredentialBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Credential Information"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="WikiPedia"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Credential"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="Credentials are an essential element or component of information in various applications within the European IT context. They serve as proof of identity, qualifications, and permissions, enabling individuals to access systems, resources, and services. Here are a few examples of how credentials are applied:&#xA;&#xA;1. User Authentication: In the European IT context, credentials are widely used for user authentication. When individuals log in to online platforms, websites, or applications, they are typically required to provide their credentials, such as a username and password. These credentials verify their identity and grant them access to the desired resources or functionalities.&#xA;&#xA;2. Digital Certificates: Digital certificates are a form of credentials used to establish trust and secure communication over networks. Within the European IT context, digital certificates are commonly employed for secure email communication, website authentication (HTTPS), and electronic signatures. These credentials are issued by trusted certification authorities and contain information about the certificate holder, ensuring the authenticity and integrity of digital transactions.&#xA;&#xA;3. Professional Certifications: Credentials play a crucial role in the European IT industry for validating an individual's professional qualifications and expertise. Various organizations and institutions offer certifications in specific IT domains, such as programming languages, network administration, cybersecurity, and project management. These credentials serve as tangible evidence of an individual's skills and knowledge, enhancing their employability and professional growth.&#xA;&#xA;4. Access Control Systems: Credentials are extensively used in access control systems to regulate physical and logical access to buildings, data centers, networks, and sensitive information. Within the European IT context, organizations employ credentials such as smart cards, RFID tags, or biometric data (fingerprint, iris scan) to grant authorized personnel access to restricted areas or confidential data. These credentials ensure that only authorized individuals can enter or access specific resources, enhancing security and privacy.&#xA;&#xA;5. API Authentication: In the European IT context, credentials are also utilized for authenticating and authorizing access to Application Programming Interfaces (APIs). APIs enable different software systems to interact and exchange data. To ensure secure and controlled access, developers often need to obtain credentials, such as API keys or tokens, which authenticate their applications and grant them specific permissions to access and utilize the API's functionalities.&#xA;&#xA;These examples illustrate how credentials serve as vital components of information within the European IT context, enabling secure access, validating qualifications, establishing trust, and enhancing overall information security."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="A credential, in the context of information technology (IT), refers to a piece of information or a set of data that is used to authenticate and verify the identity of an individual or entity in order to grant them access to certain resources, systems, or services. It is a crucial component of the authentication process and plays a vital role in ensuring the security and integrity of digital systems.&#xA;&#xA;Credentials are typically associated with user accounts and are used to establish trust and authorization within a system. They can take various forms, including usernames, passwords, personal identification numbers (PINs), security tokens, digital certificates, biometric data, or any combination of these factors. The specific type of credential used depends on the level of security required and the nature of the system or service being accessed.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, credentials are governed by various regulations and standards aimed at protecting personal data and ensuring privacy. For instance, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) sets guidelines for the collection, storage, and processing of personal information, including credentials. Organizations operating within the European Union (EU) are required to adhere to these regulations to safeguard user data and prevent unauthorized access.&#xA;&#xA;The management and storage of credentials are of utmost importance in the European IT context. Organizations must implement robust security measures to protect credentials from unauthorized access, theft, or misuse. This includes employing encryption techniques, secure storage mechanisms, and strong access controls. Additionally, regular audits and vulnerability assessments are conducted to identify and mitigate any potential risks or vulnerabilities in the credential management system.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the European IT context emphasizes the principle of data minimization, which means that organizations should only collect and store the minimum amount of personal data necessary for the intended purpose. This principle applies to credentials as well, where organizations should only request and retain the essential information required for authentication and authorization, while ensuring that the data is adequately protected.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, within the European IT context, a credential is an element or component of information used to authenticate and verify the identity of individuals or entities. It is governed by regulations and standards aimed at protecting personal data and ensuring privacy. Robust security measures and data minimization principles are essential to safeguard credentials and maintain the integrity of digital systems."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="A credential is a piece of any document that details a qualification, competence, or authority issued to an individual by a third party with a relevant or de facto authority or assumed competence to do so."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Agnostic Data Policies and Contracts- Data Space"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Semantic view - Motivation"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
