<archimate:BusinessRole
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Solution Architect"
    id="id-ce4a8b7556734f8ea596e2473999de09"
    documentation="Definition: A Solution Architect is a professional who is responsible for designing and managing the implementation of technology solutions to meet specific business needs. They work closely with the business team to understand their requirements and challenges, and then develop a technological solution that addresses those needs. This can involve selecting appropriate technologies, designing system architecture, overseeing development and implementation processes, and ensuring the solution is scalable and sustainable. They also often act as a bridge between technical and non-technical stakeholders, ensuring clear communication and understanding across all parties.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: A Solution Architect is a professional who is responsible for designing and managing the solution engineering in relation to specific business problems. They are a key part of the software development process, bridging the gap between the needs of the business and the technical capabilities of the IT team. &#xA;&#xA;The role of a Solution Architect involves understanding the company's business strategy and identifying the technology systems architecture that will support this strategy. They work closely with both the executive team and the IT team to ensure that the company's technology strategy aligns with its business goals.&#xA;&#xA;Their responsibilities include designing and leading the implementation of a solutions architecture across a range of new and existing technologies, ensuring that the solution aligns with the enterprise architecture of the organization. They also provide technical leadership and support during the sales process, including working with the sales team to propose solutions that meet the needs of potential customers.&#xA;&#xA;Solution Architects are also responsible for conducting research on existing systems and devising solutions that work seamlessly with these systems. They often work with a variety of technologies and, therefore, need to be comfortable with different programming languages and computer hardware.&#xA;&#xA;They also need to be able to communicate effectively with both technical and non-technical stakeholders. This includes explaining complex concepts in a way that is easy for non-technical people to understand, as well as being able to translate business needs into technical requirements for the IT team.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, Solution Architects often play a role in risk management, as they need to identify and mitigate potential risks associated with the proposed solution. This can include anything from security risks to the risk of the solution not being scalable enough to support future growth.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the role of a Solution Architect is a complex and multifaceted one, requiring a combination of technical expertise, business acumen, and excellent communication skills.&#xA;&#xA;Example: 1. Cloud Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing cloud-based systems and services for a company. The architect may work with Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud Platform. They are responsible for understanding the technical requirements of the company and developing a cloud strategy that meets those needs.&#xA;&#xA;2. Enterprise Solution Architect: This role is responsible for overseeing the technological needs of a large organization. They work to align the company's strategic goals with its technology strategy. They often work with various departments within the company to understand their needs and develop solutions to meet those needs.&#xA;&#xA;3. Software Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing software systems. They work closely with software developers and engineers to ensure that the software being developed meets the needs of the company. They are also responsible for troubleshooting any issues that may arise during the development process.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing data systems for a company. They are responsible for understanding the company's data needs and developing a strategy to meet those needs. This may involve designing databases, developing data models, and implementing data governance policies.&#xA;&#xA;5. Infrastructure Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing the physical and virtual resources that support a company's IT systems. This includes servers, storage, networks, and virtualization technologies. They are responsible for ensuring that the infrastructure is scalable, reliable, and secure.&#xA;&#xA;6. Security Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing the security systems for a company. They are responsible for understanding the company's security needs and developing a strategy to meet those needs. This may involve designing firewalls, developing security policies, and implementing security measures.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: [A] How to read the model&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SolutionArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:SolutionArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:None&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-19&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SolutionArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;Name: Solution Architect Business-role&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SolutionArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-19"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SolutionArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:SolutionArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Solution Architect Business-role"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="1. Cloud Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing cloud-based systems and services for a company. The architect may work with Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud Platform. They are responsible for understanding the technical requirements of the company and developing a cloud strategy that meets those needs.&#xA;&#xA;2. Enterprise Solution Architect: This role is responsible for overseeing the technological needs of a large organization. They work to align the company's strategic goals with its technology strategy. They often work with various departments within the company to understand their needs and develop solutions to meet those needs.&#xA;&#xA;3. Software Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing software systems. They work closely with software developers and engineers to ensure that the software being developed meets the needs of the company. They are also responsible for troubleshooting any issues that may arise during the development process.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing data systems for a company. They are responsible for understanding the company's data needs and developing a strategy to meet those needs. This may involve designing databases, developing data models, and implementing data governance policies.&#xA;&#xA;5. Infrastructure Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing the physical and virtual resources that support a company's IT systems. This includes servers, storage, networks, and virtualization technologies. They are responsible for ensuring that the infrastructure is scalable, reliable, and secure.&#xA;&#xA;6. Security Solution Architect: This role involves designing and managing the security systems for a company. They are responsible for understanding the company's security needs and developing a strategy to meet those needs. This may involve designing firewalls, developing security policies, and implementing security measures."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:None"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="A Solution Architect is a professional who is responsible for designing and managing the solution engineering in relation to specific business problems. They are a key part of the software development process, bridging the gap between the needs of the business and the technical capabilities of the IT team. &#xA;&#xA;The role of a Solution Architect involves understanding the company's business strategy and identifying the technology systems architecture that will support this strategy. They work closely with both the executive team and the IT team to ensure that the company's technology strategy aligns with its business goals.&#xA;&#xA;Their responsibilities include designing and leading the implementation of a solutions architecture across a range of new and existing technologies, ensuring that the solution aligns with the enterprise architecture of the organization. They also provide technical leadership and support during the sales process, including working with the sales team to propose solutions that meet the needs of potential customers.&#xA;&#xA;Solution Architects are also responsible for conducting research on existing systems and devising solutions that work seamlessly with these systems. They often work with a variety of technologies and, therefore, need to be comfortable with different programming languages and computer hardware.&#xA;&#xA;They also need to be able to communicate effectively with both technical and non-technical stakeholders. This includes explaining complex concepts in a way that is easy for non-technical people to understand, as well as being able to translate business needs into technical requirements for the IT team.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, Solution Architects often play a role in risk management, as they need to identify and mitigate potential risks associated with the proposed solution. This can include anything from security risks to the risk of the solution not being scalable enough to support future growth.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the role of a Solution Architect is a complex and multifaceted one, requiring a combination of technical expertise, business acumen, and excellent communication skills."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="A Solution Architect is a professional who is responsible for designing and managing the implementation of technology solutions to meet specific business needs. They work closely with the business team to understand their requirements and challenges, and then develop a technological solution that addresses those needs. This can involve selecting appropriate technologies, designing system architecture, overseeing development and implementation processes, and ensuring the solution is scalable and sustainable. They also often act as a bridge between technical and non-technical stakeholders, ensuring clear communication and understanding across all parties."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="[A] How to read the model"/>
</archimate:BusinessRole>
