<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Distribution list"
    id="id-3e58bf21affb4e95aa24a86c8f5e7360"
    documentation="Definition: Distribution List is data about any individual or entity which is a member of and/or is otherwise participating in a Network.&#xA;&#xA;Source: WhatIs.com&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/definition/distribution-list&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: A distribution list, in the context of information technology, refers to a feature or component that allows users to send messages or information to a predefined group of recipients simultaneously. It is commonly used in email systems, collaboration platforms, and other communication tools to streamline the process of sending messages to multiple individuals or groups.&#xA;&#xA;In essence, a distribution list acts as a virtual mailing list, enabling users to create a single address that represents multiple recipients. When a message is sent to this address, it is automatically distributed to all the members of the list. This eliminates the need to manually enter each recipient's email address, saving time and effort, particularly when dealing with large groups or frequently changing memberships.&#xA;&#xA;Distribution lists can be created and managed by individuals, teams, or organizations, depending on the specific system or platform being used. They are typically set up and maintained by administrators or designated users who have the necessary permissions to manage the list's membership.&#xA;&#xA;The primary purpose of a distribution list is to facilitate efficient and targeted communication within an organization or community. It allows users to reach a specific group of people with a single message, ensuring that relevant information is disseminated to the right individuals or teams. This is particularly useful in situations where regular updates, announcements, or notifications need to be shared with a specific audience, such as project teams, departments, or interest groups.&#xA;&#xA;Distribution lists can be static or dynamic. Static distribution lists have a fixed membership that needs to be manually updated whenever there are changes in the recipient list. Dynamic distribution lists, on the other hand, are based on predefined criteria or rules, automatically including or excluding recipients based on specific attributes or characteristics. For example, a dynamic distribution list may include all employees from a particular department or all users with a specific job title.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, distribution lists are widely used in various industries and organizations to enhance communication and collaboration. They play a crucial role in facilitating efficient information sharing, ensuring that relevant updates and messages reach the intended recipients promptly. Additionally, distribution lists can be integrated with other IT systems and tools, such as customer relationship management (CRM) software or project management platforms, to streamline workflows and improve overall productivity.&#xA;&#xA;Example: A distribution list, in the context of information management, refers to a group or list of email addresses that are used to send messages or distribute information to multiple recipients simultaneously. It is a commonly used feature in email systems and plays a crucial role in efficient communication within organizations. Here are a few examples of how distribution lists are applied in the European IT context:&#xA;&#xA;1. Internal Communication: In a European IT company, a distribution list can be created for different departments or teams, such as development, marketing, or customer support. This allows for easy and quick dissemination of information within the respective teams. For instance, the marketing team can use a distribution list to share updates on upcoming campaigns, while the development team can use it to discuss technical issues or share project updates.&#xA;&#xA;2. Project Collaboration: Distribution lists are often used to facilitate communication and collaboration among project teams. In a European IT project, a distribution list can be created to include all the project stakeholders, including team members, clients, and external consultants. This enables efficient sharing of project-related information, such as meeting minutes, progress updates, or important announcements. It ensures that everyone involved in the project stays informed and can contribute effectively.&#xA;&#xA;3. Customer Communication: Distribution lists are also utilized for customer communication in the European IT industry. For instance, a software company may maintain a distribution list of its existing customers to send them product updates, new feature releases, or important security patches. This helps in keeping customers informed about the latest developments and ensures they have access to the necessary information to enhance their user experience.&#xA;&#xA;4. Newsletter Subscriptions: Many European IT organizations use distribution lists to manage newsletter subscriptions. Users interested in receiving regular updates, industry news, or promotional offers can subscribe to a distribution list specifically created for newsletters. This allows the organization to send targeted information to the interested audience, ensuring effective communication and engagement.&#xA;&#xA;5. Event Invitations: Distribution lists are commonly employed to send event invitations within the European IT sector. For example, an IT conference organizer may maintain a distribution list of industry professionals, speakers, and sponsors to send them invitations for upcoming events. This simplifies the process of reaching out to a large number of potential attendees and ensures that the event information reaches the relevant individuals.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, distribution lists serve as a valuable component of information management in the European IT context, enabling efficient communication, collaboration, and targeted information dissemination within organizations and to external stakeholders.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DistributionListBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:DistributionListBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DistributionListBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Distribution list Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DistributionListBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DistributionListBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:DistributionListBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Distribution list Information"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="WhatIs.com"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/definition/distribution-list"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="A distribution list, in the context of information management, refers to a group or list of email addresses that are used to send messages or distribute information to multiple recipients simultaneously. It is a commonly used feature in email systems and plays a crucial role in efficient communication within organizations. Here are a few examples of how distribution lists are applied in the European IT context:&#xA;&#xA;1. Internal Communication: In a European IT company, a distribution list can be created for different departments or teams, such as development, marketing, or customer support. This allows for easy and quick dissemination of information within the respective teams. For instance, the marketing team can use a distribution list to share updates on upcoming campaigns, while the development team can use it to discuss technical issues or share project updates.&#xA;&#xA;2. Project Collaboration: Distribution lists are often used to facilitate communication and collaboration among project teams. In a European IT project, a distribution list can be created to include all the project stakeholders, including team members, clients, and external consultants. This enables efficient sharing of project-related information, such as meeting minutes, progress updates, or important announcements. It ensures that everyone involved in the project stays informed and can contribute effectively.&#xA;&#xA;3. Customer Communication: Distribution lists are also utilized for customer communication in the European IT industry. For instance, a software company may maintain a distribution list of its existing customers to send them product updates, new feature releases, or important security patches. This helps in keeping customers informed about the latest developments and ensures they have access to the necessary information to enhance their user experience.&#xA;&#xA;4. Newsletter Subscriptions: Many European IT organizations use distribution lists to manage newsletter subscriptions. Users interested in receiving regular updates, industry news, or promotional offers can subscribe to a distribution list specifically created for newsletters. This allows the organization to send targeted information to the interested audience, ensuring effective communication and engagement.&#xA;&#xA;5. Event Invitations: Distribution lists are commonly employed to send event invitations within the European IT sector. For example, an IT conference organizer may maintain a distribution list of industry professionals, speakers, and sponsors to send them invitations for upcoming events. This simplifies the process of reaching out to a large number of potential attendees and ensures that the event information reaches the relevant individuals.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, distribution lists serve as a valuable component of information management in the European IT context, enabling efficient communication, collaboration, and targeted information dissemination within organizations and to external stakeholders."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="A distribution list, in the context of information technology, refers to a feature or component that allows users to send messages or information to a predefined group of recipients simultaneously. It is commonly used in email systems, collaboration platforms, and other communication tools to streamline the process of sending messages to multiple individuals or groups.&#xA;&#xA;In essence, a distribution list acts as a virtual mailing list, enabling users to create a single address that represents multiple recipients. When a message is sent to this address, it is automatically distributed to all the members of the list. This eliminates the need to manually enter each recipient's email address, saving time and effort, particularly when dealing with large groups or frequently changing memberships.&#xA;&#xA;Distribution lists can be created and managed by individuals, teams, or organizations, depending on the specific system or platform being used. They are typically set up and maintained by administrators or designated users who have the necessary permissions to manage the list's membership.&#xA;&#xA;The primary purpose of a distribution list is to facilitate efficient and targeted communication within an organization or community. It allows users to reach a specific group of people with a single message, ensuring that relevant information is disseminated to the right individuals or teams. This is particularly useful in situations where regular updates, announcements, or notifications need to be shared with a specific audience, such as project teams, departments, or interest groups.&#xA;&#xA;Distribution lists can be static or dynamic. Static distribution lists have a fixed membership that needs to be manually updated whenever there are changes in the recipient list. Dynamic distribution lists, on the other hand, are based on predefined criteria or rules, automatically including or excluding recipients based on specific attributes or characteristics. For example, a dynamic distribution list may include all employees from a particular department or all users with a specific job title.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, distribution lists are widely used in various industries and organizations to enhance communication and collaboration. They play a crucial role in facilitating efficient information sharing, ensuring that relevant updates and messages reach the intended recipients promptly. Additionally, distribution lists can be integrated with other IT systems and tools, such as customer relationship management (CRM) software or project management platforms, to streamline workflows and improve overall productivity."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Distribution List is data about any individual or entity which is a member of and/or is otherwise participating in a Network."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
