<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="eTranslation"
    id="id-9e9af4354ced4bab98e90ee315cd56e0"
    documentation="Definition: eTranslation is a digital public service provided by the European Commission that plays a crucial role in IT interoperability. It is a language translation tool designed to facilitate communication and understanding between different languages within the European Union. eTranslation enables the automatic translation of text documents, websites, and other digital content from one language to another, ensuring that information can be easily accessed and understood by individuals and organizations across linguistic barriers. By promoting multilingualism and breaking down language barriers, eTranslation contributes to the seamless exchange of information and promotes collaboration and cooperation within the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: eTranslation is a sophisticated digital public service offered by the European Commission that plays a crucial role in promoting IT interoperability within the European Union. It is a powerful language translation tool designed to facilitate seamless communication and understanding between individuals, businesses, and public administrations across different linguistic backgrounds.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, eTranslation leverages cutting-edge language technologies and artificial intelligence to provide accurate and efficient translation services. It enables the translation of various types of digital content, including documents, websites, and even software interfaces, ensuring that information can be easily accessed and understood by users regardless of their native language.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of eTranslation is to break down language barriers and foster cross-border collaboration within the European Union. It supports all official languages of the EU member states, as well as several non-official languages, making it a truly inclusive and comprehensive translation solution. By offering translation services in multiple languages, eTranslation promotes multilingualism and ensures that language diversity does not hinder effective communication and cooperation.&#xA;&#xA;eTranslation operates through a secure and user-friendly web interface, allowing users to submit their content for translation and receive the translated output in a matter of seconds or minutes, depending on the complexity of the text. The service employs a combination of machine translation and human post-editing to ensure the highest quality translations. Machine translation algorithms analyze the input text and generate a preliminary translation, which is then reviewed and refined by professional human translators to ensure accuracy, fluency, and cultural appropriateness.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the reliability and consistency of translations, eTranslation incorporates a vast collection of language resources, such as bilingual and multilingual dictionaries, terminology databases, and parallel corpora. These resources are continuously updated and expanded to reflect the evolving nature of languages and to improve the overall translation quality.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, eTranslation adheres to strict data protection and privacy regulations, ensuring that all user data and content remain confidential and secure throughout the translation process. The service operates within the European Commission's secure IT infrastructure, which is designed to safeguard sensitive information and prevent unauthorized access.&#xA;&#xA;eTranslation is not only a standalone service but also an integral part of the European Commission's broader efforts to promote digital transformation and interoperability across its various public services. It is seamlessly integrated with other digital platforms and systems, allowing users to access translation services directly within their existing workflows and applications.&#xA;&#xA;In conclusion, eTranslation is a state-of-the-art digital public service offered by the European Commission, aimed at promoting IT interoperability by breaking down language barriers. It leverages advanced language technologies, machine translation, and human post-editing to provide accurate and efficient translations in multiple languages. By facilitating cross-border communication and collaboration, eTranslation plays a vital role in fostering a more connected and inclusive European Union.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of eTranslation within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission is the automatic translation of software documentation. When developing and implementing IT systems, it is crucial to provide comprehensive documentation to ensure interoperability and facilitate collaboration among different stakeholders. However, this documentation is often available in multiple languages to cater to the diverse linguistic needs of users across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;eTranslation can be utilized to automatically translate software documentation from one language to another, enabling seamless access and understanding for users from different linguistic backgrounds. This ensures that all stakeholders can effectively utilize and contribute to the development and interoperability of the IT systems, regardless of their native language.&#xA;&#xA;Another application of eTranslation in IT interoperability is the translation of user interfaces and software applications. When designing digital public services, it is essential to provide user interfaces that are user-friendly and accessible to individuals from various linguistic backgrounds. By integrating eTranslation, the user interfaces and software applications can be automatically translated into multiple languages, allowing users to interact with the systems in their preferred language.&#xA;&#xA;This application of eTranslation enhances the interoperability of digital public services by eliminating language barriers and ensuring equal access to information and functionalities for all users. It promotes inclusivity and facilitates seamless communication and collaboration among users from different European countries.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eTranslation can be employed for the translation of technical specifications and standards related to IT interoperability. These specifications and standards serve as guidelines for the development and implementation of IT systems, ensuring compatibility and interoperability across different platforms and technologies. By automatically translating these documents, eTranslation enables a wider dissemination and understanding of the technical requirements and standards, fostering harmonization and cooperation among IT professionals and stakeholders across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the application of eTranslation within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission includes automatic translation of software documentation, translation of user interfaces and software applications, and translation of technical specifications and standards. These applications enhance accessibility, inclusivity, and collaboration among users and stakeholders from diverse linguistic backgrounds, ultimately promoting seamless interoperability in the IT domain.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Translation Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETranslationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:ETranslationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETranslationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: eTranslation Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETranslationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETranslationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="eTranslation Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:ETranslationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of eTranslation within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission is the automatic translation of software documentation. When developing and implementing IT systems, it is crucial to provide comprehensive documentation to ensure interoperability and facilitate collaboration among different stakeholders. However, this documentation is often available in multiple languages to cater to the diverse linguistic needs of users across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;eTranslation can be utilized to automatically translate software documentation from one language to another, enabling seamless access and understanding for users from different linguistic backgrounds. This ensures that all stakeholders can effectively utilize and contribute to the development and interoperability of the IT systems, regardless of their native language.&#xA;&#xA;Another application of eTranslation in IT interoperability is the translation of user interfaces and software applications. When designing digital public services, it is essential to provide user interfaces that are user-friendly and accessible to individuals from various linguistic backgrounds. By integrating eTranslation, the user interfaces and software applications can be automatically translated into multiple languages, allowing users to interact with the systems in their preferred language.&#xA;&#xA;This application of eTranslation enhances the interoperability of digital public services by eliminating language barriers and ensuring equal access to information and functionalities for all users. It promotes inclusivity and facilitates seamless communication and collaboration among users from different European countries.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eTranslation can be employed for the translation of technical specifications and standards related to IT interoperability. These specifications and standards serve as guidelines for the development and implementation of IT systems, ensuring compatibility and interoperability across different platforms and technologies. By automatically translating these documents, eTranslation enables a wider dissemination and understanding of the technical requirements and standards, fostering harmonization and cooperation among IT professionals and stakeholders across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the application of eTranslation within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission includes automatic translation of software documentation, translation of user interfaces and software applications, and translation of technical specifications and standards. These applications enhance accessibility, inclusivity, and collaboration among users and stakeholders from diverse linguistic backgrounds, ultimately promoting seamless interoperability in the IT domain."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="eTranslation is a sophisticated digital public service offered by the European Commission that plays a crucial role in promoting IT interoperability within the European Union. It is a powerful language translation tool designed to facilitate seamless communication and understanding between individuals, businesses, and public administrations across different linguistic backgrounds.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, eTranslation leverages cutting-edge language technologies and artificial intelligence to provide accurate and efficient translation services. It enables the translation of various types of digital content, including documents, websites, and even software interfaces, ensuring that information can be easily accessed and understood by users regardless of their native language.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of eTranslation is to break down language barriers and foster cross-border collaboration within the European Union. It supports all official languages of the EU member states, as well as several non-official languages, making it a truly inclusive and comprehensive translation solution. By offering translation services in multiple languages, eTranslation promotes multilingualism and ensures that language diversity does not hinder effective communication and cooperation.&#xA;&#xA;eTranslation operates through a secure and user-friendly web interface, allowing users to submit their content for translation and receive the translated output in a matter of seconds or minutes, depending on the complexity of the text. The service employs a combination of machine translation and human post-editing to ensure the highest quality translations. Machine translation algorithms analyze the input text and generate a preliminary translation, which is then reviewed and refined by professional human translators to ensure accuracy, fluency, and cultural appropriateness.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the reliability and consistency of translations, eTranslation incorporates a vast collection of language resources, such as bilingual and multilingual dictionaries, terminology databases, and parallel corpora. These resources are continuously updated and expanded to reflect the evolving nature of languages and to improve the overall translation quality.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, eTranslation adheres to strict data protection and privacy regulations, ensuring that all user data and content remain confidential and secure throughout the translation process. The service operates within the European Commission's secure IT infrastructure, which is designed to safeguard sensitive information and prevent unauthorized access.&#xA;&#xA;eTranslation is not only a standalone service but also an integral part of the European Commission's broader efforts to promote digital transformation and interoperability across its various public services. It is seamlessly integrated with other digital platforms and systems, allowing users to access translation services directly within their existing workflows and applications.&#xA;&#xA;In conclusion, eTranslation is a state-of-the-art digital public service offered by the European Commission, aimed at promoting IT interoperability by breaking down language barriers. It leverages advanced language technologies, machine translation, and human post-editing to provide accurate and efficient translations in multiple languages. By facilitating cross-border communication and collaboration, eTranslation plays a vital role in fostering a more connected and inclusive European Union."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="eTranslation is a digital public service provided by the European Commission that plays a crucial role in IT interoperability. It is a language translation tool designed to facilitate communication and understanding between different languages within the European Union. eTranslation enables the automatic translation of text documents, websites, and other digital content from one language to another, ensuring that information can be easily accessed and understood by individuals and organizations across linguistic barriers. By promoting multilingualism and breaking down language barriers, eTranslation contributes to the seamless exchange of information and promotes collaboration and cooperation within the European Union."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Translation Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
