<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Contracting authority"
    id="de351e7f-a944-49c4-b452-4b9e0571491f"
    documentation="Definition: Contracting authority is an organization that has been granted the power to enter into contracts with other parties.&#xA;&#xA;Source: Oboloo&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://oboloo.com/blog/what-are-contracting-authorities-definition/&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Contracting Authority, within the European IT context, refers to the entity responsible for initiating and overseeing the procurement process for IT goods, services, or works. It is a crucial element in public procurement procedures, ensuring transparency, fairness, and efficiency in the acquisition of IT solutions by public sector organizations.&#xA;&#xA;The Contracting Authority can be any public sector body, such as government departments, local authorities, public agencies, or other public entities, that require IT products or services to fulfill their operational needs. These entities may have diverse objectives, ranging from delivering public services to implementing specific projects or programs.&#xA;&#xA;The role of the Contracting Authority begins with identifying the IT requirements and defining the scope of the procurement. This involves conducting a thorough analysis of the organization's needs, considering factors such as technical specifications, functional requirements, budgetary constraints, and legal obligations. The Contracting Authority must ensure that the procurement process aligns with the organization's strategic objectives and complies with relevant regulations and guidelines.&#xA;&#xA;Once the requirements are established, the Contracting Authority is responsible for initiating the procurement procedure. This typically involves preparing and publishing a procurement notice or tender documentation, which outlines the IT requirements, evaluation criteria, contract terms, and conditions. The Contracting Authority must ensure that the procurement process is open, transparent, and non-discriminatory, allowing all potential suppliers to compete on an equal footing.&#xA;&#xA;During the procurement process, the Contracting Authority evaluates the received bids or proposals from IT suppliers. This evaluation is based on the predefined criteria, which may include technical capabilities, financial stability, past performance, and compliance with legal and technical standards. The Contracting Authority must ensure a fair and objective evaluation process, adhering to the principles of equal treatment, non-discrimination, and transparency.&#xA;&#xA;Once the evaluation is completed, the Contracting Authority selects the most suitable IT supplier(s) and enters into a contract or framework agreement. The Contracting Authority negotiates the terms and conditions of the contract, including pricing, delivery schedules, service levels, and intellectual property rights. Throughout the contract duration, the Contracting Authority monitors the supplier's performance, ensuring compliance with contractual obligations and addressing any issues or disputes that may arise.&#xA;&#xA;The Contracting Authority plays a vital role in the successful implementation of IT projects within the European IT context. By effectively managing the procurement process, the Contracting Authority aims to achieve value for money, promote competition, and ensure the delivery of high-quality IT solutions that meet the organization's needs. Additionally, the Contracting Authority contributes to the overall development and growth of the European IT sector by providing opportunities for IT suppliers to compete and innovate in the market.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Contracting Authority, in the European IT context, refers to the entity responsible for initiating and managing procurement processes for IT projects within the European Union. It plays a crucial role in ensuring fair competition, transparency, and compliance with regulations in the procurement of IT goods, services, and works. Here are a few examples of how the Contracting Authority is applied in the European IT context:&#xA;&#xA;1. Tendering Process: The Contracting Authority is responsible for issuing tender documents, defining the requirements, and setting evaluation criteria for IT projects. It ensures that all potential suppliers have equal access to information and opportunities to compete for the contract.&#xA;&#xA;2. Contract Management: Once a supplier is selected, the Contracting Authority oversees the contract's execution, ensuring compliance with the agreed terms and conditions. It monitors the project's progress, manages any changes or disputes, and ensures that the supplier delivers the IT solution as per the contract requirements.&#xA;&#xA;3. Compliance and Regulation: The Contracting Authority ensures that all procurement processes adhere to relevant European Union directives and regulations, such as the Public Procurement Directive. It ensures fair competition, prevents corruption, and promotes transparency in the IT procurement process.&#xA;&#xA;4. Risk Management: The Contracting Authority assesses and manages risks associated with IT projects. It identifies potential risks, such as project delays, budget overruns, or data security breaches, and implements appropriate measures to mitigate these risks. This includes defining contractual obligations related to risk management and monitoring the supplier's compliance.&#xA;&#xA;5. Stakeholder Engagement: The Contracting Authority engages with various stakeholders involved in IT projects, including end-users, technical experts, and legal advisors. It gathers their input, requirements, and feedback to ensure that the procurement process and resulting IT solution meet the needs of the European Union and its citizens.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Contracting Authority acts as a central entity responsible for managing the procurement of IT projects within the European IT context. It ensures transparency, fairness, and compliance with regulations, ultimately contributing to the successful implementation of IT solutions that benefit the European Union and its citizens.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContractingAuthorityBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:ContractingAuthorityBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContractingAuthorityBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Contracting authority Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContractingAuthorityBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContractingAuthorityBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:ContractingAuthorityBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Contracting authority Information"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Oboloo"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://oboloo.com/blog/what-are-contracting-authorities-definition/"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Contracting Authority, in the European IT context, refers to the entity responsible for initiating and managing procurement processes for IT projects within the European Union. It plays a crucial role in ensuring fair competition, transparency, and compliance with regulations in the procurement of IT goods, services, and works. Here are a few examples of how the Contracting Authority is applied in the European IT context:&#xA;&#xA;1. Tendering Process: The Contracting Authority is responsible for issuing tender documents, defining the requirements, and setting evaluation criteria for IT projects. It ensures that all potential suppliers have equal access to information and opportunities to compete for the contract.&#xA;&#xA;2. Contract Management: Once a supplier is selected, the Contracting Authority oversees the contract's execution, ensuring compliance with the agreed terms and conditions. It monitors the project's progress, manages any changes or disputes, and ensures that the supplier delivers the IT solution as per the contract requirements.&#xA;&#xA;3. Compliance and Regulation: The Contracting Authority ensures that all procurement processes adhere to relevant European Union directives and regulations, such as the Public Procurement Directive. It ensures fair competition, prevents corruption, and promotes transparency in the IT procurement process.&#xA;&#xA;4. Risk Management: The Contracting Authority assesses and manages risks associated with IT projects. It identifies potential risks, such as project delays, budget overruns, or data security breaches, and implements appropriate measures to mitigate these risks. This includes defining contractual obligations related to risk management and monitoring the supplier's compliance.&#xA;&#xA;5. Stakeholder Engagement: The Contracting Authority engages with various stakeholders involved in IT projects, including end-users, technical experts, and legal advisors. It gathers their input, requirements, and feedback to ensure that the procurement process and resulting IT solution meet the needs of the European Union and its citizens.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Contracting Authority acts as a central entity responsible for managing the procurement of IT projects within the European IT context. It ensures transparency, fairness, and compliance with regulations, ultimately contributing to the successful implementation of IT solutions that benefit the European Union and its citizens."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Contracting Authority, within the European IT context, refers to the entity responsible for initiating and overseeing the procurement process for IT goods, services, or works. It is a crucial element in public procurement procedures, ensuring transparency, fairness, and efficiency in the acquisition of IT solutions by public sector organizations.&#xA;&#xA;The Contracting Authority can be any public sector body, such as government departments, local authorities, public agencies, or other public entities, that require IT products or services to fulfill their operational needs. These entities may have diverse objectives, ranging from delivering public services to implementing specific projects or programs.&#xA;&#xA;The role of the Contracting Authority begins with identifying the IT requirements and defining the scope of the procurement. This involves conducting a thorough analysis of the organization's needs, considering factors such as technical specifications, functional requirements, budgetary constraints, and legal obligations. The Contracting Authority must ensure that the procurement process aligns with the organization's strategic objectives and complies with relevant regulations and guidelines.&#xA;&#xA;Once the requirements are established, the Contracting Authority is responsible for initiating the procurement procedure. This typically involves preparing and publishing a procurement notice or tender documentation, which outlines the IT requirements, evaluation criteria, contract terms, and conditions. The Contracting Authority must ensure that the procurement process is open, transparent, and non-discriminatory, allowing all potential suppliers to compete on an equal footing.&#xA;&#xA;During the procurement process, the Contracting Authority evaluates the received bids or proposals from IT suppliers. This evaluation is based on the predefined criteria, which may include technical capabilities, financial stability, past performance, and compliance with legal and technical standards. The Contracting Authority must ensure a fair and objective evaluation process, adhering to the principles of equal treatment, non-discrimination, and transparency.&#xA;&#xA;Once the evaluation is completed, the Contracting Authority selects the most suitable IT supplier(s) and enters into a contract or framework agreement. The Contracting Authority negotiates the terms and conditions of the contract, including pricing, delivery schedules, service levels, and intellectual property rights. Throughout the contract duration, the Contracting Authority monitors the supplier's performance, ensuring compliance with contractual obligations and addressing any issues or disputes that may arise.&#xA;&#xA;The Contracting Authority plays a vital role in the successful implementation of IT projects within the European IT context. By effectively managing the procurement process, the Contracting Authority aims to achieve value for money, promote competition, and ensure the delivery of high-quality IT solutions that meet the organization's needs. Additionally, the Contracting Authority contributes to the overall development and growth of the European IT sector by providing opportunities for IT suppliers to compete and innovate in the market."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Contracting authority is an organization that has been granted the power to enter into contracts with other parties."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
