<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="eArchiving"
    id="id-ff108d5a524c47cb855aba850043af62"
    documentation="Definition: eArchiving within the context of IT interoperability refers to the process of preserving and maintaining digital information in a standardized and accessible manner. It involves the creation, storage, and retrieval of electronic records, documents, and data to ensure their long-term usability and authenticity. As a digital public service in the European Commission, eArchiving aims to facilitate the exchange and preservation of digital information across different systems and platforms, enabling seamless interoperability between various stakeholders. By implementing standardized formats, metadata, and preservation techniques, eArchiving ensures the longevity and integrity of digital records, promoting efficient information management and facilitating public access to valuable digital resources.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: eArchiving is a crucial component of IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. It refers to the process of preserving and maintaining digital information in a standardized and accessible manner over time. The primary objective of eArchiving is to ensure the long-term integrity, authenticity, and usability of digital records and documents, regardless of changes in technology or software.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, eArchiving plays a vital role in facilitating the exchange of information and data between different public administrations, institutions, and organizations. It enables seamless interoperability by establishing common standards, formats, and protocols for the creation, storage, and retrieval of digital records. This ensures that information can be shared and accessed efficiently, regardless of the specific systems or platforms used by different entities.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key aspects of eArchiving is the adoption of open and non-proprietary formats for storing digital records. This helps to mitigate the risks associated with technological obsolescence and vendor lock-in. By using open standards, the European Commission ensures that digital records can be accessed and interpreted in the future, even if the original software or hardware becomes obsolete.&#xA;&#xA;eArchiving also encompasses the preservation of metadata associated with digital records. Metadata provides essential contextual information about the records, such as their creation date, author, and classification. Preserving metadata is crucial for maintaining the authenticity and reliability of digital records over time, as it helps to establish their provenance and context.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve effective eArchiving, the European Commission employs various strategies and tools. These include the use of digital preservation systems, which employ advanced techniques such as migration, emulation, and encapsulation to ensure the long-term accessibility and usability of digital records. Additionally, the Commission promotes the use of metadata standards, such as the European Union's Metadata Application Profile (EUAP), to ensure consistency and interoperability across different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eArchiving within the European Commission involves collaboration with various stakeholders, including member states, public administrations, and international organizations. This collaboration aims to establish common guidelines, best practices, and standards for eArchiving, ensuring that digital records can be exchanged and preserved effectively across borders.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, eArchiving is a fundamental aspect of IT interoperability within the European Commission's digital public services. It focuses on preserving and maintaining digital records in a standardized and accessible manner, ensuring their long-term integrity, authenticity, and usability. By adopting open standards, preserving metadata, and employing advanced preservation techniques, eArchiving facilitates the seamless exchange and access of digital information across different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of eArchiving within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission could be the preservation of historical documents and records. The eArchiving system can be used to ensure that important documents, such as legislative acts, policy papers, and reports, are preserved in a standardized and interoperable format.&#xA;&#xA;By utilizing eArchiving, the European Commission can ensure that these documents are accessible and readable in the long term, regardless of changes in technology or software. This allows for seamless interoperability between different systems and ensures that the information contained in these documents can be easily retrieved and utilized by both internal and external stakeholders.&#xA;&#xA;Another example could be the preservation of datasets and statistical information. The European Commission collects and analyzes vast amounts of data for various purposes, including policy-making, research, and reporting. By applying eArchiving principles, the Commission can ensure that these datasets are preserved in a standardized format, making them interoperable with different data analysis tools and software.&#xA;&#xA;This interoperability enables the Commission to share and exchange data with other organizations, both within and outside the European Union, facilitating collaboration and data-driven decision-making. It also ensures that the historical datasets can be accessed and reused in the future, even as technology evolves.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, eArchiving can be applied to preserve and make accessible digital publications and reports produced by the European Commission. These publications often contain valuable information and insights that need to be preserved for future reference. By utilizing eArchiving, the Commission can ensure that these publications are stored in a standardized format, making them interoperable with various e-reading devices, platforms, and software.&#xA;&#xA;This interoperability allows citizens, researchers, and policymakers to easily access and read these publications, regardless of the device or software they are using. It also ensures that the publications remain accessible and readable in the long term, contributing to the transparency and openness of the European Commission's digital public service.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Data Management Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EArchivingBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:EArchivingBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EArchivingBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: eArchiving Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EArchivingBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EArchivingBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="eArchiving Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:EArchivingBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of eArchiving within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission could be the preservation of historical documents and records. The eArchiving system can be used to ensure that important documents, such as legislative acts, policy papers, and reports, are preserved in a standardized and interoperable format.&#xA;&#xA;By utilizing eArchiving, the European Commission can ensure that these documents are accessible and readable in the long term, regardless of changes in technology or software. This allows for seamless interoperability between different systems and ensures that the information contained in these documents can be easily retrieved and utilized by both internal and external stakeholders.&#xA;&#xA;Another example could be the preservation of datasets and statistical information. The European Commission collects and analyzes vast amounts of data for various purposes, including policy-making, research, and reporting. By applying eArchiving principles, the Commission can ensure that these datasets are preserved in a standardized format, making them interoperable with different data analysis tools and software.&#xA;&#xA;This interoperability enables the Commission to share and exchange data with other organizations, both within and outside the European Union, facilitating collaboration and data-driven decision-making. It also ensures that the historical datasets can be accessed and reused in the future, even as technology evolves.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, eArchiving can be applied to preserve and make accessible digital publications and reports produced by the European Commission. These publications often contain valuable information and insights that need to be preserved for future reference. By utilizing eArchiving, the Commission can ensure that these publications are stored in a standardized format, making them interoperable with various e-reading devices, platforms, and software.&#xA;&#xA;This interoperability allows citizens, researchers, and policymakers to easily access and read these publications, regardless of the device or software they are using. It also ensures that the publications remain accessible and readable in the long term, contributing to the transparency and openness of the European Commission's digital public service."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="eArchiving is a crucial component of IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. It refers to the process of preserving and maintaining digital information in a standardized and accessible manner over time. The primary objective of eArchiving is to ensure the long-term integrity, authenticity, and usability of digital records and documents, regardless of changes in technology or software.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, eArchiving plays a vital role in facilitating the exchange of information and data between different public administrations, institutions, and organizations. It enables seamless interoperability by establishing common standards, formats, and protocols for the creation, storage, and retrieval of digital records. This ensures that information can be shared and accessed efficiently, regardless of the specific systems or platforms used by different entities.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key aspects of eArchiving is the adoption of open and non-proprietary formats for storing digital records. This helps to mitigate the risks associated with technological obsolescence and vendor lock-in. By using open standards, the European Commission ensures that digital records can be accessed and interpreted in the future, even if the original software or hardware becomes obsolete.&#xA;&#xA;eArchiving also encompasses the preservation of metadata associated with digital records. Metadata provides essential contextual information about the records, such as their creation date, author, and classification. Preserving metadata is crucial for maintaining the authenticity and reliability of digital records over time, as it helps to establish their provenance and context.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve effective eArchiving, the European Commission employs various strategies and tools. These include the use of digital preservation systems, which employ advanced techniques such as migration, emulation, and encapsulation to ensure the long-term accessibility and usability of digital records. Additionally, the Commission promotes the use of metadata standards, such as the European Union's Metadata Application Profile (EUAP), to ensure consistency and interoperability across different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eArchiving within the European Commission involves collaboration with various stakeholders, including member states, public administrations, and international organizations. This collaboration aims to establish common guidelines, best practices, and standards for eArchiving, ensuring that digital records can be exchanged and preserved effectively across borders.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, eArchiving is a fundamental aspect of IT interoperability within the European Commission's digital public services. It focuses on preserving and maintaining digital records in a standardized and accessible manner, ensuring their long-term integrity, authenticity, and usability. By adopting open standards, preserving metadata, and employing advanced preservation techniques, eArchiving facilitates the seamless exchange and access of digital information across different systems and platforms."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="eArchiving within the context of IT interoperability refers to the process of preserving and maintaining digital information in a standardized and accessible manner. It involves the creation, storage, and retrieval of electronic records, documents, and data to ensure their long-term usability and authenticity. As a digital public service in the European Commission, eArchiving aims to facilitate the exchange and preservation of digital information across different systems and platforms, enabling seamless interoperability between various stakeholders. By implementing standardized formats, metadata, and preservation techniques, eArchiving ensures the longevity and integrity of digital records, promoting efficient information management and facilitating public access to valuable digital resources."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Data Management Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
