<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Economic operator"
    id="id-53ab06ce-e343-4bd2-bf60-a1e5f3f076fe"
    documentation="Definition: Economic operator is data about a business or other organisation which supplies goods, works or services within the context of market operations&#xA;&#xA;Source: WikiPedia&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economic_operator&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: An economic operator, within the European IT context, refers to any individual or legal entity that is involved in economic activities, such as the production, distribution, or provision of goods or services. It encompasses a wide range of entities, including businesses, companies, organizations, self-employed individuals, and professionals.&#xA;&#xA;The concept of an economic operator is crucial in the European IT context due to its relevance in various regulatory frameworks and policies. It plays a significant role in areas such as public procurement, product safety, market surveillance, and data protection. Understanding the role and responsibilities of economic operators is essential for ensuring compliance with relevant regulations and promoting fair competition within the European IT market.&#xA;&#xA;Within the European IT context, economic operators can be classified into different categories based on their specific roles and functions. These categories include manufacturers, authorized representatives, importers, distributors, and service providers. Each category has distinct obligations and responsibilities, which are defined by relevant legislation and regulations.&#xA;&#xA;Manufacturers are economic operators who produce or assemble IT products within the European Union (EU) or import them from non-EU countries. They are responsible for ensuring that their products comply with applicable regulations, including technical standards, safety requirements, and environmental regulations. Manufacturers must also keep documentation, such as technical files and declarations of conformity, to demonstrate compliance.&#xA;&#xA;Authorized representatives are individuals or entities appointed by non-EU manufacturers to act on their behalf within the EU. They have specific responsibilities, including ensuring that the products placed on the EU market meet the necessary requirements and maintaining the required documentation. Authorized representatives serve as a point of contact for market surveillance authorities and are responsible for handling any inquiries or issues related to the products they represent.&#xA;&#xA;Importers are economic operators who bring IT products from non-EU countries into the EU market. They have the obligation to ensure that the imported products comply with EU regulations and are safe for consumers. Importers must verify that the necessary conformity assessment procedures have been carried out, maintain documentation, and ensure that the products are appropriately labeled and accompanied by the required information.&#xA;&#xA;Distributors are economic operators involved in the supply chain of IT products. They do not modify the products but play a crucial role in ensuring that the products they distribute comply with applicable regulations. Distributors must verify that the products bear the required markings, labels, and information, and that they are accompanied by the necessary documentation. They also have the responsibility to cooperate with market surveillance authorities and manufacturers to address any non-compliance issues.&#xA;&#xA;Service providers, within the European IT context, refer to economic operators who offer IT-related services, such as software development, IT consulting, or cloud computing. They may also provide maintenance, repair, or technical support services for IT products. Service providers must comply with relevant regulations, such as data protection laws, and ensure the security and confidentiality of the data they handle.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, an economic operator, within the European IT context, encompasses various individuals and entities involved in economic activities related to IT products and services. Understanding the roles and responsibilities of economic operators is crucial for ensuring compliance with regulations, promoting fair competition, and safeguarding consumer interests within the European IT market.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Economic Operator is a crucial element or component of information within the European IT context. It refers to any person or entity engaged in economic activities, such as manufacturing, importing, distributing, or selling goods or providing services. The concept of Economic Operator is widely applied in various areas to ensure compliance with regulations, facilitate trade, and protect consumers. Here are a few examples of its application:&#xA;&#xA;1. Product Safety and Compliance: Economic Operators play a vital role in ensuring the safety and compliance of products placed on the market. Manufacturers, importers, and distributors are considered Economic Operators responsible for ensuring that products meet the necessary standards, undergo appropriate testing, and carry the required certifications. This information about the Economic Operator helps authorities and consumers trace back the responsible party in case of any safety issues or non-compliance.&#xA;&#xA;2. Supply Chain Management: In the European IT context, Economic Operators are essential for effective supply chain management. They provide information about the different entities involved in the supply chain, including manufacturers, suppliers, distributors, and retailers. This information helps in tracking the origin of products, ensuring transparency, and identifying potential risks or bottlenecks in the supply chain.&#xA;&#xA;3. Customs and Trade Facilitation: Economic Operators are also significant in customs and trade facilitation processes. They are required to provide accurate and complete information about the goods being imported or exported, including their value, origin, and classification. This information enables customs authorities to assess duties and taxes, enforce trade regulations, and ensure compliance with customs procedures.&#xA;&#xA;4. Consumer Protection: Economic Operators play a crucial role in protecting consumers' rights and interests. They are responsible for providing accurate and transparent information about the products or services they offer, including pricing, warranties, and after-sales support. This information helps consumers make informed decisions and seek redress in case of any issues or disputes.&#xA;&#xA;5. Market Surveillance: Economic Operators are subject to market surveillance activities conducted by regulatory authorities. These activities aim to ensure that products and services meet the required standards and regulations, protecting consumers and maintaining fair competition. Information about the Economic Operator helps authorities identify and target specific entities for inspections, audits, or enforcement actions.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Economic Operator is a fundamental element of information within the European IT context. Its application spans across various areas, including product safety, supply chain management, customs, trade facilitation, consumer protection, and market surveillance. Understanding and leveraging information about Economic Operators is crucial for ensuring compliance, facilitating trade, and protecting the interests of all stakeholders involved.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EconomicOperatorBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:EconomicOperatorBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EconomicOperatorBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Economic operator Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EconomicOperatorBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EconomicOperatorBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:EconomicOperatorBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Economic operator Information"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="WikiPedia"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economic_operator"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Economic Operator is a crucial element or component of information within the European IT context. It refers to any person or entity engaged in economic activities, such as manufacturing, importing, distributing, or selling goods or providing services. The concept of Economic Operator is widely applied in various areas to ensure compliance with regulations, facilitate trade, and protect consumers. Here are a few examples of its application:&#xA;&#xA;1. Product Safety and Compliance: Economic Operators play a vital role in ensuring the safety and compliance of products placed on the market. Manufacturers, importers, and distributors are considered Economic Operators responsible for ensuring that products meet the necessary standards, undergo appropriate testing, and carry the required certifications. This information about the Economic Operator helps authorities and consumers trace back the responsible party in case of any safety issues or non-compliance.&#xA;&#xA;2. Supply Chain Management: In the European IT context, Economic Operators are essential for effective supply chain management. They provide information about the different entities involved in the supply chain, including manufacturers, suppliers, distributors, and retailers. This information helps in tracking the origin of products, ensuring transparency, and identifying potential risks or bottlenecks in the supply chain.&#xA;&#xA;3. Customs and Trade Facilitation: Economic Operators are also significant in customs and trade facilitation processes. They are required to provide accurate and complete information about the goods being imported or exported, including their value, origin, and classification. This information enables customs authorities to assess duties and taxes, enforce trade regulations, and ensure compliance with customs procedures.&#xA;&#xA;4. Consumer Protection: Economic Operators play a crucial role in protecting consumers' rights and interests. They are responsible for providing accurate and transparent information about the products or services they offer, including pricing, warranties, and after-sales support. This information helps consumers make informed decisions and seek redress in case of any issues or disputes.&#xA;&#xA;5. Market Surveillance: Economic Operators are subject to market surveillance activities conducted by regulatory authorities. These activities aim to ensure that products and services meet the required standards and regulations, protecting consumers and maintaining fair competition. Information about the Economic Operator helps authorities identify and target specific entities for inspections, audits, or enforcement actions.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Economic Operator is a fundamental element of information within the European IT context. Its application spans across various areas, including product safety, supply chain management, customs, trade facilitation, consumer protection, and market surveillance. Understanding and leveraging information about Economic Operators is crucial for ensuring compliance, facilitating trade, and protecting the interests of all stakeholders involved."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="An economic operator, within the European IT context, refers to any individual or legal entity that is involved in economic activities, such as the production, distribution, or provision of goods or services. It encompasses a wide range of entities, including businesses, companies, organizations, self-employed individuals, and professionals.&#xA;&#xA;The concept of an economic operator is crucial in the European IT context due to its relevance in various regulatory frameworks and policies. It plays a significant role in areas such as public procurement, product safety, market surveillance, and data protection. Understanding the role and responsibilities of economic operators is essential for ensuring compliance with relevant regulations and promoting fair competition within the European IT market.&#xA;&#xA;Within the European IT context, economic operators can be classified into different categories based on their specific roles and functions. These categories include manufacturers, authorized representatives, importers, distributors, and service providers. Each category has distinct obligations and responsibilities, which are defined by relevant legislation and regulations.&#xA;&#xA;Manufacturers are economic operators who produce or assemble IT products within the European Union (EU) or import them from non-EU countries. They are responsible for ensuring that their products comply with applicable regulations, including technical standards, safety requirements, and environmental regulations. Manufacturers must also keep documentation, such as technical files and declarations of conformity, to demonstrate compliance.&#xA;&#xA;Authorized representatives are individuals or entities appointed by non-EU manufacturers to act on their behalf within the EU. They have specific responsibilities, including ensuring that the products placed on the EU market meet the necessary requirements and maintaining the required documentation. Authorized representatives serve as a point of contact for market surveillance authorities and are responsible for handling any inquiries or issues related to the products they represent.&#xA;&#xA;Importers are economic operators who bring IT products from non-EU countries into the EU market. They have the obligation to ensure that the imported products comply with EU regulations and are safe for consumers. Importers must verify that the necessary conformity assessment procedures have been carried out, maintain documentation, and ensure that the products are appropriately labeled and accompanied by the required information.&#xA;&#xA;Distributors are economic operators involved in the supply chain of IT products. They do not modify the products but play a crucial role in ensuring that the products they distribute comply with applicable regulations. Distributors must verify that the products bear the required markings, labels, and information, and that they are accompanied by the necessary documentation. They also have the responsibility to cooperate with market surveillance authorities and manufacturers to address any non-compliance issues.&#xA;&#xA;Service providers, within the European IT context, refer to economic operators who offer IT-related services, such as software development, IT consulting, or cloud computing. They may also provide maintenance, repair, or technical support services for IT products. Service providers must comply with relevant regulations, such as data protection laws, and ensure the security and confidentiality of the data they handle.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, an economic operator, within the European IT context, encompasses various individuals and entities involved in economic activities related to IT products and services. Understanding the roles and responsibilities of economic operators is crucial for ensuring compliance with regulations, promoting fair competition, and safeguarding consumer interests within the European IT market."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Economic operator is data about a business or other organisation which supplies goods, works or services within the context of market operations"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
