<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Document"
    id="id-76727a0d-5f7d-426e-a9dc-20cf4e6c344e"
    documentation="Definition: A document is a written, drawn, presented, or memorialized representation of thought, often the manifestation of non-fictional, as well as fictional, content&#xA;&#xA;Source: WikiPedia&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: A document, within the European IT context, refers to an electronic or physical entity that contains information in a structured or unstructured format. It serves as a means of storing, communicating, and preserving information for various purposes. Documents can exist in various forms, including text files, spreadsheets, presentations, images, audio files, videos, or any other digital or physical medium that can hold information.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, documents play a crucial role in information management, knowledge sharing, and collaboration within organizations and across different sectors. They are created, processed, stored, and accessed using various technologies, software applications, and systems. Documents can be generated by individuals, organizations, or automated processes, and they can be both static or dynamic, depending on the nature of the information they contain.&#xA;&#xA;Documents typically have a defined structure or format that helps organize and categorize the information they hold. This structure can include headings, paragraphs, tables, lists, hyperlinks, metadata, and other elements that facilitate navigation, searchability, and understanding of the content. Additionally, documents often include attributes such as authorship, creation date, versioning, access permissions, and security features to ensure proper management and control over the information they contain.&#xA;&#xA;Documents serve various purposes within the European IT context. They can be used for creating and sharing reports, contracts, policies, procedures, specifications, research papers, invoices, presentations, and many other types of content. They enable individuals and organizations to capture, record, and communicate information, ideas, and knowledge efficiently.&#xA;&#xA;In the digital realm, documents are often stored in electronic document management systems (EDMS) or content management systems (CMS) that provide features for organizing, indexing, searching, and retrieving documents. These systems may also incorporate workflow capabilities, allowing for collaborative editing, review, and approval processes.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, documents can be shared and distributed electronically through various channels such as email, file sharing platforms, cloud storage, or web-based portals. This facilitates remote collaboration, document version control, and simultaneous access by multiple users.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, within the European IT context, a document is an element or component of information that can exist in various formats and serves as a repository for storing, communicating, and preserving information. It plays a vital role in information management, knowledge sharing, and collaboration, enabling individuals and organizations to capture, organize, and disseminate information efficiently.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The application of documents as elements or components of information is prevalent in various aspects of the European IT context. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Documentation in software development: Documents play a crucial role in software development processes. Requirements documents outline the desired functionalities and specifications of a software system. Design documents provide a blueprint for the architecture and structure of the software. Technical documents document the codebase, APIs, and libraries used. User manuals and help guides are also important documents that assist end-users in understanding and utilizing the software effectively.&#xA;&#xA;2. Legal documents and contracts: In the European IT context, legal documents and contracts are essential for establishing agreements between parties involved in IT-related activities. These documents include software licensing agreements, service level agreements (SLAs), non-disclosure agreements (NDAs), and intellectual property rights documentation. They ensure legal compliance, protect intellectual property, and define the rights and responsibilities of all parties involved.&#xA;&#xA;3. Project documentation: Documentation is crucial in managing IT projects effectively. Project charters, project plans, and project scope documents outline the objectives, deliverables, timelines, and resources required for successful project execution. Progress reports, meeting minutes, and change request documents help track project progress, communicate updates, and manage changes throughout the project lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;4. Technical specifications and standards: Documents containing technical specifications and standards are vital in the European IT context. These documents define the requirements, guidelines, and best practices for hardware, software, and network infrastructure. They ensure interoperability, compatibility, and compliance with industry standards, facilitating seamless integration and communication between different IT systems and components.&#xA;&#xA;5. Research papers and whitepapers: In the European IT context, research papers and whitepapers contribute to the advancement of knowledge and innovation. These documents present findings, analyses, and insights on various IT-related topics, such as emerging technologies, cybersecurity, data privacy, and artificial intelligence. They provide valuable information to researchers, industry professionals, policymakers, and the general public, fostering informed decision-making and driving technological advancements.&#xA;&#xA;These examples illustrate how documents serve as fundamental elements or components of information in the European IT context, enabling effective communication, collaboration, and knowledge sharing within the IT industry.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DocumentBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:DocumentBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DocumentBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Document Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DocumentBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Document Information"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:DocumentBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="WikiPedia"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DocumentBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Business Agnostic Metadata"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Forms Structure"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Business Agnostic High Value Dataset"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Agnostic Ontologies"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Data Mapping"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="SV-Business Agnostic Data Models"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Semantic view - Motivation"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="A document is a written, drawn, presented, or memorialized representation of thought, often the manifestation of non-fictional, as well as fictional, content"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The application of documents as elements or components of information is prevalent in various aspects of the European IT context. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Documentation in software development: Documents play a crucial role in software development processes. Requirements documents outline the desired functionalities and specifications of a software system. Design documents provide a blueprint for the architecture and structure of the software. Technical documents document the codebase, APIs, and libraries used. User manuals and help guides are also important documents that assist end-users in understanding and utilizing the software effectively.&#xA;&#xA;2. Legal documents and contracts: In the European IT context, legal documents and contracts are essential for establishing agreements between parties involved in IT-related activities. These documents include software licensing agreements, service level agreements (SLAs), non-disclosure agreements (NDAs), and intellectual property rights documentation. They ensure legal compliance, protect intellectual property, and define the rights and responsibilities of all parties involved.&#xA;&#xA;3. Project documentation: Documentation is crucial in managing IT projects effectively. Project charters, project plans, and project scope documents outline the objectives, deliverables, timelines, and resources required for successful project execution. Progress reports, meeting minutes, and change request documents help track project progress, communicate updates, and manage changes throughout the project lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;4. Technical specifications and standards: Documents containing technical specifications and standards are vital in the European IT context. These documents define the requirements, guidelines, and best practices for hardware, software, and network infrastructure. They ensure interoperability, compatibility, and compliance with industry standards, facilitating seamless integration and communication between different IT systems and components.&#xA;&#xA;5. Research papers and whitepapers: In the European IT context, research papers and whitepapers contribute to the advancement of knowledge and innovation. These documents present findings, analyses, and insights on various IT-related topics, such as emerging technologies, cybersecurity, data privacy, and artificial intelligence. They provide valuable information to researchers, industry professionals, policymakers, and the general public, fostering informed decision-making and driving technological advancements.&#xA;&#xA;These examples illustrate how documents serve as fundamental elements or components of information in the European IT context, enabling effective communication, collaboration, and knowledge sharing within the IT industry."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="A document, within the European IT context, refers to an electronic or physical entity that contains information in a structured or unstructured format. It serves as a means of storing, communicating, and preserving information for various purposes. Documents can exist in various forms, including text files, spreadsheets, presentations, images, audio files, videos, or any other digital or physical medium that can hold information.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, documents play a crucial role in information management, knowledge sharing, and collaboration within organizations and across different sectors. They are created, processed, stored, and accessed using various technologies, software applications, and systems. Documents can be generated by individuals, organizations, or automated processes, and they can be both static or dynamic, depending on the nature of the information they contain.&#xA;&#xA;Documents typically have a defined structure or format that helps organize and categorize the information they hold. This structure can include headings, paragraphs, tables, lists, hyperlinks, metadata, and other elements that facilitate navigation, searchability, and understanding of the content. Additionally, documents often include attributes such as authorship, creation date, versioning, access permissions, and security features to ensure proper management and control over the information they contain.&#xA;&#xA;Documents serve various purposes within the European IT context. They can be used for creating and sharing reports, contracts, policies, procedures, specifications, research papers, invoices, presentations, and many other types of content. They enable individuals and organizations to capture, record, and communicate information, ideas, and knowledge efficiently.&#xA;&#xA;In the digital realm, documents are often stored in electronic document management systems (EDMS) or content management systems (CMS) that provide features for organizing, indexing, searching, and retrieving documents. These systems may also incorporate workflow capabilities, allowing for collaborative editing, review, and approval processes.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, documents can be shared and distributed electronically through various channels such as email, file sharing platforms, cloud storage, or web-based portals. This facilitates remote collaboration, document version control, and simultaneous access by multiple users.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, within the European IT context, a document is an element or component of information that can exist in various formats and serves as a repository for storing, communicating, and preserving information. It plays a vital role in information management, knowledge sharing, and collaboration, enabling individuals and organizations to capture, organize, and disseminate information efficiently."/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
