<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Anonymisation"
    id="id-a3d8335390c54f079a0ea862b7acca9c"
    documentation="Definition: Anonymisation within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission refers to the process of removing or encrypting personal data in a way that it can no longer be attributed to an individual. It ensures that data exchanged between different systems or organizations remains anonymous, protecting individuals' privacy and complying with data protection regulations. Anonymisation techniques may include removing direct identifiers, such as names or addresses, and applying additional measures to prevent re-identification of individuals. This enables secure and privacy-preserving data sharing and collaboration among different entities while maintaining the integrity and confidentiality of sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: Anonymisation, within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission, refers to the process of transforming personal data in such a way that it can no longer be attributed to a specific individual without the use of additional information. The purpose of anonymisation is to protect the privacy and confidentiality of individuals while still allowing the sharing and analysis of data for various purposes, such as research, statistics, or service improvement.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, anonymisation plays a crucial role in ensuring compliance with data protection regulations, particularly the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The GDPR emphasizes the importance of protecting personal data and provides guidelines on how to achieve this. Anonymisation is one of the techniques recommended to minimize the risks associated with processing personal data.&#xA;&#xA;The process of anonymisation involves the removal or alteration of identifiable information that could be used to directly or indirectly identify an individual. This includes elements such as names, addresses, identification numbers, and any other unique identifiers. Additionally, sensitive attributes or characteristics that could potentially lead to re-identification, such as medical records or biometric data, are also modified or removed.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the effectiveness of anonymisation, various methods and techniques can be employed. One commonly used approach is the application of statistical techniques, such as aggregation or generalization, to mask or obfuscate individual data points. Aggregation involves combining multiple data points to form a summary or average, while generalization involves replacing specific values with broader categories or ranges.&#xA;&#xA;Another technique is the use of pseudonymisation, which involves replacing direct identifiers with pseudonyms or codes. Pseudonymisation allows for the reversible transformation of data, enabling re-identification if necessary, but only by authorized individuals who possess the corresponding pseudonymization key.&#xA;&#xA;It is important to note that while anonymisation aims to protect privacy, it does not guarantee absolute anonymity. There is always a risk of re-identification, especially when combining anonymised data with other available information or through sophisticated data linkage techniques. Therefore, it is crucial to assess and mitigate these risks by implementing appropriate safeguards and ensuring compliance with legal and ethical requirements.&#xA;&#xA;In the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission, anonymisation enables the secure exchange of data between different systems and organizations while preserving the privacy rights of individuals. It allows for the sharing of aggregated or generalized data for statistical analysis, policy-making, or research purposes without compromising the confidentiality of personal information.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, anonymisation is a fundamental component of data protection and privacy in the digital public service of the European Commission. It ensures that personal data is processed in a responsible and compliant manner, fostering trust and confidence in the use of data for public interest purposes.&#xA;&#xA;Example: Anonymisation is a crucial technique used in IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. Here are a few examples of its application:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Sharing: When different public services or departments within the European Commission need to share data for collaborative purposes, anonymisation ensures that personally identifiable information (PII) is removed or obfuscated. This allows for secure and privacy-preserving data exchange, enabling effective collaboration while complying with data protection regulations.&#xA;&#xA;2. Research and Analysis: Anonymisation plays a vital role in facilitating research and analysis of large datasets while protecting individuals' privacy. By anonymising sensitive data, such as health records or demographic information, researchers can gain valuable insights without compromising the privacy of individuals involved.&#xA;&#xA;3. Statistical Reporting: Anonymisation is used to aggregate and anonymise data collected from various sources to generate statistical reports. For instance, when compiling reports on employment rates, GDP growth, or demographic trends, personal identifiers are removed or replaced with pseudonyms to ensure privacy while providing accurate and reliable statistical information.&#xA;&#xA;4. Testing and Development: Anonymised data is often used for testing and development purposes within the European Commission's digital public services. By anonymising real datasets, developers can create realistic test environments without exposing sensitive information. This allows for the identification and resolution of potential issues or vulnerabilities before deploying services to the public.&#xA;&#xA;5. Open Data Initiatives: Anonymisation is employed in the context of open data initiatives, where public datasets are made available to the general public for reuse and analysis. Before releasing such datasets, personal identifiers are removed or anonymised to protect individuals' privacy while promoting transparency and innovation.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, anonymisation ensures that IT interoperability within the European Commission's digital public services is conducted in a privacy-preserving manner, enabling secure data sharing, research, statistical reporting, testing, and open data initiatives.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Privacy Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/AnonymisationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:AnonymisationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/AnonymisationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: Anonymisation Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/AnonymisationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/AnonymisationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Anonymisation Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:AnonymisationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="Anonymisation is a crucial technique used in IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. Here are a few examples of its application:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Sharing: When different public services or departments within the European Commission need to share data for collaborative purposes, anonymisation ensures that personally identifiable information (PII) is removed or obfuscated. This allows for secure and privacy-preserving data exchange, enabling effective collaboration while complying with data protection regulations.&#xA;&#xA;2. Research and Analysis: Anonymisation plays a vital role in facilitating research and analysis of large datasets while protecting individuals' privacy. By anonymising sensitive data, such as health records or demographic information, researchers can gain valuable insights without compromising the privacy of individuals involved.&#xA;&#xA;3. Statistical Reporting: Anonymisation is used to aggregate and anonymise data collected from various sources to generate statistical reports. For instance, when compiling reports on employment rates, GDP growth, or demographic trends, personal identifiers are removed or replaced with pseudonyms to ensure privacy while providing accurate and reliable statistical information.&#xA;&#xA;4. Testing and Development: Anonymised data is often used for testing and development purposes within the European Commission's digital public services. By anonymising real datasets, developers can create realistic test environments without exposing sensitive information. This allows for the identification and resolution of potential issues or vulnerabilities before deploying services to the public.&#xA;&#xA;5. Open Data Initiatives: Anonymisation is employed in the context of open data initiatives, where public datasets are made available to the general public for reuse and analysis. Before releasing such datasets, personal identifiers are removed or anonymised to protect individuals' privacy while promoting transparency and innovation.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, anonymisation ensures that IT interoperability within the European Commission's digital public services is conducted in a privacy-preserving manner, enabling secure data sharing, research, statistical reporting, testing, and open data initiatives."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="Anonymisation, within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission, refers to the process of transforming personal data in such a way that it can no longer be attributed to a specific individual without the use of additional information. The purpose of anonymisation is to protect the privacy and confidentiality of individuals while still allowing the sharing and analysis of data for various purposes, such as research, statistics, or service improvement.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, anonymisation plays a crucial role in ensuring compliance with data protection regulations, particularly the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The GDPR emphasizes the importance of protecting personal data and provides guidelines on how to achieve this. Anonymisation is one of the techniques recommended to minimize the risks associated with processing personal data.&#xA;&#xA;The process of anonymisation involves the removal or alteration of identifiable information that could be used to directly or indirectly identify an individual. This includes elements such as names, addresses, identification numbers, and any other unique identifiers. Additionally, sensitive attributes or characteristics that could potentially lead to re-identification, such as medical records or biometric data, are also modified or removed.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the effectiveness of anonymisation, various methods and techniques can be employed. One commonly used approach is the application of statistical techniques, such as aggregation or generalization, to mask or obfuscate individual data points. Aggregation involves combining multiple data points to form a summary or average, while generalization involves replacing specific values with broader categories or ranges.&#xA;&#xA;Another technique is the use of pseudonymisation, which involves replacing direct identifiers with pseudonyms or codes. Pseudonymisation allows for the reversible transformation of data, enabling re-identification if necessary, but only by authorized individuals who possess the corresponding pseudonymization key.&#xA;&#xA;It is important to note that while anonymisation aims to protect privacy, it does not guarantee absolute anonymity. There is always a risk of re-identification, especially when combining anonymised data with other available information or through sophisticated data linkage techniques. Therefore, it is crucial to assess and mitigate these risks by implementing appropriate safeguards and ensuring compliance with legal and ethical requirements.&#xA;&#xA;In the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission, anonymisation enables the secure exchange of data between different systems and organizations while preserving the privacy rights of individuals. It allows for the sharing of aggregated or generalized data for statistical analysis, policy-making, or research purposes without compromising the confidentiality of personal information.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, anonymisation is a fundamental component of data protection and privacy in the digital public service of the European Commission. It ensures that personal data is processed in a responsible and compliant manner, fostering trust and confidence in the use of data for public interest purposes."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Anonymisation within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission refers to the process of removing or encrypting personal data in a way that it can no longer be attributed to an individual. It ensures that data exchanged between different systems or organizations remains anonymous, protecting individuals' privacy and complying with data protection regulations. Anonymisation techniques may include removing direct identifiers, such as names or addresses, and applying additional measures to prevent re-identification of individuals. This enables secure and privacy-preserving data sharing and collaboration among different entities while maintaining the integrity and confidentiality of sensitive information."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Privacy Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
