<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="eTendering"
    id="id-405c209ade324a1fb404e022a251de36"
    documentation="Definition: eTendering enables the electronic end-to-end management of the purchasing process and related tasks associated to the acquisition of third-party goods and/or services through digital means and information and communication technologies.&#xA;&#xA;Source: European Commission&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://etendering.ted.europa.eu/general/page.html?name=home&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: eTendering, within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission, refers to the electronic procurement process that enables public sector organizations to publish, manage, and award tenders or contracts to suppliers through an online platform. It is a digital solution designed to streamline and enhance the efficiency, transparency, and fairness of the procurement process.&#xA;&#xA;eTendering platforms provide a centralized and standardized system for managing the entire tendering lifecycle, from the publication of tender notices to the submission and evaluation of bids, and ultimately the awarding of contracts. These platforms are typically web-based and accessible to both public sector entities and potential suppliers, ensuring a level playing field for all participants.&#xA;&#xA;One of the primary objectives of eTendering is to promote open competition and increase transparency in public procurement. By digitizing the entire process, it becomes easier for suppliers to access and participate in tenders, regardless of their geographical location. This fosters a more competitive environment, as a larger pool of potential suppliers can submit their bids, leading to better value for money for the public sector.&#xA;&#xA;In terms of IT interoperability, eTendering platforms adhere to certain technical standards and specifications to ensure seamless integration with other systems and services. These standards enable interoperability between different eTendering platforms, allowing for the exchange of data and information between various stakeholders involved in the procurement process.&#xA;&#xA;For instance, eTendering platforms may utilize standardized data formats, such as XML or JSON, to facilitate the exchange of tender notices, bid documents, and evaluation reports between the platform and other systems, such as eProcurement systems or financial management systems. This interoperability ensures that information flows smoothly across different stages of the procurement process, reducing manual effort, minimizing errors, and enhancing data accuracy.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eTendering platforms often integrate with electronic signature solutions to ensure the authenticity and integrity of tender documents. This integration enables suppliers to digitally sign their bids, eliminating the need for physical paperwork and enabling a fully digital and secure tendering process.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, eTendering plays a crucial role in promoting fair competition, efficiency, and transparency in public procurement. It aligns with the principles of the EU's Digital Single Market strategy, which aims to harness the potential of digital technologies to drive economic growth, innovation, and job creation across the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, eTendering within the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public service is a comprehensive digital solution that revolutionizes the procurement process. It leverages technology to enhance transparency, increase competition, and improve efficiency, ultimately benefiting both public sector organizations and suppliers.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of eTendering within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission could be the procurement process for software development services. &#xA;&#xA;In this scenario, the European Commission may need to develop a new software application to enhance its digital services. The eTendering system would be utilized to streamline the procurement process and ensure interoperability among different IT systems involved.&#xA;&#xA;1. Publication of tender: The European Commission would publish a tender notice on the eTendering platform, providing details about the software development project, requirements, and evaluation criteria. This notice would be accessible to potential bidders from various IT companies across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;2. Electronic submission of bids: Interested IT companies would submit their bids electronically through the eTendering system. The system would ensure that all bids are submitted in a standardized format, promoting interoperability among different IT systems used by the bidders.&#xA;&#xA;3. Evaluation of bids: The evaluation committee, consisting of representatives from the European Commission, would assess the submitted bids using the eTendering system. The system would allow for efficient comparison and evaluation of bids based on predefined criteria, ensuring transparency and fairness in the evaluation process.&#xA;&#xA;4. Clarifications and communication: The eTendering system would facilitate communication between the European Commission and the bidders. Any clarifications or additional information requested by the bidders would be addressed through the system, ensuring all parties have access to the same information and promoting interoperability in communication.&#xA;&#xA;5. Contract award: Once the evaluation process is complete, the European Commission would award the contract to the successful bidder through the eTendering system. The system would generate the necessary documentation, including the contract agreement, which would be digitally signed by both parties, ensuring legal validity and interoperability in contract management.&#xA;&#xA;6. Project implementation: Throughout the software development project, the eTendering system would continue to play a role in monitoring and managing the project progress. It could be used for progress reporting, change management, and invoice submission, ensuring interoperability in project management processes.&#xA;&#xA;By utilizing eTendering in this manner, the European Commission can ensure a transparent, efficient, and interoperable procurement process for IT services, ultimately leading to the successful development and implementation of digital public services.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-API Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETenderingBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:ETenderingBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETenderingBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: eTendering Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETenderingBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ETenderingBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="eTendering Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:ETenderingBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="European Commission"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://etendering.ted.europa.eu/general/page.html?name=home"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of eTendering within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission could be the procurement process for software development services. &#xA;&#xA;In this scenario, the European Commission may need to develop a new software application to enhance its digital services. The eTendering system would be utilized to streamline the procurement process and ensure interoperability among different IT systems involved.&#xA;&#xA;1. Publication of tender: The European Commission would publish a tender notice on the eTendering platform, providing details about the software development project, requirements, and evaluation criteria. This notice would be accessible to potential bidders from various IT companies across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;2. Electronic submission of bids: Interested IT companies would submit their bids electronically through the eTendering system. The system would ensure that all bids are submitted in a standardized format, promoting interoperability among different IT systems used by the bidders.&#xA;&#xA;3. Evaluation of bids: The evaluation committee, consisting of representatives from the European Commission, would assess the submitted bids using the eTendering system. The system would allow for efficient comparison and evaluation of bids based on predefined criteria, ensuring transparency and fairness in the evaluation process.&#xA;&#xA;4. Clarifications and communication: The eTendering system would facilitate communication between the European Commission and the bidders. Any clarifications or additional information requested by the bidders would be addressed through the system, ensuring all parties have access to the same information and promoting interoperability in communication.&#xA;&#xA;5. Contract award: Once the evaluation process is complete, the European Commission would award the contract to the successful bidder through the eTendering system. The system would generate the necessary documentation, including the contract agreement, which would be digitally signed by both parties, ensuring legal validity and interoperability in contract management.&#xA;&#xA;6. Project implementation: Throughout the software development project, the eTendering system would continue to play a role in monitoring and managing the project progress. It could be used for progress reporting, change management, and invoice submission, ensuring interoperability in project management processes.&#xA;&#xA;By utilizing eTendering in this manner, the European Commission can ensure a transparent, efficient, and interoperable procurement process for IT services, ultimately leading to the successful development and implementation of digital public services."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="eTendering, within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission, refers to the electronic procurement process that enables public sector organizations to publish, manage, and award tenders or contracts to suppliers through an online platform. It is a digital solution designed to streamline and enhance the efficiency, transparency, and fairness of the procurement process.&#xA;&#xA;eTendering platforms provide a centralized and standardized system for managing the entire tendering lifecycle, from the publication of tender notices to the submission and evaluation of bids, and ultimately the awarding of contracts. These platforms are typically web-based and accessible to both public sector entities and potential suppliers, ensuring a level playing field for all participants.&#xA;&#xA;One of the primary objectives of eTendering is to promote open competition and increase transparency in public procurement. By digitizing the entire process, it becomes easier for suppliers to access and participate in tenders, regardless of their geographical location. This fosters a more competitive environment, as a larger pool of potential suppliers can submit their bids, leading to better value for money for the public sector.&#xA;&#xA;In terms of IT interoperability, eTendering platforms adhere to certain technical standards and specifications to ensure seamless integration with other systems and services. These standards enable interoperability between different eTendering platforms, allowing for the exchange of data and information between various stakeholders involved in the procurement process.&#xA;&#xA;For instance, eTendering platforms may utilize standardized data formats, such as XML or JSON, to facilitate the exchange of tender notices, bid documents, and evaluation reports between the platform and other systems, such as eProcurement systems or financial management systems. This interoperability ensures that information flows smoothly across different stages of the procurement process, reducing manual effort, minimizing errors, and enhancing data accuracy.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eTendering platforms often integrate with electronic signature solutions to ensure the authenticity and integrity of tender documents. This integration enables suppliers to digitally sign their bids, eliminating the need for physical paperwork and enabling a fully digital and secure tendering process.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, eTendering plays a crucial role in promoting fair competition, efficiency, and transparency in public procurement. It aligns with the principles of the EU's Digital Single Market strategy, which aims to harness the potential of digital technologies to drive economic growth, innovation, and job creation across the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, eTendering within the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public service is a comprehensive digital solution that revolutionizes the procurement process. It leverages technology to enhance transparency, increase competition, and improve efficiency, ultimately benefiting both public sector organizations and suppliers."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="eTendering enables the electronic end-to-end management of the purchasing process and related tasks associated to the acquisition of third-party goods and/or services through digital means and information and communication technologies."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-API Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
