<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Qualification"
    id="b151b174-b5bd-44fb-b3ca-2a686c58d338"
    documentation="Definition: A qualification is somehting that could potentially be used to qualifiy a particular person or entity. Qualification information specify the ability, characteristic, or experience that makes an individual or entity suitable for a particular job or activity.&#xA;&#xA;Source: Philip Barnhart&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://books.google.it/books?id=3tY8Fck5UVkC&amp;pg=PA2&amp;redir_esc=y&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: Qualification, within the realm of information technology (IT) in Europe, refers to the process of assessing and validating an individual's knowledge, skills, and competencies in a specific field or domain. It serves as a means to demonstrate one's expertise and proficiency to potential employers, clients, or educational institutions.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, qualifications are typically obtained through formal education, vocational training, or professional certifications. These qualifications play a crucial role in determining an individual's suitability for employment, career advancement, or further educational opportunities within the IT industry.&#xA;&#xA;Formal education qualifications in IT often include degrees such as Bachelor's, Master's, or Doctorate programs in computer science, information systems, software engineering, or related fields. These qualifications are typically awarded by universities or higher education institutions and provide a comprehensive theoretical foundation along with practical skills necessary for various IT roles.&#xA;&#xA;Vocational training qualifications are another significant aspect of the European IT context. These qualifications are typically obtained through specialized training programs, apprenticeships, or vocational schools. They focus on equipping individuals with specific technical skills and practical knowledge required for specific IT job roles, such as network administration, programming, cybersecurity, or database management.&#xA;&#xA;Professional certifications also hold great value in the European IT context. These qualifications are awarded by industry-recognized organizations or vendors and validate an individual's expertise in specific technologies, methodologies, or frameworks. Examples of widely recognized IT certifications in Europe include Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE), or Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP).&#xA;&#xA;Qualifications in the European IT context are often regulated and standardized to ensure consistency and comparability across different countries. For instance, the European Qualifications Framework (EQF) provides a common reference framework to understand and compare qualifications across European countries. It enables individuals, employers, and educational institutions to assess the level and complexity of qualifications, facilitating mobility and recognition of qualifications within Europe.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, qualifications in the European IT context serve as a vital tool for individuals to showcase their knowledge and skills, enabling them to pursue rewarding careers, contribute to the IT industry, and meet the evolving demands of the digital era.&#xA;&#xA;Example: Qualification, as an element or component of information, plays a crucial role in various aspects of the European IT context. Here are a few examples of its application:&#xA;&#xA;1. Job Applications: In the European IT industry, qualifications are essential for job seekers to demonstrate their knowledge, skills, and expertise. Candidates typically include their educational qualifications, such as degrees, certifications, and diplomas, in their resumes or job applications. These qualifications provide employers with a clear understanding of the candidate's technical competencies and suitability for the role.&#xA;&#xA;2. Vendor Certifications: Many IT professionals in Europe pursue vendor-specific certifications offered by renowned technology companies like Microsoft, Cisco, or Oracle. These certifications validate an individual's proficiency in using specific software, hardware, or platforms. For instance, a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE) qualification indicates expertise in Microsoft technologies, making it valuable for IT professionals working with Microsoft products in Europe.&#xA;&#xA;3. Professional Associations: Europe has several professional IT associations that offer qualifications to their members. These qualifications often involve a combination of education, experience, and examinations. For example, the British Computer Society (BCS) offers various certifications, including Chartered IT Professional (CITP), which recognizes individuals who have demonstrated a high level of competence and professionalism in the IT field.&#xA;&#xA;4. Academic Degrees: European universities and educational institutions offer a wide range of IT-related academic degrees, such as Bachelor's, Master's, and Ph.D. programs. These qualifications provide students with a comprehensive understanding of IT concepts, theories, and practical skills. Employers in the European IT industry often consider these degrees as a prerequisite for certain roles or as an indication of a candidate's commitment to continuous learning and development.&#xA;&#xA;5. Project Bidding: In the European IT sector, companies often bid for projects or contracts. Qualifications play a significant role in the bidding process as they help potential clients assess the capabilities and expertise of the bidding companies. Qualifications such as ISO certifications, industry-specific accreditations, or previous successful project experiences can enhance a company's chances of winning a bid.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, qualifications serve as a standardized measure of an individual's or organization's capabilities and expertise within the European IT context. They provide valuable information to employers, clients, and stakeholders, enabling them to make informed decisions and ensure the quality and competence of IT professionals and companies.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:QualificationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Qualification Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Qualification Information"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:QualificationBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Philip Barnhart"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://books.google.it/books?id=3tY8Fck5UVkC&amp;pg=PA2&amp;redir_esc=y"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="A qualification is somehting that could potentially be used to qualifiy a particular person or entity. Qualification information specify the ability, characteristic, or experience that makes an individual or entity suitable for a particular job or activity."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="Qualification, as an element or component of information, plays a crucial role in various aspects of the European IT context. Here are a few examples of its application:&#xA;&#xA;1. Job Applications: In the European IT industry, qualifications are essential for job seekers to demonstrate their knowledge, skills, and expertise. Candidates typically include their educational qualifications, such as degrees, certifications, and diplomas, in their resumes or job applications. These qualifications provide employers with a clear understanding of the candidate's technical competencies and suitability for the role.&#xA;&#xA;2. Vendor Certifications: Many IT professionals in Europe pursue vendor-specific certifications offered by renowned technology companies like Microsoft, Cisco, or Oracle. These certifications validate an individual's proficiency in using specific software, hardware, or platforms. For instance, a Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE) qualification indicates expertise in Microsoft technologies, making it valuable for IT professionals working with Microsoft products in Europe.&#xA;&#xA;3. Professional Associations: Europe has several professional IT associations that offer qualifications to their members. These qualifications often involve a combination of education, experience, and examinations. For example, the British Computer Society (BCS) offers various certifications, including Chartered IT Professional (CITP), which recognizes individuals who have demonstrated a high level of competence and professionalism in the IT field.&#xA;&#xA;4. Academic Degrees: European universities and educational institutions offer a wide range of IT-related academic degrees, such as Bachelor's, Master's, and Ph.D. programs. These qualifications provide students with a comprehensive understanding of IT concepts, theories, and practical skills. Employers in the European IT industry often consider these degrees as a prerequisite for certain roles or as an indication of a candidate's commitment to continuous learning and development.&#xA;&#xA;5. Project Bidding: In the European IT sector, companies often bid for projects or contracts. Qualifications play a significant role in the bidding process as they help potential clients assess the capabilities and expertise of the bidding companies. Qualifications such as ISO certifications, industry-specific accreditations, or previous successful project experiences can enhance a company's chances of winning a bid.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, qualifications serve as a standardized measure of an individual's or organization's capabilities and expertise within the European IT context. They provide valuable information to employers, clients, and stakeholders, enabling them to make informed decisions and ensure the quality and competence of IT professionals and companies."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="Qualification, within the realm of information technology (IT) in Europe, refers to the process of assessing and validating an individual's knowledge, skills, and competencies in a specific field or domain. It serves as a means to demonstrate one's expertise and proficiency to potential employers, clients, or educational institutions.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, qualifications are typically obtained through formal education, vocational training, or professional certifications. These qualifications play a crucial role in determining an individual's suitability for employment, career advancement, or further educational opportunities within the IT industry.&#xA;&#xA;Formal education qualifications in IT often include degrees such as Bachelor's, Master's, or Doctorate programs in computer science, information systems, software engineering, or related fields. These qualifications are typically awarded by universities or higher education institutions and provide a comprehensive theoretical foundation along with practical skills necessary for various IT roles.&#xA;&#xA;Vocational training qualifications are another significant aspect of the European IT context. These qualifications are typically obtained through specialized training programs, apprenticeships, or vocational schools. They focus on equipping individuals with specific technical skills and practical knowledge required for specific IT job roles, such as network administration, programming, cybersecurity, or database management.&#xA;&#xA;Professional certifications also hold great value in the European IT context. These qualifications are awarded by industry-recognized organizations or vendors and validate an individual's expertise in specific technologies, methodologies, or frameworks. Examples of widely recognized IT certifications in Europe include Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE), or Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP).&#xA;&#xA;Qualifications in the European IT context are often regulated and standardized to ensure consistency and comparability across different countries. For instance, the European Qualifications Framework (EQF) provides a common reference framework to understand and compare qualifications across European countries. It enables individuals, employers, and educational institutions to assess the level and complexity of qualifications, facilitating mobility and recognition of qualifications within Europe.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, qualifications in the European IT context serve as a vital tool for individuals to showcase their knowledge and skills, enabling them to pursue rewarding careers, contribute to the IT industry, and meet the evolving demands of the digital era."/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
