<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Exchange"
    id="id-eeafe407a598495d934c0ef54173d17b"
    documentation="Definition: Data exchange business service involves the secure and efficient exchange of data between different entities, such as organizations, systems, or individuals. It enables the seamless transfer of data in various formats, protocols, or standards, while ensuring data integrity, privacy, and compliance.&#xA;&#xA;Source: International Organization for Standardization (ISO)&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.iso.org/committee/45306/x/catalogue/&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: Data exchange within the context of IT interoperability refers to the seamless and secure transfer of data between different systems, applications, or organizations. It plays a crucial role in enabling efficient and effective communication, collaboration, and integration of digital services within the European Commission's digital public service framework.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, data exchange is a fundamental aspect of ensuring interoperability among various public services and systems. It involves the exchange of structured and standardized data formats, protocols, and interfaces to enable the smooth flow of information across different domains, departments, and entities.&#xA;&#xA;The data exchange process begins with the identification of the data that needs to be shared or accessed by different stakeholders. This data can include various types such as personal information, statistical data, financial records, administrative data, or any other relevant data required for the provision of public services.&#xA;&#xA;To facilitate data exchange, the European Commission adopts a range of interoperability frameworks, standards, and protocols. These frameworks ensure that data is exchanged in a consistent, secure, and reliable manner, regardless of the systems or applications involved. They define common data models, data formats, and communication protocols that enable seamless integration and interoperability between different systems.&#xA;&#xA;Data exchange also involves the establishment of secure and trusted channels for transmitting data. This includes the use of encryption, authentication, and access control mechanisms to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the exchanged data. Additionally, data exchange mechanisms often incorporate error handling, data validation, and synchronization mechanisms to ensure the accuracy and consistency of the transferred data.&#xA;&#xA;Within the European Commission, data exchange is governed by policies, regulations, and legal frameworks that ensure compliance with data protection and privacy laws. These regulations aim to safeguard the rights and privacy of individuals whose data is being exchanged, ensuring that data is processed lawfully and transparently.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, data exchange in the European Commission is not limited to internal systems but also extends to external stakeholders, such as member states, other public administrations, or even private organizations. This enables collaboration, information sharing, and interoperability across different entities involved in the delivery of public services.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, data exchange within the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public service framework is a complex and critical process. It enables the seamless flow of data between systems, applications, and organizations, ensuring efficient and effective delivery of public services while adhering to data protection and privacy regulations.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of Data Exchange in the context of IT interoperability within a digital public service in the European Commission could be the exchange of citizen data between different government agencies. &#xA;&#xA;For instance, let's consider a scenario where a citizen applies for a new passport. The Data Exchange system can facilitate the seamless transfer of relevant information between various entities involved in the process, such as the passport office, immigration department, and law enforcement agencies. This exchange of data can include personal details, biometric information, visa history, and any other relevant data required for the passport application process.&#xA;&#xA;Another example could be the exchange of data between different healthcare providers within the European Commission's digital public service. This could involve sharing patient medical records, test results, and treatment plans between hospitals, clinics, and other healthcare facilities. The Data Exchange system can ensure that the information is securely transmitted and accessible to authorized healthcare professionals, enabling better coordination of care and improved patient outcomes.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the Data Exchange can also facilitate the exchange of data between different government agencies involved in taxation and financial services. For instance, tax authorities can securely exchange taxpayer information with financial institutions to verify income statements, detect tax fraud, and ensure compliance with tax regulations. This exchange of data can streamline processes, reduce administrative burdens, and enhance the accuracy of financial reporting.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the application of Data Exchange within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission can enable seamless data sharing between government agencies, healthcare providers, and financial institutions. This promotes efficiency, improves service delivery, and enhances collaboration among various stakeholders.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Data Exchange Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataExchangeBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:DataExchangeBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataExchangeBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Exchange Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataExchangeBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataExchangeBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Exchange Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:DataExchangeBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="International Organization for Standardization (ISO)"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.iso.org/committee/45306/x/catalogue/"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of Data Exchange in the context of IT interoperability within a digital public service in the European Commission could be the exchange of citizen data between different government agencies. &#xA;&#xA;For instance, let's consider a scenario where a citizen applies for a new passport. The Data Exchange system can facilitate the seamless transfer of relevant information between various entities involved in the process, such as the passport office, immigration department, and law enforcement agencies. This exchange of data can include personal details, biometric information, visa history, and any other relevant data required for the passport application process.&#xA;&#xA;Another example could be the exchange of data between different healthcare providers within the European Commission's digital public service. This could involve sharing patient medical records, test results, and treatment plans between hospitals, clinics, and other healthcare facilities. The Data Exchange system can ensure that the information is securely transmitted and accessible to authorized healthcare professionals, enabling better coordination of care and improved patient outcomes.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the Data Exchange can also facilitate the exchange of data between different government agencies involved in taxation and financial services. For instance, tax authorities can securely exchange taxpayer information with financial institutions to verify income statements, detect tax fraud, and ensure compliance with tax regulations. This exchange of data can streamline processes, reduce administrative burdens, and enhance the accuracy of financial reporting.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the application of Data Exchange within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission can enable seamless data sharing between government agencies, healthcare providers, and financial institutions. This promotes efficiency, improves service delivery, and enhances collaboration among various stakeholders."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="Data exchange within the context of IT interoperability refers to the seamless and secure transfer of data between different systems, applications, or organizations. It plays a crucial role in enabling efficient and effective communication, collaboration, and integration of digital services within the European Commission's digital public service framework.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, data exchange is a fundamental aspect of ensuring interoperability among various public services and systems. It involves the exchange of structured and standardized data formats, protocols, and interfaces to enable the smooth flow of information across different domains, departments, and entities.&#xA;&#xA;The data exchange process begins with the identification of the data that needs to be shared or accessed by different stakeholders. This data can include various types such as personal information, statistical data, financial records, administrative data, or any other relevant data required for the provision of public services.&#xA;&#xA;To facilitate data exchange, the European Commission adopts a range of interoperability frameworks, standards, and protocols. These frameworks ensure that data is exchanged in a consistent, secure, and reliable manner, regardless of the systems or applications involved. They define common data models, data formats, and communication protocols that enable seamless integration and interoperability between different systems.&#xA;&#xA;Data exchange also involves the establishment of secure and trusted channels for transmitting data. This includes the use of encryption, authentication, and access control mechanisms to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the exchanged data. Additionally, data exchange mechanisms often incorporate error handling, data validation, and synchronization mechanisms to ensure the accuracy and consistency of the transferred data.&#xA;&#xA;Within the European Commission, data exchange is governed by policies, regulations, and legal frameworks that ensure compliance with data protection and privacy laws. These regulations aim to safeguard the rights and privacy of individuals whose data is being exchanged, ensuring that data is processed lawfully and transparently.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, data exchange in the European Commission is not limited to internal systems but also extends to external stakeholders, such as member states, other public administrations, or even private organizations. This enables collaboration, information sharing, and interoperability across different entities involved in the delivery of public services.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, data exchange within the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public service framework is a complex and critical process. It enables the seamless flow of data between systems, applications, and organizations, ensuring efficient and effective delivery of public services while adhering to data protection and privacy regulations."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Data exchange business service involves the secure and efficient exchange of data between different entities, such as organizations, systems, or individuals. It enables the seamless transfer of data in various formats, protocols, or standards, while ensuring data integrity, privacy, and compliance."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Data Exchange Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
