<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="eDelivery"
    id="id-8adeed6de2bc48bb8882810d14e31a26"
    documentation="Definition: eDelivery is a crucial component of IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. It refers to a standardized framework that enables secure and reliable exchange of electronic documents and data between different public administrations, businesses, and citizens across European Union member states. eDelivery ensures seamless communication and interoperability by providing a common set of technical specifications, protocols, and security measures for transmitting information in a standardized format. This facilitates the efficient and secure exchange of documents, such as invoices, permits, certificates, and notifications, enhancing the overall effectiveness and accessibility of digital public services within the European Commission.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: eDelivery is a crucial component of IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. It serves as a standardized and secure messaging infrastructure that enables the exchange of electronic documents and data between different entities, such as public administrations, businesses, and citizens, across various European countries.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of eDelivery is to facilitate seamless and reliable communication between these entities, regardless of their geographical location or the underlying technical systems they employ. It ensures that information can be exchanged in a standardized and interoperable manner, eliminating barriers that may arise due to varying protocols, formats, or security measures.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, eDelivery provides a secure and trusted channel for the transmission of digital documents and data. It employs encryption and digital signatures to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of the exchanged information. This guarantees that only authorized recipients can access the content and that it has not been tampered with during transit.&#xA;&#xA;eDelivery also offers a range of additional features and functionalities to enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of digital communication. These include message routing, delivery status notifications, and support for large file transfers. The infrastructure supports both synchronous and asynchronous messaging, allowing real-time interactions as well as deferred exchanges.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eDelivery adheres to open standards and specifications, ensuring that it can seamlessly integrate with existing IT systems and services. It supports various communication protocols, such as AS4, SFTP, and Web Services, enabling interoperability with different messaging platforms and technologies. This flexibility allows organizations to leverage their existing infrastructure investments while still benefiting from the advantages of eDelivery.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, eDelivery plays a vital role in enabling the provision of digital public services across member states. It facilitates the secure exchange of documents and data related to public administration, such as tax filings, permits, notifications, and other official communications. By standardizing and streamlining these interactions, eDelivery contributes to the harmonization of digital services within the European Union, promoting cross-border collaboration and cooperation.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, eDelivery is a fundamental component of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public services landscape. It ensures secure and standardized communication, enabling the efficient exchange of electronic documents and data between various entities. By providing a trusted messaging infrastructure, eDelivery supports the seamless provision of digital public services across European countries, fostering interoperability and collaboration in the digital realm.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of eDelivery within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission is the secure exchange of electronic documents between different government entities. &#xA;&#xA;For instance, let's consider a scenario where a citizen submits an application for a social security benefit online. The application is received by the relevant government department, which needs to securely share the application with other departments involved in the processing and decision-making process.&#xA;&#xA;In this case, eDelivery can be used to ensure the secure and reliable exchange of the application and related documents between the different government entities. The application and supporting documents can be digitally signed and encrypted, ensuring their integrity and confidentiality during transit.&#xA;&#xA;eDelivery provides a standardized and interoperable framework for exchanging electronic documents, regardless of the underlying technical systems used by the different government entities. This allows for seamless integration and communication between various systems, ensuring efficient and secure information exchange.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eDelivery supports the use of different transport protocols, such as AS4, which enables the exchange of large files and ensures reliable delivery. This is particularly important when dealing with complex documents or when multiple documents need to be exchanged as part of a single transaction.&#xA;&#xA;By leveraging eDelivery, the European Commission can enhance the interoperability of its digital public services, enabling seamless and secure communication between different government entities involved in the delivery of services to citizens. This ultimately improves the efficiency, transparency, and reliability of the public service delivery process.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EDeliveryBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:EDeliveryBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EDeliveryBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: eDelivery Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EDeliveryBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EDeliveryBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="eDelivery Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:EDeliveryBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of eDelivery within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service in the European Commission is the secure exchange of electronic documents between different government entities. &#xA;&#xA;For instance, let's consider a scenario where a citizen submits an application for a social security benefit online. The application is received by the relevant government department, which needs to securely share the application with other departments involved in the processing and decision-making process.&#xA;&#xA;In this case, eDelivery can be used to ensure the secure and reliable exchange of the application and related documents between the different government entities. The application and supporting documents can be digitally signed and encrypted, ensuring their integrity and confidentiality during transit.&#xA;&#xA;eDelivery provides a standardized and interoperable framework for exchanging electronic documents, regardless of the underlying technical systems used by the different government entities. This allows for seamless integration and communication between various systems, ensuring efficient and secure information exchange.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eDelivery supports the use of different transport protocols, such as AS4, which enables the exchange of large files and ensures reliable delivery. This is particularly important when dealing with complex documents or when multiple documents need to be exchanged as part of a single transaction.&#xA;&#xA;By leveraging eDelivery, the European Commission can enhance the interoperability of its digital public services, enabling seamless and secure communication between different government entities involved in the delivery of services to citizens. This ultimately improves the efficiency, transparency, and reliability of the public service delivery process."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="eDelivery is a crucial component of IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. It serves as a standardized and secure messaging infrastructure that enables the exchange of electronic documents and data between different entities, such as public administrations, businesses, and citizens, across various European countries.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of eDelivery is to facilitate seamless and reliable communication between these entities, regardless of their geographical location or the underlying technical systems they employ. It ensures that information can be exchanged in a standardized and interoperable manner, eliminating barriers that may arise due to varying protocols, formats, or security measures.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, eDelivery provides a secure and trusted channel for the transmission of digital documents and data. It employs encryption and digital signatures to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of the exchanged information. This guarantees that only authorized recipients can access the content and that it has not been tampered with during transit.&#xA;&#xA;eDelivery also offers a range of additional features and functionalities to enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of digital communication. These include message routing, delivery status notifications, and support for large file transfers. The infrastructure supports both synchronous and asynchronous messaging, allowing real-time interactions as well as deferred exchanges.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eDelivery adheres to open standards and specifications, ensuring that it can seamlessly integrate with existing IT systems and services. It supports various communication protocols, such as AS4, SFTP, and Web Services, enabling interoperability with different messaging platforms and technologies. This flexibility allows organizations to leverage their existing infrastructure investments while still benefiting from the advantages of eDelivery.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, eDelivery plays a vital role in enabling the provision of digital public services across member states. It facilitates the secure exchange of documents and data related to public administration, such as tax filings, permits, notifications, and other official communications. By standardizing and streamlining these interactions, eDelivery contributes to the harmonization of digital services within the European Union, promoting cross-border collaboration and cooperation.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, eDelivery is a fundamental component of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public services landscape. It ensures secure and standardized communication, enabling the efficient exchange of electronic documents and data between various entities. By providing a trusted messaging infrastructure, eDelivery supports the seamless provision of digital public services across European countries, fostering interoperability and collaboration in the digital realm."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="eDelivery is a crucial component of IT interoperability within the context of digital public services in the European Commission. It refers to a standardized framework that enables secure and reliable exchange of electronic documents and data between different public administrations, businesses, and citizens across European Union member states. eDelivery ensures seamless communication and interoperability by providing a common set of technical specifications, protocols, and security measures for transmitting information in a standardized format. This facilitates the efficient and secure exchange of documents, such as invoices, permits, certificates, and notifications, enhancing the overall effectiveness and accessibility of digital public services within the European Commission."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
