<archimate:BusinessObject
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Security Measure"
    id="id-339e54bf-e4fa-4c8a-8c40-8cca507f387b"
    documentation="Definition: Security Measure is data about a precaution taken against terrorism, espionage or other danger&#xA;&#xA;Source: Collins Dictionary&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.collinsdictionary.com/dictionary/english/security-measure#:~:text=(s%C9%AA%CB%88kj%CA%8A%C9%99r%C9%AAt%C9%AA%20%CB%88m%C9%9B%CA%92%C9%99%20),terrorism%2C%20espionage%20or%20other%20danger&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: A security measure, in the context of information technology (IT), refers to a set of actions, procedures, or controls implemented to protect information and systems from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, destruction, or disruption. It encompasses various technical, administrative, and physical safeguards designed to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information within an IT environment.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, security measures are of utmost importance due to the increasing reliance on digital systems and the vast amount of personal and sensitive data processed within the European Union (EU). The EU has established comprehensive regulations and guidelines to safeguard the privacy and security of individuals' data, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Network and Information Security (NIS) Directive.&#xA;&#xA;Security measures can be categorized into different types, including:&#xA;&#xA;1. Technical Measures: These measures involve the use of technology and software to protect information. Examples include encryption, firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention systems, access controls, secure coding practices, and vulnerability management. Technical measures aim to prevent unauthorized access, detect and respond to security incidents, and ensure the secure transmission and storage of data.&#xA;&#xA;2. Administrative Measures: These measures encompass policies, procedures, and guidelines that govern the management and operation of IT systems. They include activities such as risk assessments, security awareness training, incident response planning, access control policies, and regular security audits. Administrative measures focus on establishing a security-conscious culture, defining roles and responsibilities, and ensuring compliance with applicable laws and regulations.&#xA;&#xA;3. Physical Measures: These measures involve securing the physical infrastructure that houses IT systems and sensitive data. They include physical access controls, video surveillance, environmental controls (e.g., temperature and humidity monitoring), and secure disposal of physical media. Physical measures aim to protect against unauthorized physical access, theft, natural disasters, and other physical threats.&#xA;&#xA;4. Organizational Measures: These measures involve the establishment of security-related roles, responsibilities, and governance structures within an organization. They include appointing a Data Protection Officer (DPO) to oversee data protection activities, establishing incident response teams, conducting regular security assessments, and implementing privacy-by-design principles. Organizational measures ensure that security is integrated into the overall business processes and decision-making frameworks.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, security measures must comply with the GDPR, which sets out specific requirements for the protection of personal data. These include implementing appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk, conducting data protection impact assessments, and notifying individuals and relevant authorities in case of a data breach.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, security measures in the European IT context are crucial for protecting sensitive information, ensuring compliance with data protection regulations, and maintaining the trust of individuals and organizations in the digital ecosystem.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of security measures in the European IT context is the implementation of encryption techniques. Encryption is a security measure that involves converting sensitive information into a coded form that can only be accessed by authorized individuals or systems. This ensures that even if the data is intercepted or accessed by unauthorized parties, it remains unreadable and protected.&#xA;&#xA;Another example is the use of multi-factor authentication (MFA) systems. MFA is a security measure that requires users to provide multiple forms of identification, such as a password, a fingerprint scan, or a one-time password, to gain access to a system or application. This adds an extra layer of security by making it more difficult for unauthorized individuals to gain access to sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is another important security measure. GDPR is a set of regulations that aim to protect the privacy and personal data of individuals within the European Union. It requires organizations to implement various security measures, such as data encryption, regular data backups, and access controls, to ensure the protection of personal data.&#xA;&#xA;Firewalls are also commonly used security measures in the European IT context. Firewalls act as a barrier between an internal network and external networks, monitoring and controlling incoming and outgoing network traffic. They help prevent unauthorized access to a network and protect against various types of cyber threats, such as malware and hacking attempts.&#xA;&#xA;Lastly, regular security audits and vulnerability assessments are essential security measures in the European IT context. These involve conducting systematic evaluations of an organization's IT infrastructure, identifying potential vulnerabilities or weaknesses, and implementing necessary measures to mitigate them. This proactive approach helps ensure that security measures are up to date and effective in protecting against emerging threats.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SecurityMeasureBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:SecurityMeasureBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SecurityMeasureBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;Name: Security Measure Information&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SecurityMeasureBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SecurityMeasureBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:SecurityMeasureBusinessObject"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Security Measure Information"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Collins Dictionary"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.collinsdictionary.com/dictionary/english/security-measure#:~:text=(s%C9%AA%CB%88kj%CA%8A%C9%99r%C9%AAt%C9%AA%20%CB%88m%C9%9B%CA%92%C9%99%20),terrorism%2C%20espionage%20or%20other%20danger"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of security measures in the European IT context is the implementation of encryption techniques. Encryption is a security measure that involves converting sensitive information into a coded form that can only be accessed by authorized individuals or systems. This ensures that even if the data is intercepted or accessed by unauthorized parties, it remains unreadable and protected.&#xA;&#xA;Another example is the use of multi-factor authentication (MFA) systems. MFA is a security measure that requires users to provide multiple forms of identification, such as a password, a fingerprint scan, or a one-time password, to gain access to a system or application. This adds an extra layer of security by making it more difficult for unauthorized individuals to gain access to sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is another important security measure. GDPR is a set of regulations that aim to protect the privacy and personal data of individuals within the European Union. It requires organizations to implement various security measures, such as data encryption, regular data backups, and access controls, to ensure the protection of personal data.&#xA;&#xA;Firewalls are also commonly used security measures in the European IT context. Firewalls act as a barrier between an internal network and external networks, monitoring and controlling incoming and outgoing network traffic. They help prevent unauthorized access to a network and protect against various types of cyber threats, such as malware and hacking attempts.&#xA;&#xA;Lastly, regular security audits and vulnerability assessments are essential security measures in the European IT context. These involve conducting systematic evaluations of an organization's IT infrastructure, identifying potential vulnerabilities or weaknesses, and implementing necessary measures to mitigate them. This proactive approach helps ensure that security measures are up to date and effective in protecting against emerging threats."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="A security measure, in the context of information technology (IT), refers to a set of actions, procedures, or controls implemented to protect information and systems from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, destruction, or disruption. It encompasses various technical, administrative, and physical safeguards designed to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information within an IT environment.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, security measures are of utmost importance due to the increasing reliance on digital systems and the vast amount of personal and sensitive data processed within the European Union (EU). The EU has established comprehensive regulations and guidelines to safeguard the privacy and security of individuals' data, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Network and Information Security (NIS) Directive.&#xA;&#xA;Security measures can be categorized into different types, including:&#xA;&#xA;1. Technical Measures: These measures involve the use of technology and software to protect information. Examples include encryption, firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention systems, access controls, secure coding practices, and vulnerability management. Technical measures aim to prevent unauthorized access, detect and respond to security incidents, and ensure the secure transmission and storage of data.&#xA;&#xA;2. Administrative Measures: These measures encompass policies, procedures, and guidelines that govern the management and operation of IT systems. They include activities such as risk assessments, security awareness training, incident response planning, access control policies, and regular security audits. Administrative measures focus on establishing a security-conscious culture, defining roles and responsibilities, and ensuring compliance with applicable laws and regulations.&#xA;&#xA;3. Physical Measures: These measures involve securing the physical infrastructure that houses IT systems and sensitive data. They include physical access controls, video surveillance, environmental controls (e.g., temperature and humidity monitoring), and secure disposal of physical media. Physical measures aim to protect against unauthorized physical access, theft, natural disasters, and other physical threats.&#xA;&#xA;4. Organizational Measures: These measures involve the establishment of security-related roles, responsibilities, and governance structures within an organization. They include appointing a Data Protection Officer (DPO) to oversee data protection activities, establishing incident response teams, conducting regular security assessments, and implementing privacy-by-design principles. Organizational measures ensure that security is integrated into the overall business processes and decision-making frameworks.&#xA;&#xA;In the European IT context, security measures must comply with the GDPR, which sets out specific requirements for the protection of personal data. These include implementing appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk, conducting data protection impact assessments, and notifying individuals and relevant authorities in case of a data breach.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, security measures in the European IT context are crucial for protecting sensitive information, ensuring compliance with data protection regulations, and maintaining the trust of individuals and organizations in the digital ecosystem."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Security Measure is data about a precaution taken against terrorism, espionage or other danger"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/InformationBusinessObject"/>
</archimate:BusinessObject>
