<archimate:BusinessRole
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Software Architect"
    id="id-6abb220435d8420f8a0363f8a19add12"
    documentation="Definition: A Software Architect is a technology professional who designs and manages the structure of software systems. They are responsible for creating the fundamental architecture that underpins a software program, ensuring it meets the needs of users and business requirements. Their role involves making high-level design choices, dictating technical standards, including software coding standards, tools, and platforms. They often work closely with stakeholders and other IT members to guide the software project from its conceptualization to its final product, making sure it's scalable, maintainable, and high-performing.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: A Software Architect is a key role in the field of software development. This individual is responsible for making high-level design choices and for dictating technical standards, including software coding standards, tools, and platforms. They are involved in all stages of the software development life cycle, from initial concept, through design, development, testing, and deployment.&#xA;&#xA;The Software Architect's role is multifaceted. They are responsible for understanding the business requirements and translating them into a software solution. They must have a deep understanding of the system being developed and be able to make decisions about the most suitable architecture and technologies to use. They must also be able to foresee potential problems and design the system in a way that avoids them.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, the Software Architect is responsible for ensuring that the system is scalable, reliable, and efficient. They must consider factors such as performance, security, and maintainability. They also need to ensure that the architecture is flexible enough to accommodate future changes and enhancements.&#xA;&#xA;The Software Architect often acts as a technical leader within the development team. They provide guidance and support to the developers, helping them to understand the architecture and to implement it correctly. They also liaise with other stakeholders, such as project managers and business analysts, to ensure that the system meets the business needs.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the Software Architect is responsible for creating and maintaining documentation of the system architecture. This includes diagrams and descriptions of the system's components, their relationships, and their interactions. This documentation is crucial for understanding the system, for maintaining it, and for making future enhancements.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Software Architect plays a crucial role in software development. They are responsible for designing the system's architecture, for making key technical decisions, for guiding the development team, and for ensuring that the system meets the business requirements and is of high quality.&#xA;&#xA;Example: 1. Enterprise Software Architect: This role involves designing and implementing software architecture for an entire organization. The enterprise software architect works closely with various departments to understand their needs and ensure the software solutions meet those needs. They also oversee the integration of different software systems across the organization.&#xA;&#xA;2. Solution Software Architect: This role focuses on designing and implementing software solutions for specific business problems. They work closely with business analysts and project managers to understand the requirements and constraints of the solution. They then design the software architecture and oversee its implementation.&#xA;&#xA;3. Application Software Architect: This role involves designing the architecture for specific software applications. The application software architect works closely with software developers and engineers to ensure the application is designed and built according to the architectural plan.&#xA;&#xA;4. System Software Architect: This role involves designing the architecture for system software such as operating systems, database systems, and middleware. They work closely with system engineers and developers to ensure the system software is designed and built according to the architectural plan.&#xA;&#xA;5. Cloud Software Architect: This role involves designing and implementing software architecture for cloud-based systems. The cloud software architect works closely with cloud engineers and developers to ensure the cloud systems are designed and built according to the architectural plan.&#xA;&#xA;6. Data Architect: This role involves designing and implementing data architecture, including data models, database architecture, and data warehousing solutions. They work closely with data engineers and analysts to ensure the data architecture supports the organization's data needs.&#xA;&#xA;7. Software Architect Consultant: This role involves providing expert advice and guidance on software architecture to organizations. The software architect consultant may be hired to design a new software architecture, review an existing architecture, or provide training on software architecture best practices.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: [A] How to read the model&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SoftwareArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:SoftwareArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:None&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-19&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SoftwareArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;Name: Software Architect Business-role&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SoftwareArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-19"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/SoftwareArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:SoftwareArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Software Architect Business-role"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="1. Enterprise Software Architect: This role involves designing and implementing software architecture for an entire organization. The enterprise software architect works closely with various departments to understand their needs and ensure the software solutions meet those needs. They also oversee the integration of different software systems across the organization.&#xA;&#xA;2. Solution Software Architect: This role focuses on designing and implementing software solutions for specific business problems. They work closely with business analysts and project managers to understand the requirements and constraints of the solution. They then design the software architecture and oversee its implementation.&#xA;&#xA;3. Application Software Architect: This role involves designing the architecture for specific software applications. The application software architect works closely with software developers and engineers to ensure the application is designed and built according to the architectural plan.&#xA;&#xA;4. System Software Architect: This role involves designing the architecture for system software such as operating systems, database systems, and middleware. They work closely with system engineers and developers to ensure the system software is designed and built according to the architectural plan.&#xA;&#xA;5. Cloud Software Architect: This role involves designing and implementing software architecture for cloud-based systems. The cloud software architect works closely with cloud engineers and developers to ensure the cloud systems are designed and built according to the architectural plan.&#xA;&#xA;6. Data Architect: This role involves designing and implementing data architecture, including data models, database architecture, and data warehousing solutions. They work closely with data engineers and analysts to ensure the data architecture supports the organization's data needs.&#xA;&#xA;7. Software Architect Consultant: This role involves providing expert advice and guidance on software architecture to organizations. The software architect consultant may be hired to design a new software architecture, review an existing architecture, or provide training on software architecture best practices."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:None"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="A Software Architect is a key role in the field of software development. This individual is responsible for making high-level design choices and for dictating technical standards, including software coding standards, tools, and platforms. They are involved in all stages of the software development life cycle, from initial concept, through design, development, testing, and deployment.&#xA;&#xA;The Software Architect's role is multifaceted. They are responsible for understanding the business requirements and translating them into a software solution. They must have a deep understanding of the system being developed and be able to make decisions about the most suitable architecture and technologies to use. They must also be able to foresee potential problems and design the system in a way that avoids them.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, the Software Architect is responsible for ensuring that the system is scalable, reliable, and efficient. They must consider factors such as performance, security, and maintainability. They also need to ensure that the architecture is flexible enough to accommodate future changes and enhancements.&#xA;&#xA;The Software Architect often acts as a technical leader within the development team. They provide guidance and support to the developers, helping them to understand the architecture and to implement it correctly. They also liaise with other stakeholders, such as project managers and business analysts, to ensure that the system meets the business needs.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the Software Architect is responsible for creating and maintaining documentation of the system architecture. This includes diagrams and descriptions of the system's components, their relationships, and their interactions. This documentation is crucial for understanding the system, for maintaining it, and for making future enhancements.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Software Architect plays a crucial role in software development. They are responsible for designing the system's architecture, for making key technical decisions, for guiding the development team, and for ensuring that the system meets the business requirements and is of high quality."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="A Software Architect is a technology professional who designs and manages the structure of software systems. They are responsible for creating the fundamental architecture that underpins a software program, ensuring it meets the needs of users and business requirements. Their role involves making high-level design choices, dictating technical standards, including software coding standards, tools, and platforms. They often work closely with stakeholders and other IT members to guide the software project from its conceptualization to its final product, making sure it's scalable, maintainable, and high-performing."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="[A] How to read the model"/>
</archimate:BusinessRole>
