<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Contact Management"
    id="id-224bd7a8623549468fce2da1a7b293ce"
    documentation="Definition: Contact Management enables the storage and the organisation of contacts of a public administration's user base (both providers and consumers of its public services), and the tracking of the related interactions.&#xA;&#xA;Source: Aberdeen Group&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: http://download.act.com/act2010/docs/Choice_Between_Contact_Management_or_CRM.pdf&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: Contact management within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission refers to the systematic and efficient management of all contacts and interactions with various stakeholders, including individuals, organizations, and entities involved in the provision and consumption of digital services.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of contact management is to establish and maintain effective communication channels, ensuring seamless information exchange and collaboration between different parties involved in the digital public service ecosystem. It encompasses a range of activities, tools, and processes that facilitate the collection, organization, storage, retrieval, and analysis of contact-related data.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, contact management involves the creation and maintenance of a centralized repository or database that stores comprehensive and up-to-date information about each contact. This information typically includes contact details such as names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, and organizational affiliations. Additionally, it may also include specific attributes or categorizations related to the contact, such as their role, responsibilities, preferences, and any previous interactions or engagements with the digital public service.&#xA;&#xA;The contact management system enables the European Commission to effectively manage and track interactions with various stakeholders. It allows for the recording and tracking of communication history, ensuring that all relevant information is readily available for reference and analysis. This includes details of meetings, emails, phone calls, and any other form of communication that has taken place between the digital public service and the contact.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, contact management also facilitates the coordination and scheduling of meetings, events, and other engagements with stakeholders. It enables the European Commission to efficiently plan and organize interactions, ensuring that the right people are involved at the right time. This may involve features such as calendar integration, reminders, and notifications to ensure timely and effective communication.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to managing individual contacts, contact management within the European Commission's digital public service also involves the management of contact lists or groups. These lists can be created based on various criteria, such as organizational affiliations, roles, or specific interests. They allow for targeted communication and engagement with specific segments of stakeholders, ensuring that relevant information reaches the intended audience.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, contact management may also involve integration with other IT systems and tools used within the European Commission. This integration enables seamless data exchange and synchronization between contact management and other systems, such as customer relationship management (CRM) systems, email clients, or collaboration platforms. It ensures that contact information remains consistent and up-to-date across different systems, avoiding duplication or discrepancies.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, contact management plays a crucial role in facilitating effective communication, collaboration, and engagement within the digital public service ecosystem of the European Commission. It ensures that stakeholders are appropriately informed, involved, and supported throughout their interactions with the digital public service, ultimately contributing to the successful delivery of services and the achievement of organizational goals.&#xA;&#xA;Example: Contact management is a crucial aspect of IT interoperability within the context of a digital public service in the European Commission. It ensures efficient communication and collaboration between different stakeholders involved in the service. Here are some examples of how contact management can be applied:&#xA;&#xA;1. Stakeholder Engagement: The digital public service may involve multiple stakeholders such as government agencies, citizens, businesses, and other organizations. Contact management allows for the effective management of contact information for each stakeholder, ensuring seamless communication and engagement throughout the service's lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;2. Interagency Collaboration: Within the European Commission, various departments and agencies may be involved in the development and delivery of the digital public service. Contact management enables the establishment and maintenance of contact lists for different agencies, facilitating collaboration, information sharing, and coordination between them.&#xA;&#xA;3. User Support: Contact management plays a vital role in providing user support for the digital public service. It allows for the management of contact details of users seeking assistance or reporting issues. This ensures that users can easily reach out for help, and their queries or problems are efficiently addressed by the appropriate support team.&#xA;&#xA;4. Vendor Management: The digital public service may rely on external vendors or service providers for certain components or functionalities. Contact management helps in maintaining contact information for these vendors, enabling effective communication, contract management, and issue resolution.&#xA;&#xA;5. Stakeholder Notifications: Contact management facilitates the dissemination of important notifications, updates, or announcements to relevant stakeholders. It ensures that the right information reaches the right individuals or groups, helping to keep them informed and engaged throughout the service's lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;6. Data Sharing and Integration: Contact management can also support data sharing and integration efforts within the digital public service. By maintaining accurate and up-to-date contact information, it becomes easier to exchange data with other systems or services, ensuring interoperability and seamless information flow.&#xA;&#xA;7. Event Management: The digital public service may organize events, workshops, or training sessions involving various stakeholders. Contact management assists in managing attendee lists, sending invitations, and tracking RSVPs, ensuring smooth event coordination and participation.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, contact management within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service at the European Commission enables effective stakeholder engagement, interagency collaboration, user support, vendor management, stakeholder notifications, data sharing, and event management.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Data Management Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContactManagementBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:ContactManagementBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContactManagementBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: Contact Management Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContactManagementBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ContactManagementBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Contact Management Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:ContactManagementBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Aberdeen Group"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="http://download.act.com/act2010/docs/Choice_Between_Contact_Management_or_CRM.pdf"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="Contact management is a crucial aspect of IT interoperability within the context of a digital public service in the European Commission. It ensures efficient communication and collaboration between different stakeholders involved in the service. Here are some examples of how contact management can be applied:&#xA;&#xA;1. Stakeholder Engagement: The digital public service may involve multiple stakeholders such as government agencies, citizens, businesses, and other organizations. Contact management allows for the effective management of contact information for each stakeholder, ensuring seamless communication and engagement throughout the service's lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;2. Interagency Collaboration: Within the European Commission, various departments and agencies may be involved in the development and delivery of the digital public service. Contact management enables the establishment and maintenance of contact lists for different agencies, facilitating collaboration, information sharing, and coordination between them.&#xA;&#xA;3. User Support: Contact management plays a vital role in providing user support for the digital public service. It allows for the management of contact details of users seeking assistance or reporting issues. This ensures that users can easily reach out for help, and their queries or problems are efficiently addressed by the appropriate support team.&#xA;&#xA;4. Vendor Management: The digital public service may rely on external vendors or service providers for certain components or functionalities. Contact management helps in maintaining contact information for these vendors, enabling effective communication, contract management, and issue resolution.&#xA;&#xA;5. Stakeholder Notifications: Contact management facilitates the dissemination of important notifications, updates, or announcements to relevant stakeholders. It ensures that the right information reaches the right individuals or groups, helping to keep them informed and engaged throughout the service's lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;6. Data Sharing and Integration: Contact management can also support data sharing and integration efforts within the digital public service. By maintaining accurate and up-to-date contact information, it becomes easier to exchange data with other systems or services, ensuring interoperability and seamless information flow.&#xA;&#xA;7. Event Management: The digital public service may organize events, workshops, or training sessions involving various stakeholders. Contact management assists in managing attendee lists, sending invitations, and tracking RSVPs, ensuring smooth event coordination and participation.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, contact management within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service at the European Commission enables effective stakeholder engagement, interagency collaboration, user support, vendor management, stakeholder notifications, data sharing, and event management."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="Contact management within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service within the European Commission refers to the systematic and efficient management of all contacts and interactions with various stakeholders, including individuals, organizations, and entities involved in the provision and consumption of digital services.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of contact management is to establish and maintain effective communication channels, ensuring seamless information exchange and collaboration between different parties involved in the digital public service ecosystem. It encompasses a range of activities, tools, and processes that facilitate the collection, organization, storage, retrieval, and analysis of contact-related data.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, contact management involves the creation and maintenance of a centralized repository or database that stores comprehensive and up-to-date information about each contact. This information typically includes contact details such as names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, and organizational affiliations. Additionally, it may also include specific attributes or categorizations related to the contact, such as their role, responsibilities, preferences, and any previous interactions or engagements with the digital public service.&#xA;&#xA;The contact management system enables the European Commission to effectively manage and track interactions with various stakeholders. It allows for the recording and tracking of communication history, ensuring that all relevant information is readily available for reference and analysis. This includes details of meetings, emails, phone calls, and any other form of communication that has taken place between the digital public service and the contact.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, contact management also facilitates the coordination and scheduling of meetings, events, and other engagements with stakeholders. It enables the European Commission to efficiently plan and organize interactions, ensuring that the right people are involved at the right time. This may involve features such as calendar integration, reminders, and notifications to ensure timely and effective communication.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to managing individual contacts, contact management within the European Commission's digital public service also involves the management of contact lists or groups. These lists can be created based on various criteria, such as organizational affiliations, roles, or specific interests. They allow for targeted communication and engagement with specific segments of stakeholders, ensuring that relevant information reaches the intended audience.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, contact management may also involve integration with other IT systems and tools used within the European Commission. This integration enables seamless data exchange and synchronization between contact management and other systems, such as customer relationship management (CRM) systems, email clients, or collaboration platforms. It ensures that contact information remains consistent and up-to-date across different systems, avoiding duplication or discrepancies.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, contact management plays a crucial role in facilitating effective communication, collaboration, and engagement within the digital public service ecosystem of the European Commission. It ensures that stakeholders are appropriately informed, involved, and supported throughout their interactions with the digital public service, ultimately contributing to the successful delivery of services and the achievement of organizational goals."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Contact Management enables the storage and the organisation of contacts of a public administration's user base (both providers and consumers of its public services), and the tracking of the related interactions."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Data Management Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
