<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Digital Inmutability"
    id="id-c38d28c689254e0e8737ea338beff5d3"
    documentation="Definition: Digital immutability within the context of IT interoperability refers to the characteristic of data or information that cannot be altered, tampered with, or modified once it has been recorded or stored in a digital format. In the context of a digital public service in the European Commission, digital immutability ensures that the data and information provided by the service remain unchanged and trustworthy throughout its lifecycle. This ensures transparency, accountability, and reliability of the digital service, allowing users to have confidence in the integrity and authenticity of the information they access or interact with.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: Digital immutability refers to the characteristic of data or information that cannot be altered, tampered with, or modified once it has been recorded or stored in a digital system. In the context of IT interoperability within a digital public service in the European Commission, digital immutability ensures the integrity and reliability of data throughout its lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, digital public services are designed to provide efficient and transparent services to citizens, businesses, and other stakeholders. These services rely heavily on the use of digital systems and technologies to process, store, and exchange data. To ensure trust and confidence in these services, it is crucial to maintain the immutability of digital information.&#xA;&#xA;Immutability is achieved through the use of various cryptographic techniques and technologies. When data is created or received, it is digitally signed using cryptographic algorithms. This digital signature acts as a unique identifier and proof of authenticity for the data. Any attempt to modify the data after it has been signed will result in the invalidation of the signature, thus indicating tampering or unauthorized changes.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, digital immutability is reinforced by the use of distributed ledger technologies, such as blockchain. In a blockchain-based system, data is stored in a decentralized and distributed manner across multiple nodes or computers. Each transaction or change made to the data is recorded in a block, which is linked to the previous blocks in a chain-like structure. Once a block is added to the chain, it becomes virtually impossible to alter or delete the information it contains, ensuring the immutability of the data.&#xA;&#xA;The concept of digital immutability is crucial for IT interoperability within the European Commission's digital public services. It ensures that data exchanged between different systems and platforms remains consistent and trustworthy. By maintaining the integrity of data, digital immutability enables seamless integration and interoperability between various IT systems, allowing for efficient and secure data sharing.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, digital immutability plays a vital role in ensuring compliance with legal and regulatory requirements. In the European Commission, where privacy and data protection are of utmost importance, digital immutability helps to prevent unauthorized access, manipulation, or deletion of sensitive information. It provides a robust mechanism to demonstrate the integrity and authenticity of data, which is essential for legal proceedings, audits, and accountability.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, digital immutability within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service of the European Commission refers to the ability to maintain the integrity and reliability of data throughout its lifecycle. It is achieved through cryptographic techniques, digital signatures, and distributed ledger technologies like blockchain. By ensuring the immutability of data, the European Commission can provide trustworthy and transparent digital public services while complying with legal and regulatory requirements.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of digital immutability within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service at the European Commission is the use of blockchain technology. Blockchain provides a decentralized and transparent system that ensures the immutability of data and enhances interoperability between different systems.&#xA;&#xA;In this scenario, the European Commission could utilize blockchain to maintain a secure and tamper-proof record of various public service transactions. For instance, when a citizen interacts with different government agencies or departments, their data and interactions could be recorded on a blockchain. This would create an immutable audit trail that can be accessed by authorized parties, ensuring transparency and trust in the system.&#xA;&#xA;By leveraging digital immutability through blockchain, the European Commission can enhance interoperability between different public service providers. For example, if a citizen applies for a passport renewal, the relevant information and documents can be securely shared across different departments involved in the process, such as the passport office, immigration authorities, and law enforcement agencies. The immutability of the blockchain ensures that the shared data remains unchanged and can be trusted by all parties involved.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, digital immutability can also be applied to ensure the integrity of digital signatures and certificates used in the European Commission's public services. By utilizing blockchain technology, the Commission can create a decentralized and tamper-proof system for issuing and verifying digital signatures. This would enhance interoperability by enabling different systems and applications to trust and validate digital signatures across various public service processes.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of digital immutability, particularly through blockchain technology, can significantly enhance IT interoperability within the context of a digital public service at the European Commission. It ensures the integrity of data, enhances transparency, and enables secure sharing of information between different departments and agencies involved in delivering public services.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Trust Enablers [Motivation]&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInmutabilityBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:DigitalInmutabilityBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInmutabilityBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: Digital Inmutability Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInmutabilityBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInmutabilityBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Digital Inmutability Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:DigitalInmutabilityBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of digital immutability within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service at the European Commission is the use of blockchain technology. Blockchain provides a decentralized and transparent system that ensures the immutability of data and enhances interoperability between different systems.&#xA;&#xA;In this scenario, the European Commission could utilize blockchain to maintain a secure and tamper-proof record of various public service transactions. For instance, when a citizen interacts with different government agencies or departments, their data and interactions could be recorded on a blockchain. This would create an immutable audit trail that can be accessed by authorized parties, ensuring transparency and trust in the system.&#xA;&#xA;By leveraging digital immutability through blockchain, the European Commission can enhance interoperability between different public service providers. For example, if a citizen applies for a passport renewal, the relevant information and documents can be securely shared across different departments involved in the process, such as the passport office, immigration authorities, and law enforcement agencies. The immutability of the blockchain ensures that the shared data remains unchanged and can be trusted by all parties involved.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, digital immutability can also be applied to ensure the integrity of digital signatures and certificates used in the European Commission's public services. By utilizing blockchain technology, the Commission can create a decentralized and tamper-proof system for issuing and verifying digital signatures. This would enhance interoperability by enabling different systems and applications to trust and validate digital signatures across various public service processes.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of digital immutability, particularly through blockchain technology, can significantly enhance IT interoperability within the context of a digital public service at the European Commission. It ensures the integrity of data, enhances transparency, and enables secure sharing of information between different departments and agencies involved in delivering public services."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="Digital immutability refers to the characteristic of data or information that cannot be altered, tampered with, or modified once it has been recorded or stored in a digital system. In the context of IT interoperability within a digital public service in the European Commission, digital immutability ensures the integrity and reliability of data throughout its lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission, digital public services are designed to provide efficient and transparent services to citizens, businesses, and other stakeholders. These services rely heavily on the use of digital systems and technologies to process, store, and exchange data. To ensure trust and confidence in these services, it is crucial to maintain the immutability of digital information.&#xA;&#xA;Immutability is achieved through the use of various cryptographic techniques and technologies. When data is created or received, it is digitally signed using cryptographic algorithms. This digital signature acts as a unique identifier and proof of authenticity for the data. Any attempt to modify the data after it has been signed will result in the invalidation of the signature, thus indicating tampering or unauthorized changes.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, digital immutability is reinforced by the use of distributed ledger technologies, such as blockchain. In a blockchain-based system, data is stored in a decentralized and distributed manner across multiple nodes or computers. Each transaction or change made to the data is recorded in a block, which is linked to the previous blocks in a chain-like structure. Once a block is added to the chain, it becomes virtually impossible to alter or delete the information it contains, ensuring the immutability of the data.&#xA;&#xA;The concept of digital immutability is crucial for IT interoperability within the European Commission's digital public services. It ensures that data exchanged between different systems and platforms remains consistent and trustworthy. By maintaining the integrity of data, digital immutability enables seamless integration and interoperability between various IT systems, allowing for efficient and secure data sharing.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, digital immutability plays a vital role in ensuring compliance with legal and regulatory requirements. In the European Commission, where privacy and data protection are of utmost importance, digital immutability helps to prevent unauthorized access, manipulation, or deletion of sensitive information. It provides a robust mechanism to demonstrate the integrity and authenticity of data, which is essential for legal proceedings, audits, and accountability.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, digital immutability within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service of the European Commission refers to the ability to maintain the integrity and reliability of data throughout its lifecycle. It is achieved through cryptographic techniques, digital signatures, and distributed ledger technologies like blockchain. By ensuring the immutability of data, the European Commission can provide trustworthy and transparent digital public services while complying with legal and regulatory requirements."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Digital immutability within the context of IT interoperability refers to the characteristic of data or information that cannot be altered, tampered with, or modified once it has been recorded or stored in a digital format. In the context of a digital public service in the European Commission, digital immutability ensures that the data and information provided by the service remain unchanged and trustworthy throughout its lifecycle. This ensures transparency, accountability, and reliability of the digital service, allowing users to have confidence in the integrity and authenticity of the information they access or interact with."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Trust Enablers [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
