<archimate:BusinessRole
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Infrastructure Architect"
    id="id-ed611a3ee1cc469682c27fe00c96af05"
    documentation="Definition: An Infrastructure Architect is a professional responsible for designing, implementing, and managing the IT infrastructure of an organization. This includes the development and maintenance of networks, servers, software, and hardware systems to ensure optimal performance and security. They also work closely with other IT professionals to align the infrastructure with the business goals, assess system requirements, and troubleshoot any issues that arise. Their role is crucial in the strategic planning of an organization's IT framework, considering factors such as cost efficiency, scalability, and technological advancements.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: An Infrastructure Architect is a key role in the field of information technology. This professional is responsible for designing, implementing, and managing the infrastructure of an organization's IT landscape. The infrastructure typically includes hardware, software, networks, data centers, and various services. &#xA;&#xA;The Infrastructure Architect's primary responsibility is to ensure that all aspects of an organization's technical systems align with its business goals. They are involved in every phase of a system's lifecycle, from initial design through implementation, maintenance, and eventual retirement or replacement.&#xA;&#xA;The Infrastructure Architect's role involves a wide range of tasks. They must analyze the current state of the organization's infrastructure, identify weaknesses or inefficiencies, and propose improvements. They also need to stay current with the latest technologies and trends in IT infrastructure, and determine how these could be applied to benefit the organization.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, the Infrastructure Architect must work closely with other IT professionals, such as network engineers, system administrators, and software developers, to ensure that all components of the infrastructure work together seamlessly. They also need to coordinate with business leaders and stakeholders to understand their needs and ensure that the infrastructure supports them.&#xA;&#xA;The Infrastructure Architect is also responsible for creating and maintaining documentation of the infrastructure, including diagrams, specifications, and policies. They may also be involved in training staff on the use and maintenance of the infrastructure.&#xA;&#xA;In terms of skills, an Infrastructure Architect needs a deep understanding of various technologies, including servers, storage systems, networks, and software applications. They also need strong problem-solving skills, the ability to think strategically, and excellent communication skills. A degree in computer science or a related field, as well as several years of experience in IT, are typically required for this role. &#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Infrastructure Architect plays a crucial role in shaping and maintaining the IT backbone of an organization, ensuring that it is robust, efficient, and aligned with the organization's business objectives.&#xA;&#xA;Example: 1. Cloud Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and managing cloud-based systems and services for a company. This includes selecting appropriate cloud services, setting up virtual servers and networks, and ensuring the security and efficiency of cloud infrastructure.&#xA;&#xA;2. Network Infrastructure Architect: This professional is responsible for designing and implementing computer networks within an organization. They determine the layout of cables, network devices, and servers, and they ensure that these elements are secure and efficient.&#xA;&#xA;3. IT Infrastructure Architect: This role involves planning and designing the IT infrastructure that supports an organization's business operations. This includes determining the hardware, software, and network resources needed, as well as overseeing the installation and maintenance of these systems.&#xA;&#xA;4. Enterprise Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and implementing IT solutions that support the strategic objectives of a large organization. They work closely with other IT professionals and business leaders to understand the organization's needs and to ensure that the IT infrastructure meets these needs.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Center Infrastructure Architect: This professional is responsible for designing and managing the physical and virtual infrastructure of a data center. This includes servers, storage systems, network devices, and security systems.&#xA;&#xA;6. Solutions Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and implementing IT solutions that meet the specific needs of a business. This could involve integrating different systems, designing custom software, or implementing new technologies.&#xA;&#xA;7. Security Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and implementing security systems to protect an organization's IT infrastructure. This includes firewalls, intrusion detection systems, encryption technologies, and other security measures.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: [A] How to read the model&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InfrastructureArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:InfrastructureArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:None&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-19&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InfrastructureArchitectBusinessRole&#xA;&#xA;Name: Infrastructure Architect Business-role&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InfrastructureArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-19"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InfrastructureArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:InfrastructureArchitectBusinessRole"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Infrastructure Architect Business-role"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="1. Cloud Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and managing cloud-based systems and services for a company. This includes selecting appropriate cloud services, setting up virtual servers and networks, and ensuring the security and efficiency of cloud infrastructure.&#xA;&#xA;2. Network Infrastructure Architect: This professional is responsible for designing and implementing computer networks within an organization. They determine the layout of cables, network devices, and servers, and they ensure that these elements are secure and efficient.&#xA;&#xA;3. IT Infrastructure Architect: This role involves planning and designing the IT infrastructure that supports an organization's business operations. This includes determining the hardware, software, and network resources needed, as well as overseeing the installation and maintenance of these systems.&#xA;&#xA;4. Enterprise Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and implementing IT solutions that support the strategic objectives of a large organization. They work closely with other IT professionals and business leaders to understand the organization's needs and to ensure that the IT infrastructure meets these needs.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Center Infrastructure Architect: This professional is responsible for designing and managing the physical and virtual infrastructure of a data center. This includes servers, storage systems, network devices, and security systems.&#xA;&#xA;6. Solutions Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and implementing IT solutions that meet the specific needs of a business. This could involve integrating different systems, designing custom software, or implementing new technologies.&#xA;&#xA;7. Security Infrastructure Architect: This role involves designing and implementing security systems to protect an organization's IT infrastructure. This includes firewalls, intrusion detection systems, encryption technologies, and other security measures."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:None"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="An Infrastructure Architect is a key role in the field of information technology. This professional is responsible for designing, implementing, and managing the infrastructure of an organization's IT landscape. The infrastructure typically includes hardware, software, networks, data centers, and various services. &#xA;&#xA;The Infrastructure Architect's primary responsibility is to ensure that all aspects of an organization's technical systems align with its business goals. They are involved in every phase of a system's lifecycle, from initial design through implementation, maintenance, and eventual retirement or replacement.&#xA;&#xA;The Infrastructure Architect's role involves a wide range of tasks. They must analyze the current state of the organization's infrastructure, identify weaknesses or inefficiencies, and propose improvements. They also need to stay current with the latest technologies and trends in IT infrastructure, and determine how these could be applied to benefit the organization.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, the Infrastructure Architect must work closely with other IT professionals, such as network engineers, system administrators, and software developers, to ensure that all components of the infrastructure work together seamlessly. They also need to coordinate with business leaders and stakeholders to understand their needs and ensure that the infrastructure supports them.&#xA;&#xA;The Infrastructure Architect is also responsible for creating and maintaining documentation of the infrastructure, including diagrams, specifications, and policies. They may also be involved in training staff on the use and maintenance of the infrastructure.&#xA;&#xA;In terms of skills, an Infrastructure Architect needs a deep understanding of various technologies, including servers, storage systems, networks, and software applications. They also need strong problem-solving skills, the ability to think strategically, and excellent communication skills. A degree in computer science or a related field, as well as several years of experience in IT, are typically required for this role. &#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Infrastructure Architect plays a crucial role in shaping and maintaining the IT backbone of an organization, ensuring that it is robust, efficient, and aligned with the organization's business objectives."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="An Infrastructure Architect is a professional responsible for designing, implementing, and managing the IT infrastructure of an organization. This includes the development and maintenance of networks, servers, software, and hardware systems to ensure optimal performance and security. They also work closely with other IT professionals to align the infrastructure with the business goals, assess system requirements, and troubleshoot any issues that arise. Their role is crucial in the strategic planning of an organization's IT framework, considering factors such as cost efficiency, scalability, and technological advancements."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="[A] How to read the model"/>
</archimate:BusinessRole>
