<archimate:BusinessService
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="eIdentification"
    id="id-4977ee29fc50404aa299656f90a0eba7"
    documentation="Definition: eIdentification, within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service of the European Commission, refers to the process of verifying and authenticating the identity of individuals or entities accessing online services. It involves the use of digital credentials, such as electronic identity cards or digital signatures, to establish trust and ensure secure access to various online platforms and services. eIdentification plays a crucial role in enabling seamless and secure interactions between users and digital public services, facilitating the exchange of information and promoting interoperability across different systems and organizations.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: eIdentification, within the context of IT interoperability, refers to the process of electronically verifying and authenticating the identity of individuals or entities in a digital public service provided by the European Commission. It involves the use of digital technologies and standardized protocols to establish the identity of users accessing online services, ensuring secure and reliable interactions between different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission's digital public service, eIdentification plays a crucial role in enabling seamless and trusted electronic transactions, as well as facilitating the exchange of information and data across various government departments, agencies, and organizations. It aims to provide a unified and standardized approach to identity verification, eliminating the need for multiple, separate identification processes for different services.&#xA;&#xA;The eIdentification system incorporates various elements to ensure the security and integrity of digital identities. It typically involves the use of unique identifiers, such as usernames or email addresses, along with strong authentication mechanisms, such as passwords, PINs, or biometric data, to verify the identity of users. These authentication factors are securely stored and transmitted using encryption techniques to prevent unauthorized access or tampering.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eIdentification within the European Commission's digital public service adheres to established standards and frameworks, such as the eIDAS Regulation (electronic Identification, Authentication and Trust Services), which provides a legal framework for electronic identification and trust services across the European Union. This regulation ensures that eIdentification processes are interoperable, secure, and recognized across member states, promoting cross-border digital services and enhancing trust in online transactions.&#xA;&#xA;The eIdentification system also supports the concept of federated identity, allowing users to access multiple services using a single set of credentials. This means that individuals or entities can authenticate themselves once and gain access to various digital public services without the need for separate identification processes for each service. Federated identity relies on trusted identity providers, which may include government agencies, private organizations, or trusted third-party service providers, to verify and vouch for the identities of users.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, eIdentification in the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public service is a comprehensive and standardized approach to verifying and authenticating the identity of users accessing online services. It ensures secure and trusted interactions, promotes cross-border digital services, and enhances the overall efficiency and effectiveness of public administration in the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;Example: One example of the application of eIdentification within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service of the European Commission is the use of eIdentification for accessing and authenticating users on the European Commission's online platform for submitting grant applications.&#xA;&#xA;When individuals or organizations want to apply for grants offered by the European Commission, they can access the online platform using their eIdentification credentials. This could be a digital identity issued by a trusted authority, such as a national eID card or a digital certificate.&#xA;&#xA;By using eIdentification, the European Commission ensures that only authorized individuals or organizations can access and submit grant applications. This helps to prevent unauthorized access and ensures the security and integrity of the application process.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eIdentification allows for seamless integration and interoperability with various national and regional eID systems across the European Union. This means that applicants from different member states can use their respective eIDs to access the platform, eliminating the need for multiple login credentials and simplifying the user experience.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, eIdentification enables the European Commission to securely verify the identity of applicants during the grant evaluation process. By leveraging interoperable eID systems, the Commission can efficiently authenticate the identity of applicants and validate their eligibility for grants.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of eIdentification in this digital public service of the European Commission enhances IT interoperability by enabling secure access, authentication, and verification of users from different member states, while ensuring the integrity and efficiency of the grant application process.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: OV-Functional Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EIdentificationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:EIdentificationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EIdentificationBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;Name: eIdentification Digital Public Service&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EIdentificationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EIdentificationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="eIdentification Digital Public Service"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:EIdentificationBusinessService"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="One example of the application of eIdentification within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service of the European Commission is the use of eIdentification for accessing and authenticating users on the European Commission's online platform for submitting grant applications.&#xA;&#xA;When individuals or organizations want to apply for grants offered by the European Commission, they can access the online platform using their eIdentification credentials. This could be a digital identity issued by a trusted authority, such as a national eID card or a digital certificate.&#xA;&#xA;By using eIdentification, the European Commission ensures that only authorized individuals or organizations can access and submit grant applications. This helps to prevent unauthorized access and ensures the security and integrity of the application process.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eIdentification allows for seamless integration and interoperability with various national and regional eID systems across the European Union. This means that applicants from different member states can use their respective eIDs to access the platform, eliminating the need for multiple login credentials and simplifying the user experience.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, eIdentification enables the European Commission to securely verify the identity of applicants during the grant evaluation process. By leveraging interoperable eID systems, the Commission can efficiently authenticate the identity of applicants and validate their eligibility for grants.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of eIdentification in this digital public service of the European Commission enhances IT interoperability by enabling secure access, authentication, and verification of users from different member states, while ensuring the integrity and efficiency of the grant application process."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="eIdentification, within the context of IT interoperability, refers to the process of electronically verifying and authenticating the identity of individuals or entities in a digital public service provided by the European Commission. It involves the use of digital technologies and standardized protocols to establish the identity of users accessing online services, ensuring secure and reliable interactions between different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Commission's digital public service, eIdentification plays a crucial role in enabling seamless and trusted electronic transactions, as well as facilitating the exchange of information and data across various government departments, agencies, and organizations. It aims to provide a unified and standardized approach to identity verification, eliminating the need for multiple, separate identification processes for different services.&#xA;&#xA;The eIdentification system incorporates various elements to ensure the security and integrity of digital identities. It typically involves the use of unique identifiers, such as usernames or email addresses, along with strong authentication mechanisms, such as passwords, PINs, or biometric data, to verify the identity of users. These authentication factors are securely stored and transmitted using encryption techniques to prevent unauthorized access or tampering.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, eIdentification within the European Commission's digital public service adheres to established standards and frameworks, such as the eIDAS Regulation (electronic Identification, Authentication and Trust Services), which provides a legal framework for electronic identification and trust services across the European Union. This regulation ensures that eIdentification processes are interoperable, secure, and recognized across member states, promoting cross-border digital services and enhancing trust in online transactions.&#xA;&#xA;The eIdentification system also supports the concept of federated identity, allowing users to access multiple services using a single set of credentials. This means that individuals or entities can authenticate themselves once and gain access to various digital public services without the need for separate identification processes for each service. Federated identity relies on trusted identity providers, which may include government agencies, private organizations, or trusted third-party service providers, to verify and vouch for the identities of users.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, eIdentification in the context of IT interoperability in the European Commission's digital public service is a comprehensive and standardized approach to verifying and authenticating the identity of users accessing online services. It ensures secure and trusted interactions, promotes cross-border digital services, and enhances the overall efficiency and effectiveness of public administration in the European Union."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="eIdentification, within the context of IT interoperability in a digital public service of the European Commission, refers to the process of verifying and authenticating the identity of individuals or entities accessing online services. It involves the use of digital credentials, such as electronic identity cards or digital signatures, to establish trust and ensure secure access to various online platforms and services. eIdentification plays a crucial role in enabling seamless and secure interactions between users and digital public services, facilitating the exchange of information and promoting interoperability across different systems and organizations."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Functional Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view [Motivation]"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Data Spaces"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalPublicBusinessService"/>
</archimate:BusinessService>
