<archimate:Assessment
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Spaces Business Alliance"
    id="id-95db7b9f785b4c40a57af3251183eeef"
    documentation="Definition: The Data Spaces Business Alliance is a global initiative launched by several leading technology companies, including Atos, Dell Technologies, Google Cloud, and IBM. The alliance aims to develop a set of standards, protocols, and best practices for data sharing and collaboration across industries. The goal is to create secure and trusted data spaces that enable businesses to share and leverage data in a privacy-compliant manner, fostering innovation and driving digital transformation.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team research&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Data Spaces Business Alliance is a global initiative established by a group of leading technology companies, including Atos, Dell Technologies, Google Cloud, IBM, Intel, Microsoft, and SAP. The alliance aims to create a trusted and secure data sharing environment that enables businesses to collaborate and innovate through shared data spaces. &#xA;&#xA;The Data Spaces Business Alliance is built on the principle of data sovereignty, which means that organizations maintain control over their data, even when it is shared or combined with data from other organizations. This is achieved through the use of secure and standardized technologies that ensure data privacy and security.&#xA;&#xA;The alliance's goal is to create a global standard for data spaces, which are virtual environments where organizations can share and collaborate on data. These data spaces are designed to be interoperable, meaning that they can work together seamlessly, regardless of the technology or platform used.&#xA;&#xA;The Data Spaces Business Alliance also aims to foster a vibrant ecosystem of technology providers, data providers, and data users. This ecosystem will support the development and adoption of data spaces, and will provide businesses with the tools and resources they need to leverage shared data for innovation and growth.&#xA;&#xA;The alliance believes that by enabling secure and trusted data sharing, it can help businesses unlock new opportunities, drive innovation, and create value. This could include developing new products and services, improving operational efficiency, or gaining insights for decision-making.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Data Spaces Business Alliance is a global initiative that aims to create a secure and trusted environment for data sharing, based on the principle of data sovereignty. It seeks to establish a global standard for data spaces, foster a vibrant ecosystem of stakeholders, and help businesses unlock the value of shared data.&#xA;&#xA;Example: 1. Snowflake and Databricks: Snowflake, a cloud-based data warehousing startup, and Databricks, a big data analytics service, have formed a business alliance to provide a unified, open, and dynamic data ecosystem. This alliance allows customers to run Databricks' analytics platform on Snowflake's data cloud, enabling them to easily unify, analyze, and extract valuable insights from their data.&#xA;&#xA;2. Google Cloud and SAP: Google Cloud and SAP have formed a business alliance to help customers execute business transformations, migrate critical business systems to the cloud, and augment existing business systems with Google Cloud capabilities in artificial intelligence and machine learning.&#xA;&#xA;3. Microsoft and Adobe: Microsoft and Adobe have formed a strategic partnership to redefine customer experiences. The partnership makes Adobe Marketing Cloud the preferred marketing service for Microsoft Dynamics 365 Enterprise edition.&#xA;&#xA;4. IBM and Salesforce: IBM and Salesforce have partnered to deliver joint solutions designed to leverage artificial intelligence and enable companies to make smarter decisions, faster. The partnership brings together IBM Watson and Salesforce Einstein to enable an entirely new level of intelligent customer engagement across sales, service, marketing, commerce and more.&#xA;&#xA;5. Amazon Web Services and Tableau: Tableau, a leading data visualization tool, has partnered with Amazon Web Services to provide a comprehensive cloud-based analytics solution. This partnership allows users to connect, visualize, and share data with a seamless experience from the source in AWS to the visualization in Tableau.&#xA;&#xA;6. Oracle and VMware: Oracle and VMware have formed a strategic partnership to support customers’ hybrid cloud strategies and enable them to leverage their existing software investments while enjoying new technology advancements. This partnership allows customers to run, manage, connect, and secure applications across VMware environments and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure.&#xA;&#xA;7. Cisco and NetApp: Cisco and NetApp have formed a business alliance to deliver a portfolio of integrated solutions designed to simplify and modernize IT and deliver enhanced data management capabilities. The partnership combines the innovation of Cisco UCS Integrated Infrastructure with the simplicity of NetApp data services.&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSpacesBusinessAllianceAssessment&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:DataSpacesBusinessAllianceAssessment&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSpacesBusinessAllianceAssessment&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Spaces Business Alliance Assessment&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: N/A&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSpacesBusinessAllianceAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSpacesBusinessAllianceAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:DataSpacesBusinessAllianceAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Spaces Business Alliance Assessment"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="The Data Spaces Business Alliance is a global initiative launched by several leading technology companies, including Atos, Dell Technologies, Google Cloud, and IBM. The alliance aims to develop a set of standards, protocols, and best practices for data sharing and collaboration across industries. The goal is to create secure and trusted data spaces that enable businesses to share and leverage data in a privacy-compliant manner, fostering innovation and driving digital transformation."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team research"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="1. Snowflake and Databricks: Snowflake, a cloud-based data warehousing startup, and Databricks, a big data analytics service, have formed a business alliance to provide a unified, open, and dynamic data ecosystem. This alliance allows customers to run Databricks' analytics platform on Snowflake's data cloud, enabling them to easily unify, analyze, and extract valuable insights from their data.&#xA;&#xA;2. Google Cloud and SAP: Google Cloud and SAP have formed a business alliance to help customers execute business transformations, migrate critical business systems to the cloud, and augment existing business systems with Google Cloud capabilities in artificial intelligence and machine learning.&#xA;&#xA;3. Microsoft and Adobe: Microsoft and Adobe have formed a strategic partnership to redefine customer experiences. The partnership makes Adobe Marketing Cloud the preferred marketing service for Microsoft Dynamics 365 Enterprise edition.&#xA;&#xA;4. IBM and Salesforce: IBM and Salesforce have partnered to deliver joint solutions designed to leverage artificial intelligence and enable companies to make smarter decisions, faster. The partnership brings together IBM Watson and Salesforce Einstein to enable an entirely new level of intelligent customer engagement across sales, service, marketing, commerce and more.&#xA;&#xA;5. Amazon Web Services and Tableau: Tableau, a leading data visualization tool, has partnered with Amazon Web Services to provide a comprehensive cloud-based analytics solution. This partnership allows users to connect, visualize, and share data with a seamless experience from the source in AWS to the visualization in Tableau.&#xA;&#xA;6. Oracle and VMware: Oracle and VMware have formed a strategic partnership to support customers’ hybrid cloud strategies and enable them to leverage their existing software investments while enjoying new technology advancements. This partnership allows customers to run, manage, connect, and secure applications across VMware environments and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure.&#xA;&#xA;7. Cisco and NetApp: Cisco and NetApp have formed a business alliance to deliver a portfolio of integrated solutions designed to simplify and modernize IT and deliver enhanced data management capabilities. The partnership combines the innovation of Cisco UCS Integrated Infrastructure with the simplicity of NetApp data services."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Data Spaces Business Alliance is a global initiative established by a group of leading technology companies, including Atos, Dell Technologies, Google Cloud, IBM, Intel, Microsoft, and SAP. The alliance aims to create a trusted and secure data sharing environment that enables businesses to collaborate and innovate through shared data spaces. &#xA;&#xA;The Data Spaces Business Alliance is built on the principle of data sovereignty, which means that organizations maintain control over their data, even when it is shared or combined with data from other organizations. This is achieved through the use of secure and standardized technologies that ensure data privacy and security.&#xA;&#xA;The alliance's goal is to create a global standard for data spaces, which are virtual environments where organizations can share and collaborate on data. These data spaces are designed to be interoperable, meaning that they can work together seamlessly, regardless of the technology or platform used.&#xA;&#xA;The Data Spaces Business Alliance also aims to foster a vibrant ecosystem of technology providers, data providers, and data users. This ecosystem will support the development and adoption of data spaces, and will provide businesses with the tools and resources they need to leverage shared data for innovation and growth.&#xA;&#xA;The alliance believes that by enabling secure and trusted data sharing, it can help businesses unlock new opportunities, drive innovation, and create value. This could include developing new products and services, improving operational efficiency, or gaining insights for decision-making.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Data Spaces Business Alliance is a global initiative that aims to create a secure and trusted environment for data sharing, based on the principle of data sovereignty. It seeks to establish a global standard for data spaces, foster a vibrant ecosystem of stakeholders, and help businesses unlock the value of shared data."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="N/A"/>
</archimate:Assessment>
