<archimate:Assessment
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Eclipse Dataspace Components"
    id="id-4b75e1cf8dd5485fa5e2f89a1eb555b7"
    documentation="Definition: Eclipse Dataspace Components (EDC) is an open-source project under the Eclipse Foundation that provides a platform for developing and managing IoT applications. It offers a set of modular components that can be used to collect, process, and distribute data from various devices and sensors. EDC also supports edge computing, allowing data processing to occur closer to the source, reducing latency and bandwidth usage. It is designed to be flexible and scalable, supporting a wide range of IoT use cases across different industries.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team research&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: Eclipse Dataspace Components (EDC) is an open-source project under the Eclipse Foundation that aims to provide a set of reusable components for building data-centric applications. These components are designed to help developers manage and manipulate data in a more efficient and effective way.&#xA;&#xA;EDC is built on the Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF), which is a modeling framework and code generation facility for building tools and other applications based on a structured data model. This allows EDC to provide a consistent and unified approach to data management, making it easier for developers to work with data in their applications.&#xA;&#xA;The components provided by EDC cover a wide range of data management tasks. These include components for data access, data transformation, data validation, and data visualization. Each component is designed to be reusable and customizable, allowing developers to tailor them to their specific needs.&#xA;&#xA;Data Access Components are used for reading and writing data from various sources, such as databases, files, and web services. They provide a unified API for data access, abstracting the underlying data source and allowing developers to work with data in a consistent way.&#xA;&#xA;Data Transformation Components are used for converting data from one format to another. They support a wide range of data formats and provide a flexible and powerful transformation engine.&#xA;&#xA;Data Validation Components are used for checking the integrity and consistency of data. They provide a set of validation rules that can be applied to data to ensure it meets certain criteria.&#xA;&#xA;Data Visualization Components are used for presenting data in a visual format. They support a variety of visualization techniques, including charts, graphs, and tables.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to these components, EDC also provides a set of utilities for common data management tasks, such as data filtering, sorting, and paging.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, Eclipse Dataspace Components is a comprehensive solution for data management in application development. It provides a set of powerful and flexible components that can significantly simplify the task of working with data, allowing developers to focus more on the business logic of their applications.&#xA;&#xA;Example: 1. Eclipse Dataspace Connector (EDC): EDC is a software framework that enables secure and reliable data exchange between different systems. It provides a set of APIs and services that allow developers to build applications that can connect, interact, and exchange data with other systems in a secure and reliable manner.&#xA;&#xA;2. Eclipse Dataspace Runtime: This is a runtime environment that supports the execution of applications built using the Eclipse Dataspace Connector. It provides a set of services and capabilities that enable the secure and reliable execution of these applications.&#xA;&#xA;3. Eclipse Dataspace SDK: This is a software development kit that provides a set of tools and libraries that developers can use to build applications that use the Eclipse Dataspace Connector. It includes APIs, documentation, sample code, and other resources that make it easier for developers to build these applications.&#xA;&#xA;4. Eclipse Dataspace Management Console: This is a web-based interface that allows administrators to manage and monitor the operation of the Eclipse Dataspace Connector and the applications that use it. It provides capabilities for configuring the connector, monitoring its operation, and troubleshooting any issues that may arise.&#xA;&#xA;5. Eclipse Dataspace Security Services: These are a set of services that provide security capabilities for the Eclipse Dataspace Connector and the applications that use it. They include services for authentication, authorization, encryption, and other security-related functions.&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EclipseDataspaceComponentsAssessment&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:EclipseDataspaceComponentsAssessment&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EclipseDataspaceComponentsAssessment&#xA;&#xA;Name: Eclipse Dataspace Components Assessment&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: N/A&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EclipseDataspaceComponentsAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/EclipseDataspaceComponentsAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:EclipseDataspaceComponentsAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Eclipse Dataspace Components Assessment"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Eclipse Dataspace Components (EDC) is an open-source project under the Eclipse Foundation that provides a platform for developing and managing IoT applications. It offers a set of modular components that can be used to collect, process, and distribute data from various devices and sensors. EDC also supports edge computing, allowing data processing to occur closer to the source, reducing latency and bandwidth usage. It is designed to be flexible and scalable, supporting a wide range of IoT use cases across different industries."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team research"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="1. Eclipse Dataspace Connector (EDC): EDC is a software framework that enables secure and reliable data exchange between different systems. It provides a set of APIs and services that allow developers to build applications that can connect, interact, and exchange data with other systems in a secure and reliable manner.&#xA;&#xA;2. Eclipse Dataspace Runtime: This is a runtime environment that supports the execution of applications built using the Eclipse Dataspace Connector. It provides a set of services and capabilities that enable the secure and reliable execution of these applications.&#xA;&#xA;3. Eclipse Dataspace SDK: This is a software development kit that provides a set of tools and libraries that developers can use to build applications that use the Eclipse Dataspace Connector. It includes APIs, documentation, sample code, and other resources that make it easier for developers to build these applications.&#xA;&#xA;4. Eclipse Dataspace Management Console: This is a web-based interface that allows administrators to manage and monitor the operation of the Eclipse Dataspace Connector and the applications that use it. It provides capabilities for configuring the connector, monitoring its operation, and troubleshooting any issues that may arise.&#xA;&#xA;5. Eclipse Dataspace Security Services: These are a set of services that provide security capabilities for the Eclipse Dataspace Connector and the applications that use it. They include services for authentication, authorization, encryption, and other security-related functions."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="Eclipse Dataspace Components (EDC) is an open-source project under the Eclipse Foundation that aims to provide a set of reusable components for building data-centric applications. These components are designed to help developers manage and manipulate data in a more efficient and effective way.&#xA;&#xA;EDC is built on the Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF), which is a modeling framework and code generation facility for building tools and other applications based on a structured data model. This allows EDC to provide a consistent and unified approach to data management, making it easier for developers to work with data in their applications.&#xA;&#xA;The components provided by EDC cover a wide range of data management tasks. These include components for data access, data transformation, data validation, and data visualization. Each component is designed to be reusable and customizable, allowing developers to tailor them to their specific needs.&#xA;&#xA;Data Access Components are used for reading and writing data from various sources, such as databases, files, and web services. They provide a unified API for data access, abstracting the underlying data source and allowing developers to work with data in a consistent way.&#xA;&#xA;Data Transformation Components are used for converting data from one format to another. They support a wide range of data formats and provide a flexible and powerful transformation engine.&#xA;&#xA;Data Validation Components are used for checking the integrity and consistency of data. They provide a set of validation rules that can be applied to data to ensure it meets certain criteria.&#xA;&#xA;Data Visualization Components are used for presenting data in a visual format. They support a variety of visualization techniques, including charts, graphs, and tables.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to these components, EDC also provides a set of utilities for common data management tasks, such as data filtering, sorting, and paging.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, Eclipse Dataspace Components is a comprehensive solution for data management in application development. It provides a set of powerful and flexible components that can significantly simplify the task of working with data, allowing developers to focus more on the business logic of their applications."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="N/A"/>
</archimate:Assessment>
