<archimate:Assessment
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM)"
    id="id-92b8e984a7ea49c0ab2d57ce54bfa20b"
    documentation="Definition: The International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) is a comprehensive framework designed to facilitate secure and standardized data exchange between different organizations. It provides a set of guidelines and specifications for creating a trusted data sharing environment, ensuring data sovereignty and data usage control. The IDS-RAM encompasses various components including connectors, app store, clearing house, and vocabulary, among others, which work together to enable interoperability, data security, and privacy. It is developed and maintained by the International Data Spaces Association, a European non-profit organization.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team research&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) is a comprehensive framework that outlines the principles and mechanisms for a secure and standardized data exchange between different stakeholders in a digital ecosystem. It is developed by the International Data Spaces Association (IDSA), a European initiative aiming to facilitate the sovereign, self-determined exchange and usage of industrial data.&#xA;&#xA;The IDS-RAM is designed to ensure data sovereignty for all participants, meaning that data providers maintain full control over their data at all times, deciding who can access it, for what purpose, and under what conditions. It provides a blueprint for creating a decentralized architecture where data can be exchanged in a trusted, secure, and interoperable manner.&#xA;&#xA;The model is based on several key components:&#xA;&#xA;1. IDS Connectors: These are the main components of the IDS architecture. They act as data processors and data providers, ensuring secure data exchange between participants.&#xA;&#xA;2. IDS Broker: This component helps participants find each other by providing a registry of available data sources and services.&#xA;&#xA;3. IDS Clearing House: This component records transactions in a verifiable and tamper-proof manner, ensuring transparency and traceability.&#xA;&#xA;4. IDS App Store: This is a platform where participants can offer and obtain data-driven applications and services.&#xA;&#xA;5. IDS Vocabulary: This provides a common language for all participants, ensuring interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;6. IDS Certification: This ensures that all components and participants comply with IDS standards and principles.&#xA;&#xA;The IDS-RAM also includes various layers such as the business layer, the functional layer, the process layer, the system layer, and the infrastructure layer, each of which plays a crucial role in the overall architecture.&#xA;&#xA;The IDS-RAM is not a software or a product, but a set of guidelines and standards that organizations can adopt to create a secure and trusted data exchange environment. It is technology-neutral and can be implemented using various technologies such as cloud computing, edge computing, blockchain, and others. It is designed to be flexible and adaptable to different use cases and sectors, from manufacturing and logistics to healthcare and agriculture.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) is a framework that provides guidelines for creating secure and standardized data spaces. It is designed to facilitate data exchange and ensure data sovereignty in business ecosystems. Here are some examples of how IDS-RAM can be applied:&#xA;&#xA;1. Supply Chain Management: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing information between suppliers, manufacturers, and retailers. This can help to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and enhance transparency in the supply chain.&#xA;&#xA;2. Healthcare: In the healthcare sector, IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing patient data between healthcare providers, insurance companies, and research institutions. This can help to improve patient care, streamline administrative processes, and facilitate medical research.&#xA;&#xA;3. Smart Cities: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between various stakeholders in a smart city, such as government agencies, utility companies, and transportation providers. This can help to improve urban planning, enhance public services, and promote sustainability.&#xA;&#xA;4. Agriculture: In the agricultural sector, IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between farmers, suppliers, and agricultural research institutions. This can help to improve crop yield, reduce waste, and promote sustainable farming practices.&#xA;&#xA;5. Automotive Industry: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between car manufacturers, suppliers, and service providers. This can help to improve vehicle design, enhance safety features, and streamline maintenance processes.&#xA;&#xA;6. Energy Sector: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between energy producers, distributors, and consumers. This can help to improve energy efficiency, reduce costs, and promote renewable energy sources.&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InternationalDataSpacesReferenceArchitectureModelAssessment&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:InternationalDataSpacesReferenceArchitectureModelAssessment&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InternationalDataSpacesReferenceArchitectureModelAssessment&#xA;&#xA;Name: International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) Assessment&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: N/A&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InternationalDataSpacesReferenceArchitectureModelAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/InternationalDataSpacesReferenceArchitectureModelAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:InternationalDataSpacesReferenceArchitectureModelAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) Assessment"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="The International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) is a comprehensive framework designed to facilitate secure and standardized data exchange between different organizations. It provides a set of guidelines and specifications for creating a trusted data sharing environment, ensuring data sovereignty and data usage control. The IDS-RAM encompasses various components including connectors, app store, clearing house, and vocabulary, among others, which work together to enable interoperability, data security, and privacy. It is developed and maintained by the International Data Spaces Association, a European non-profit organization."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team research"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) is a framework that provides guidelines for creating secure and standardized data spaces. It is designed to facilitate data exchange and ensure data sovereignty in business ecosystems. Here are some examples of how IDS-RAM can be applied:&#xA;&#xA;1. Supply Chain Management: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing information between suppliers, manufacturers, and retailers. This can help to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and enhance transparency in the supply chain.&#xA;&#xA;2. Healthcare: In the healthcare sector, IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing patient data between healthcare providers, insurance companies, and research institutions. This can help to improve patient care, streamline administrative processes, and facilitate medical research.&#xA;&#xA;3. Smart Cities: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between various stakeholders in a smart city, such as government agencies, utility companies, and transportation providers. This can help to improve urban planning, enhance public services, and promote sustainability.&#xA;&#xA;4. Agriculture: In the agricultural sector, IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between farmers, suppliers, and agricultural research institutions. This can help to improve crop yield, reduce waste, and promote sustainable farming practices.&#xA;&#xA;5. Automotive Industry: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between car manufacturers, suppliers, and service providers. This can help to improve vehicle design, enhance safety features, and streamline maintenance processes.&#xA;&#xA;6. Energy Sector: IDS-RAM can be used to create a secure data space for sharing data between energy producers, distributors, and consumers. This can help to improve energy efficiency, reduce costs, and promote renewable energy sources."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The International Data Spaces Reference Architecture Model (IDS-RAM) is a comprehensive framework that outlines the principles and mechanisms for a secure and standardized data exchange between different stakeholders in a digital ecosystem. It is developed by the International Data Spaces Association (IDSA), a European initiative aiming to facilitate the sovereign, self-determined exchange and usage of industrial data.&#xA;&#xA;The IDS-RAM is designed to ensure data sovereignty for all participants, meaning that data providers maintain full control over their data at all times, deciding who can access it, for what purpose, and under what conditions. It provides a blueprint for creating a decentralized architecture where data can be exchanged in a trusted, secure, and interoperable manner.&#xA;&#xA;The model is based on several key components:&#xA;&#xA;1. IDS Connectors: These are the main components of the IDS architecture. They act as data processors and data providers, ensuring secure data exchange between participants.&#xA;&#xA;2. IDS Broker: This component helps participants find each other by providing a registry of available data sources and services.&#xA;&#xA;3. IDS Clearing House: This component records transactions in a verifiable and tamper-proof manner, ensuring transparency and traceability.&#xA;&#xA;4. IDS App Store: This is a platform where participants can offer and obtain data-driven applications and services.&#xA;&#xA;5. IDS Vocabulary: This provides a common language for all participants, ensuring interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;6. IDS Certification: This ensures that all components and participants comply with IDS standards and principles.&#xA;&#xA;The IDS-RAM also includes various layers such as the business layer, the functional layer, the process layer, the system layer, and the infrastructure layer, each of which plays a crucial role in the overall architecture.&#xA;&#xA;The IDS-RAM is not a software or a product, but a set of guidelines and standards that organizations can adopt to create a secure and trusted data exchange environment. It is technology-neutral and can be implemented using various technologies such as cloud computing, edge computing, blockchain, and others. It is designed to be flexible and adaptable to different use cases and sectors, from manufacturing and logistics to healthcare and agriculture."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="N/A"/>
</archimate:Assessment>
