<archimate:Assessment
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base"
    id="id-69f1d76374974ce8b155b1ad6792b2db"
    documentation="Definition: The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base is a digital platform developed by the Joint Research Centre (JRC) of the European Commission. It serves as a comprehensive resource for information related to data spaces, which are virtual environments where data is exchanged and shared. The Knowledge Base includes a wide range of materials such as reports, case studies, technical guides, and policy documents. It aims to support the development and implementation of data spaces by providing relevant and up-to-date information to stakeholders, including policymakers, researchers, and data professionals.&#xA;&#xA;Source: EIRA Team research&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base is a comprehensive online resource developed by the Joint Research Centre (JRC) of the European Commission. It is designed to provide a wide range of information and resources related to data spaces, which are virtual environments where organizations can share, exchange, and work with data.&#xA;&#xA;The Knowledge Base is a part of the JRC's broader initiative to support the development and implementation of data spaces in Europe, in line with the European strategy for data. It aims to facilitate the understanding, design, and operation of data spaces by providing a variety of resources, including technical guides, policy documents, case studies, and research papers.&#xA;&#xA;The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base covers a wide range of topics related to data spaces, including data governance, data interoperability, data infrastructure, and data sharing. It also provides information on various aspects of data spaces, such as their architecture, legal and ethical considerations, and potential applications in different sectors.&#xA;&#xA;The Knowledge Base is intended for a wide range of users, including policymakers, data professionals, researchers, and businesses. It aims to support these users in making informed decisions about the design and implementation of data spaces, and to promote the sharing and reuse of data in a secure and trustworthy manner.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to providing information and resources, the JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base also serves as a platform for dialogue and collaboration. It encourages users to contribute their own knowledge and experiences, and to engage in discussions and collaborations with other users. This collaborative approach is intended to foster a vibrant and dynamic community of practice around data spaces, and to support the ongoing development and evolution of data spaces in Europe.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base is a comprehensive resource that provides access to various datasets and information related to different fields of study. Here are some examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Agriculture and Rural Development: This data space includes information about crop yield, livestock production, agricultural practices, and rural development policies across different regions.&#xA;&#xA;2. Climate Change: This data space provides datasets related to climate change indicators, greenhouse gas emissions, climate models, and impacts of climate change on various sectors.&#xA;&#xA;3. Energy: This data space includes data on energy production, consumption, energy efficiency, renewable energy sources, and energy policies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Health and Food Safety: This data space provides information on food safety standards, health indicators, disease outbreaks, and health policies.&#xA;&#xA;5. Migration and Demography: This data space includes data on migration flows, population demographics, social integration, and policies related to migration and demography.&#xA;&#xA;6. Transport and Mobility: This data space provides datasets on transport networks, mobility patterns, transport emissions, and transport policies.&#xA;&#xA;7. Digital Economy: This data space includes information on digital technologies, internet usage, e-commerce, digital skills, and digital policies.&#xA;&#xA;8. Environment and Sustainability: This data space provides data on environmental indicators, biodiversity, waste management, water resources, and sustainability policies.&#xA;&#xA;9. Education and Culture: This data space includes data on education systems, cultural heritage, language diversity, and policies related to education and culture.&#xA;&#xA;10. Security and Justice: This data space provides information on crime rates, justice systems, security threats, and policies related to security and justice.&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/JRCDataSpacesKnowledgeBaseAssessment&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: egovera:JRCDataSpacesKnowledgeBaseAssessment&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2023-11-20&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/JRCDataSpacesKnowledgeBaseAssessment&#xA;&#xA;Name: JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base Assessment&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: N/A&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/JRCDataSpacesKnowledgeBaseAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2023-11-20"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/JRCDataSpacesKnowledgeBaseAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="egovera:JRCDataSpacesKnowledgeBaseAssessment"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base Assessment"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base is a digital platform developed by the Joint Research Centre (JRC) of the European Commission. It serves as a comprehensive resource for information related to data spaces, which are virtual environments where data is exchanged and shared. The Knowledge Base includes a wide range of materials such as reports, case studies, technical guides, and policy documents. It aims to support the development and implementation of data spaces by providing relevant and up-to-date information to stakeholders, including policymakers, researchers, and data professionals."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team research"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base is a comprehensive resource that provides access to various datasets and information related to different fields of study. Here are some examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Agriculture and Rural Development: This data space includes information about crop yield, livestock production, agricultural practices, and rural development policies across different regions.&#xA;&#xA;2. Climate Change: This data space provides datasets related to climate change indicators, greenhouse gas emissions, climate models, and impacts of climate change on various sectors.&#xA;&#xA;3. Energy: This data space includes data on energy production, consumption, energy efficiency, renewable energy sources, and energy policies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Health and Food Safety: This data space provides information on food safety standards, health indicators, disease outbreaks, and health policies.&#xA;&#xA;5. Migration and Demography: This data space includes data on migration flows, population demographics, social integration, and policies related to migration and demography.&#xA;&#xA;6. Transport and Mobility: This data space provides datasets on transport networks, mobility patterns, transport emissions, and transport policies.&#xA;&#xA;7. Digital Economy: This data space includes information on digital technologies, internet usage, e-commerce, digital skills, and digital policies.&#xA;&#xA;8. Environment and Sustainability: This data space provides data on environmental indicators, biodiversity, waste management, water resources, and sustainability policies.&#xA;&#xA;9. Education and Culture: This data space includes data on education systems, cultural heritage, language diversity, and policies related to education and culture.&#xA;&#xA;10. Security and Justice: This data space provides information on crime rates, justice systems, security threats, and policies related to security and justice."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base is a comprehensive online resource developed by the Joint Research Centre (JRC) of the European Commission. It is designed to provide a wide range of information and resources related to data spaces, which are virtual environments where organizations can share, exchange, and work with data.&#xA;&#xA;The Knowledge Base is a part of the JRC's broader initiative to support the development and implementation of data spaces in Europe, in line with the European strategy for data. It aims to facilitate the understanding, design, and operation of data spaces by providing a variety of resources, including technical guides, policy documents, case studies, and research papers.&#xA;&#xA;The JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base covers a wide range of topics related to data spaces, including data governance, data interoperability, data infrastructure, and data sharing. It also provides information on various aspects of data spaces, such as their architecture, legal and ethical considerations, and potential applications in different sectors.&#xA;&#xA;The Knowledge Base is intended for a wide range of users, including policymakers, data professionals, researchers, and businesses. It aims to support these users in making informed decisions about the design and implementation of data spaces, and to promote the sharing and reuse of data in a secure and trustworthy manner.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to providing information and resources, the JRC Data Spaces Knowledge Base also serves as a platform for dialogue and collaboration. It encourages users to contribute their own knowledge and experiences, and to engage in discussions and collaborations with other users. This collaborative approach is intended to foster a vibrant and dynamic community of practice around data spaces, and to support the ongoing development and evolution of data spaces in Europe."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="N/A"/>
</archimate:Assessment>
