<archimate:Principle
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Neo-Weberian-State approach (NWS)"
    id="id-419bf81f5150483ea49500058c47add9"
    documentation="Definition: Ensure the evolution of society and eGovernment by implementing means for the achievement of the purpose, specifically for inclusion and equitative public service, resilience towards crises and efficient and effective innovation.  NWS is a hierarchy-driven system within a hierarchy-market-network space. This NWS (based and driven by hierarchy) then moved to one of the normative reform models. The Neo-Weberian-State approach is focused an aimed to ensure three main core principles, that are specifically relevant to the development of eGovernment and societies:  inclusive and equitable service delivery, resilient crises governance, and effective innovation for government and society. The application of the principle or the work towards the approach is a key enabler for digital and healthy societies, where users and the overall society is taken into account, and put on the focus on the development of Digital Public Services.  Public administrations need to promote and implement policies, and legal instruments that guide the creation of inclusive and equitable service delivery, resilient crises governance, and effective innovation for government and society.&#xA;&#xA;Source: \&quot;The neo-Weberian state: From ideal type model to reality?\&quot; by UCL Institute for Innovation and Public Purpose&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.ucl.ac.uk/bartlett/public-purpose/sites/bartlett_public_purpose/files/bouckaert_g._2022_the_neo-weberian_state_from_ideal_type_model_to_reality_0.pdf&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: NWS is a hierarchy-driven system within a hierarchy-market-network space. This NWS (based and driven by hierarchy) then moved to one of the normative reform models. &#xA;&#xA;The Neo-Weberian-State approach is focused an aimed to ensure three main core principles, that are specifically relevant to the development of eGovernment and societies:  inclusive and equitable service delivery, resilient crises governance, and effective innovation for government and society. &#xA;&#xA;The application of the principle or the work towards the approach is a key enabler for digital and healthy societies, where users and the overall society is taken into account, and put on the focus on the development of Digital Public Services. &#xA;The UCL Institute for Innovation and Public Purpose is focused on the development and research of how digital platforms and services can improve societies. &#xA;&#xA;LOST view: TVA-Governance Architecture Principles&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/2sa/elap/neo-weberian-state-approach&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: elap:neo-weberian-state-approach&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-17&#xA;&#xA;Name: Neo-Weberian-State approach (NWS)&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: N/A&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: eira:EuropeanLibraryofArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="elap:neo-weberian-state-approach"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Neo-Weberian-State approach (NWS)"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/2sa/elap/neo-weberian-state-approach"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-17"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="NWS is a hierarchy-driven system within a hierarchy-market-network space. This NWS (based and driven by hierarchy) then moved to one of the normative reform models. &#xA;&#xA;The Neo-Weberian-State approach is focused an aimed to ensure three main core principles, that are specifically relevant to the development of eGovernment and societies:  inclusive and equitable service delivery, resilient crises governance, and effective innovation for government and society. &#xA;&#xA;The application of the principle or the work towards the approach is a key enabler for digital and healthy societies, where users and the overall society is taken into account, and put on the focus on the development of Digital Public Services. &#xA;The UCL Institute for Innovation and Public Purpose is focused on the development and research of how digital platforms and services can improve societies. "/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="\&quot;The neo-Weberian state: From ideal type model to reality?\&quot; by UCL Institute for Innovation and Public Purpose"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/bartlett/public-purpose/sites/bartlett_public_purpose/files/bouckaert_g._2022_the_neo-weberian_state_from_ideal_type_model_to_reality_0.pdf"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVA-Governance Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="OV-Governance Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="TVI-Governance Architecture Principles"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Architecture Principles view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="N/A"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Ensure the evolution of society and eGovernment by implementing means for the achievement of the purpose, specifically for inclusion and equitative public service, resilience towards crises and efficient and effective innovation.  NWS is a hierarchy-driven system within a hierarchy-market-network space. This NWS (based and driven by hierarchy) then moved to one of the normative reform models. The Neo-Weberian-State approach is focused an aimed to ensure three main core principles, that are specifically relevant to the development of eGovernment and societies:  inclusive and equitable service delivery, resilient crises governance, and effective innovation for government and society. The application of the principle or the work towards the approach is a key enabler for digital and healthy societies, where users and the overall society is taken into account, and put on the focus on the development of Digital Public Services.  Public administrations need to promote and implement policies, and legal instruments that guide the creation of inclusive and equitable service delivery, resilient crises governance, and effective innovation for government and society."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="eira:EuropeanLibraryofArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple"/>
</archimate:Principle>
