<archimate:Principle
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="European Library of Architecture Principles"
    id="id-7db70d70c2824650997a08f280fbb117"
    documentation="Definition: European Library of Architecture Principles (ELAP) ABB is a set of principles that aim to support interoperability and standardization in eGoverment across the EU.&#xA;&#xA;Source: ELAP&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://joinup.ec.europa.eu/collection/common-assessment-method-standards-and-specifications-camss/solution/elap&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The European Library of Architecture Principles (ELAP) ABB is a set of principles intended to direct government organizations in initiating changes and implementing IT projects. Particularly when designing new or modified services, it is necessary to make visible how the principles are implemented and which considerations are made in this regard. The apply-or-explain principle applies here, whereby deviations are permitted provided that they are substantiated and recorded with good arguments so that they can be revisited at a later stage. This prevents important matters from being overlooked.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The following implementation is an example of how this specific Architecture Building Block (ABB) can be instantiated as a Solution Building Block (SBB): ELAP transparency principle in the EIF context refers to: Enabling visibility inside the administrative environment of a public administration. This is about allowing other public administrations, citizens, and businesses to view and understand administrative rules, processes, 11 data, services, and decision-making. Ensuring availability of interfaces with internal information systems. Public administrations operate a large number of what are often heterogeneous and disparate information systems in support of their internal processes. Interoperability depends on ensuring the availability of interfaces to these systems and the data they handle. In turn, interoperability facilitates reuse of systems and data, and enables these to be integrated into larger systems. Securing the right to the protection of personal data, by respecting the applicable legal framework for the large volumes of personal data of citizens, held and managed by Public administrations. https://joinup.ec.europa.eu/collection/common-assessment-method-standards-and-specifications-camss/solution/elap/distribution/elap-catalogue-v100xlsx&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Dimension: Governance IoP&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: EIRA Ontology view&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Saliency: The European Library of Architecture Principles (ELAP) ABB is salient for governance interoperability due to it establishes the principles and framework to ensure interoperability at the European level. Also, the European Library of Architecture Principles ABB is salient for organizational interoperability due to it establishes requirements and business processes to enable interoperability between public services.&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/EuropeanLibraryOfArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:EuropeanLibraryOfArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/EuropeanLibraryOfArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: N/A&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/EuropeanLibraryOfArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:EuropeanLibraryOfArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:synonym"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="European Library of Architecture Principles (ELAP) ABB is a set of principles that aim to support interoperability and standardization in eGoverment across the EU."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="ELAP"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://joinup.ec.europa.eu/collection/common-assessment-method-standards-and-specifications-camss/solution/elap"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The following implementation is an example of how this specific Architecture Building Block (ABB) can be instantiated as a Solution Building Block (SBB): ELAP transparency principle in the EIF context refers to: Enabling visibility inside the administrative environment of a public administration. This is about allowing other public administrations, citizens, and businesses to view and understand administrative rules, processes, 11 data, services, and decision-making. Ensuring availability of interfaces with internal information systems. Public administrations operate a large number of what are often heterogeneous and disparate information systems in support of their internal processes. Interoperability depends on ensuring the availability of interfaces to these systems and the data they handle. In turn, interoperability facilitates reuse of systems and data, and enables these to be integrated into larger systems. Securing the right to the protection of personal data, by respecting the applicable legal framework for the large volumes of personal data of citizens, held and managed by Public administrations. https://joinup.ec.europa.eu/collection/common-assessment-method-standards-and-specifications-camss/solution/elap/distribution/elap-catalogue-v100xlsx"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:iopSaliency"
      value="The European Library of Architecture Principles (ELAP) ABB is salient for governance interoperability due to it establishes the principles and framework to ensure interoperability at the European level. Also, the European Library of Architecture Principles ABB is salient for organizational interoperability due to it establishes requirements and business processes to enable interoperability between public services."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The European Library of Architecture Principles (ELAP) ABB is a set of principles intended to direct government organizations in initiating changes and implementing IT projects. Particularly when designing new or modified services, it is necessary to make visible how the principles are implemented and which considerations are made in this regard. The apply-or-explain principle applies here, whereby deviations are permitted provided that they are substantiated and recorded with good arguments so that they can be revisited at a later stage. This prevents important matters from being overlooked."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:iopDimension"
      value="Governance IoP"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:iopDimension"
      value="Behavioral IoP"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:iopDimension"
      value="Structural IoP"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="EIRA Ontology view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Semantic view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Technical view - application"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Technical view - infrastructure"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="EIRA Ontology viewpoint"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/EuropeanLibraryOfArchitecturePrinciplesPrinciple"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="N/A"/>
</archimate:Principle>
