<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Sharing"
    id="id-af63efa21f0f419f9b2d6474ff217e9a"
    documentation="Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to securely and efficiently share data with internal and external stakeholders. This capability involves the establishment of data governance frameworks, data privacy and security measures, and the implementation of technologies and platforms that enable seamless data exchange. By effectively sharing data, organizations can enhance collaboration, improve decision-making processes, and drive innovation across various business functions.&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to effectively and securely share data across various systems, applications, and stakeholders. It encompasses the processes, technologies, and governance mechanisms required to enable seamless data exchange and collaboration.&#xA;&#xA;This capability involves the establishment of standardized data formats, protocols, and interfaces to facilitate the smooth flow of information between different entities. It ensures that data is shared in a consistent and reliable manner, enabling real-time access, analysis, and decision-making.&#xA;&#xA;Key components of the Data Sharing Digital Business Capability include:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Integration: This involves integrating data from disparate sources, such as databases, applications, and external systems, into a unified and coherent format. It includes data cleansing, transformation, and mapping to ensure data consistency and accuracy.&#xA;&#xA;2. Data Exchange: This capability enables the secure and efficient transfer of data between internal and external stakeholders. It involves the use of standardized protocols, such as APIs (Application Programming Interfaces), web services, or messaging systems, to facilitate data exchange in a secure and controlled manner.&#xA;&#xA;3. Data Governance: This component focuses on establishing policies, procedures, and controls to ensure data quality, privacy, and compliance. It includes defining data ownership, access controls, data classification, and data lifecycle management to ensure that data is shared in a controlled and secure manner.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data Security: This capability ensures that data is protected from unauthorized access, manipulation, or disclosure. It involves implementing encryption, access controls, authentication mechanisms, and monitoring systems to safeguard sensitive data during sharing and transmission.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Analytics: This capability leverages shared data to derive insights, make informed decisions, and drive business value. It includes the use of advanced analytics techniques, such as data mining, machine learning, and predictive modeling, to extract meaningful patterns and trends from shared data.&#xA;&#xA;6. Collaboration: This component focuses on enabling effective collaboration and knowledge sharing among stakeholders. It involves providing tools and platforms for real-time collaboration, document sharing, and communication to foster collaboration and innovation.&#xA;&#xA;The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability is crucial for organizations to leverage the power of data and enable digital transformation. It allows organizations to break down data silos, improve operational efficiency, enhance customer experiences, and drive innovation. By enabling seamless data sharing, organizations can unlock the full potential of their data assets and gain a competitive advantage in the digital era.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to the ability to securely and efficiently share data across different government agencies or departments. This capability enables seamless collaboration, improved decision-making, and enhanced service delivery. Here are some real examples of this capability in action:&#xA;&#xA;1. Integrated Health Information Systems: In many countries, public health agencies have implemented integrated health information systems that allow healthcare providers, hospitals, and clinics to securely share patient data. This capability enables healthcare professionals to access comprehensive medical records, reducing duplication of tests, improving diagnoses, and enhancing patient care.&#xA;&#xA;2. Criminal Justice Information Sharing: Law enforcement agencies often require real-time access to criminal records, arrest warrants, and other relevant information. Data sharing capabilities enable police departments, courts, and correctional facilities to exchange data securely, facilitating faster and more accurate investigations, improved public safety, and efficient case management.&#xA;&#xA;3. Social Services Coordination: Public sector organizations responsible for delivering social services, such as welfare, housing, and employment assistance, often need to share client information to ensure coordinated support. Data sharing capabilities enable these agencies to exchange relevant data securely, ensuring that individuals receive the appropriate services and reducing administrative burdens.&#xA;&#xA;4. Emergency Management and Response: During emergencies or natural disasters, multiple government agencies and organizations need to collaborate and share critical information in real-time. Data sharing capabilities enable emergency management agencies, first responders, and other stakeholders to exchange data on incident status, resource availability, and public safety alerts, facilitating effective response and coordination.&#xA;&#xA;5. Open Data Initiatives: Some public sector organizations have embraced open data initiatives, making certain non-sensitive government data available to the public. Data sharing capabilities enable the publication and dissemination of datasets, fostering transparency, innovation, and public engagement. Examples include publishing crime statistics, transportation data, or environmental information for citizens, researchers, and businesses to utilize.&#xA;&#xA;These examples illustrate how the Data Sharing Digital Business Capability in the public sector can enhance collaboration, decision-making, and service delivery across various domains.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSharingCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DataSharingCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSharingCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Sharing Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSharingCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSharingCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Sharing Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to securely and efficiently share data with internal and external stakeholders. This capability involves the establishment of data governance frameworks, data privacy and security measures, and the implementation of technologies and platforms that enable seamless data exchange. By effectively sharing data, organizations can enhance collaboration, improve decision-making processes, and drive innovation across various business functions."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to the ability to securely and efficiently share data across different government agencies or departments. This capability enables seamless collaboration, improved decision-making, and enhanced service delivery. Here are some real examples of this capability in action:&#xA;&#xA;1. Integrated Health Information Systems: In many countries, public health agencies have implemented integrated health information systems that allow healthcare providers, hospitals, and clinics to securely share patient data. This capability enables healthcare professionals to access comprehensive medical records, reducing duplication of tests, improving diagnoses, and enhancing patient care.&#xA;&#xA;2. Criminal Justice Information Sharing: Law enforcement agencies often require real-time access to criminal records, arrest warrants, and other relevant information. Data sharing capabilities enable police departments, courts, and correctional facilities to exchange data securely, facilitating faster and more accurate investigations, improved public safety, and efficient case management.&#xA;&#xA;3. Social Services Coordination: Public sector organizations responsible for delivering social services, such as welfare, housing, and employment assistance, often need to share client information to ensure coordinated support. Data sharing capabilities enable these agencies to exchange relevant data securely, ensuring that individuals receive the appropriate services and reducing administrative burdens.&#xA;&#xA;4. Emergency Management and Response: During emergencies or natural disasters, multiple government agencies and organizations need to collaborate and share critical information in real-time. Data sharing capabilities enable emergency management agencies, first responders, and other stakeholders to exchange data on incident status, resource availability, and public safety alerts, facilitating effective response and coordination.&#xA;&#xA;5. Open Data Initiatives: Some public sector organizations have embraced open data initiatives, making certain non-sensitive government data available to the public. Data sharing capabilities enable the publication and dissemination of datasets, fostering transparency, innovation, and public engagement. Examples include publishing crime statistics, transportation data, or environmental information for citizens, researchers, and businesses to utilize.&#xA;&#xA;These examples illustrate how the Data Sharing Digital Business Capability in the public sector can enhance collaboration, decision-making, and service delivery across various domains."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to effectively and securely share data across various systems, applications, and stakeholders. It encompasses the processes, technologies, and governance mechanisms required to enable seamless data exchange and collaboration.&#xA;&#xA;This capability involves the establishment of standardized data formats, protocols, and interfaces to facilitate the smooth flow of information between different entities. It ensures that data is shared in a consistent and reliable manner, enabling real-time access, analysis, and decision-making.&#xA;&#xA;Key components of the Data Sharing Digital Business Capability include:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Integration: This involves integrating data from disparate sources, such as databases, applications, and external systems, into a unified and coherent format. It includes data cleansing, transformation, and mapping to ensure data consistency and accuracy.&#xA;&#xA;2. Data Exchange: This capability enables the secure and efficient transfer of data between internal and external stakeholders. It involves the use of standardized protocols, such as APIs (Application Programming Interfaces), web services, or messaging systems, to facilitate data exchange in a secure and controlled manner.&#xA;&#xA;3. Data Governance: This component focuses on establishing policies, procedures, and controls to ensure data quality, privacy, and compliance. It includes defining data ownership, access controls, data classification, and data lifecycle management to ensure that data is shared in a controlled and secure manner.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data Security: This capability ensures that data is protected from unauthorized access, manipulation, or disclosure. It involves implementing encryption, access controls, authentication mechanisms, and monitoring systems to safeguard sensitive data during sharing and transmission.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Analytics: This capability leverages shared data to derive insights, make informed decisions, and drive business value. It includes the use of advanced analytics techniques, such as data mining, machine learning, and predictive modeling, to extract meaningful patterns and trends from shared data.&#xA;&#xA;6. Collaboration: This component focuses on enabling effective collaboration and knowledge sharing among stakeholders. It involves providing tools and platforms for real-time collaboration, document sharing, and communication to foster collaboration and innovation.&#xA;&#xA;The Data Sharing Digital Business Capability is crucial for organizations to leverage the power of data and enable digital transformation. It allows organizations to break down data silos, improve operational efficiency, enhance customer experiences, and drive innovation. By enabling seamless data sharing, organizations can unlock the full potential of their data assets and gain a competitive advantage in the digital era."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DataSharingCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
