<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Digital Procurement"
    id="id-592ad0865992490796dbc5c58b589d3e"
    documentation="Definition: Digital Procurement enables the electronic end-to-end management of the purchasing process and related tasks associated to the acquisition of third-party goods and/or services through digital means and information and communication technologies.&#xA;&#xA;Source: European Commission&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://ec.europa.eu/growth/single-market/public-procurement/digital-procurement_it&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability (DP-DBC) is a comprehensive framework and set of practices aimed at enhancing the efficiency, transparency, and interoperability of procurement processes within the European Union (EU). It focuses on leveraging digital technologies to streamline procurement activities and promote collaboration between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of the DP-DBC is to establish a standardized and harmonized digital procurement ecosystem across the EU, enabling seamless communication and data exchange between member states and private entities. It encompasses various aspects of procurement, including sourcing, tendering, contracting, invoicing, and supplier management.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key elements of the DP-DBC is the development and implementation of interoperable IT systems and platforms. These systems facilitate the exchange of procurement-related information and data between different stakeholders, such as government agencies, public authorities, and private companies. The interoperability ensures that information can be shared and understood consistently, regardless of the specific IT systems used by each entity.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve this interoperability, the DP-DBC promotes the adoption of common data standards, formats, and protocols. These standards enable seamless integration and data exchange between disparate IT systems, eliminating the need for manual data entry and reducing errors and inefficiencies. They also ensure that procurement-related data can be easily accessed, analyzed, and shared across member states and private companies, fostering transparency and collaboration.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the DP-DBC emphasizes the use of digital signatures and electronic identification mechanisms to authenticate and secure procurement transactions. These technologies enable the creation of legally binding contracts and ensure the integrity and confidentiality of sensitive procurement information. By leveraging digital signatures and electronic identification, member states and private companies can streamline the procurement process, reduce paperwork, and enhance security.&#xA;&#xA;The DP-DBC also encompasses the establishment of centralized procurement portals and platforms at both the national and EU levels. These portals serve as a single point of access for procurement-related information, allowing suppliers to find and participate in tendering processes across member states. The portals provide standardized templates, guidelines, and documentation, simplifying the procurement process for both buyers and suppliers.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the DP-DBC promotes the use of advanced analytics and artificial intelligence (AI) technologies to improve procurement decision-making and performance. By analyzing large volumes of procurement data, AI algorithms can identify patterns, trends, and potential risks, enabling more informed and strategic procurement decisions. These technologies also support the automation of routine procurement tasks, freeing up resources and enabling procurement professionals to focus on value-added activities.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability aims to enhance the European IT interoperability among member states and private companies by leveraging digital technologies, establishing common data standards, promoting secure authentication mechanisms, creating centralized procurement portals, and utilizing advanced analytics and AI. By adopting this capability, the EU seeks to streamline procurement processes, increase transparency, and foster collaboration in the procurement ecosystem.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The application of Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can have several examples. Here are a few:&#xA;&#xA;1. E-procurement platforms: Digital procurement capabilities can be utilized to develop and implement e-procurement platforms at the European level. These platforms can enable member states and private companies to streamline their procurement processes, share information, and collaborate more efficiently.&#xA;&#xA;2. Standardization of procurement processes: Digital procurement capabilities can be used to establish standardized procurement processes across member states and private companies. This can ensure consistency, transparency, and interoperability in procurement activities, making it easier for organizations to work together and exchange information.&#xA;&#xA;3. Electronic document exchange: Digital procurement capabilities can facilitate the electronic exchange of procurement-related documents, such as requests for proposals (RFPs), bids, contracts, and invoices. This can eliminate the need for paper-based processes, reduce administrative burden, and enable seamless communication between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data analytics and reporting: Digital procurement capabilities can enable the collection, analysis, and reporting of procurement data at the European level. This can provide valuable insights into procurement trends, performance, and compliance, helping member states and private companies make informed decisions and improve their procurement practices.&#xA;&#xA;5. Supplier management and collaboration: Digital procurement capabilities can support the management and collaboration with suppliers across member states and private companies. This can include features like supplier onboarding, performance evaluation, and contract management, ensuring a more efficient and effective supplier relationship management process.&#xA;&#xA;6. Integration with existing systems: Digital procurement capabilities can be integrated with existing IT systems used by member states and private companies. This integration can enable seamless data exchange, interoperability, and process automation, reducing manual effort and enhancing overall efficiency.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability can significantly improve the European IT interoperability among member states and private companies, leading to enhanced collaboration, efficiency, and transparency in procurement processes.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalProcurementCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DigitalProcurementCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalProcurementCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalProcurementCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalProcurementCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Digital Procurement enables the electronic end-to-end management of the purchasing process and related tasks associated to the acquisition of third-party goods and/or services through digital means and information and communication technologies."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The application of Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can have several examples. Here are a few:&#xA;&#xA;1. E-procurement platforms: Digital procurement capabilities can be utilized to develop and implement e-procurement platforms at the European level. These platforms can enable member states and private companies to streamline their procurement processes, share information, and collaborate more efficiently.&#xA;&#xA;2. Standardization of procurement processes: Digital procurement capabilities can be used to establish standardized procurement processes across member states and private companies. This can ensure consistency, transparency, and interoperability in procurement activities, making it easier for organizations to work together and exchange information.&#xA;&#xA;3. Electronic document exchange: Digital procurement capabilities can facilitate the electronic exchange of procurement-related documents, such as requests for proposals (RFPs), bids, contracts, and invoices. This can eliminate the need for paper-based processes, reduce administrative burden, and enable seamless communication between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data analytics and reporting: Digital procurement capabilities can enable the collection, analysis, and reporting of procurement data at the European level. This can provide valuable insights into procurement trends, performance, and compliance, helping member states and private companies make informed decisions and improve their procurement practices.&#xA;&#xA;5. Supplier management and collaboration: Digital procurement capabilities can support the management and collaboration with suppliers across member states and private companies. This can include features like supplier onboarding, performance evaluation, and contract management, ensuring a more efficient and effective supplier relationship management process.&#xA;&#xA;6. Integration with existing systems: Digital procurement capabilities can be integrated with existing IT systems used by member states and private companies. This integration can enable seamless data exchange, interoperability, and process automation, reducing manual effort and enhancing overall efficiency.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability can significantly improve the European IT interoperability among member states and private companies, leading to enhanced collaboration, efficiency, and transparency in procurement processes."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability (DP-DBC) is a comprehensive framework and set of practices aimed at enhancing the efficiency, transparency, and interoperability of procurement processes within the European Union (EU). It focuses on leveraging digital technologies to streamline procurement activities and promote collaboration between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of the DP-DBC is to establish a standardized and harmonized digital procurement ecosystem across the EU, enabling seamless communication and data exchange between member states and private entities. It encompasses various aspects of procurement, including sourcing, tendering, contracting, invoicing, and supplier management.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key elements of the DP-DBC is the development and implementation of interoperable IT systems and platforms. These systems facilitate the exchange of procurement-related information and data between different stakeholders, such as government agencies, public authorities, and private companies. The interoperability ensures that information can be shared and understood consistently, regardless of the specific IT systems used by each entity.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve this interoperability, the DP-DBC promotes the adoption of common data standards, formats, and protocols. These standards enable seamless integration and data exchange between disparate IT systems, eliminating the need for manual data entry and reducing errors and inefficiencies. They also ensure that procurement-related data can be easily accessed, analyzed, and shared across member states and private companies, fostering transparency and collaboration.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the DP-DBC emphasizes the use of digital signatures and electronic identification mechanisms to authenticate and secure procurement transactions. These technologies enable the creation of legally binding contracts and ensure the integrity and confidentiality of sensitive procurement information. By leveraging digital signatures and electronic identification, member states and private companies can streamline the procurement process, reduce paperwork, and enhance security.&#xA;&#xA;The DP-DBC also encompasses the establishment of centralized procurement portals and platforms at both the national and EU levels. These portals serve as a single point of access for procurement-related information, allowing suppliers to find and participate in tendering processes across member states. The portals provide standardized templates, guidelines, and documentation, simplifying the procurement process for both buyers and suppliers.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the DP-DBC promotes the use of advanced analytics and artificial intelligence (AI) technologies to improve procurement decision-making and performance. By analyzing large volumes of procurement data, AI algorithms can identify patterns, trends, and potential risks, enabling more informed and strategic procurement decisions. These technologies also support the automation of routine procurement tasks, freeing up resources and enabling procurement professionals to focus on value-added activities.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Digital Procurement Digital Business Capability aims to enhance the European IT interoperability among member states and private companies by leveraging digital technologies, establishing common data standards, promoting secure authentication mechanisms, creating centralized procurement portals, and utilizing advanced analytics and AI. By adopting this capability, the EU seeks to streamline procurement processes, increase transparency, and foster collaboration in the procurement ecosystem."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="European Commission"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://ec.europa.eu/growth/single-market/public-procurement/digital-procurement_it"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DigitalProcurementCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
