<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Digital Exchange"
    id="id-f992894f117e4547b643392e12cde072"
    documentation="Definition: Digital Exchange enables the transmission of digitally encoded information to profiled targets of stakeholders. &#xA;&#xA;Source: Fred Turner&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://books.google.it/books?id=2SNFpgX_WigC&amp;pg=PA131&amp;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Digital Exchange Digital Business Capability (DBC) is a comprehensive framework established to facilitate and enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies within the European Union (EU). It aims to create a seamless digital environment that enables the exchange of data, information, and services across borders, fostering collaboration and innovation in the digital economy.&#xA;&#xA;The DBC recognizes the importance of interoperability in enabling efficient and effective communication, cooperation, and integration of digital systems and services. It seeks to address the challenges posed by the diverse IT landscapes, differing technical standards, and varying legal and regulatory frameworks across member states.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the DBC focuses on establishing a common set of technical specifications, standards, and protocols that ensure seamless connectivity and data exchange between different digital systems. It promotes the use of open standards and open interfaces, enabling interoperability between various IT systems, platforms, and applications.&#xA;&#xA;The DBC also emphasizes the importance of data sharing and accessibility. It encourages the development of common data models, formats, and APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) that enable the secure and standardized exchange of data across different systems. This facilitates the integration of data from various sources, enabling the creation of new digital services and applications.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the DBC recognizes the need for trust and security in digital exchanges. It promotes the use of secure authentication mechanisms, encryption techniques, and privacy-enhancing technologies to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of exchanged data. It also emphasizes compliance with relevant data protection and privacy regulations, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) within the EU.&#xA;&#xA;The DBC is not limited to the public sector but also extends its scope to private companies operating within the EU. It encourages the adoption of interoperability principles and standards by private enterprises, enabling them to seamlessly collaborate and integrate their digital systems with those of other organizations. This promotes cross-sectoral cooperation and innovation, leading to the development of new digital products, services, and business models.&#xA;&#xA;To support the implementation of the DBC, the EU provides various tools and resources. These include technical guidelines, reference architectures, best practices, and interoperability frameworks that assist member states and private companies in adopting and implementing interoperability solutions. The EU also facilitates knowledge sharing and collaboration through workshops, conferences, and communities of practice.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Digital Exchange Digital Business Capability is a comprehensive framework that aims to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies within the EU. It promotes the use of common technical specifications, standards, and protocols, facilitates data sharing and accessibility, ensures trust and security, and encourages collaboration and innovation in the digital economy. By fostering interoperability, the DBC enables the seamless exchange of data, information, and services, driving the digital transformation and integration of the European IT landscape.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The following implementation is an example on how this specific Architecture Building Block (ABB) can be instantiated as a Solution Building Block (SBB): ePrescription: &quot;Generation, transmission, and filling of a medical prescription through digital channels. ePrescribing allows a physician, pharmacist, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant to use digital prescription software to electronically transmit a new prescription or renewal authorization to a community or mail-order pharmacy&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalExchangeCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DigitalExchangeCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalExchangeCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Digital Exchange Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalExchangeCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalExchangeCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Digital Exchange Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Digital Exchange enables the transmission of digitally encoded information to profiled targets of stakeholders. "/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The following implementation is an example on how this specific Architecture Building Block (ABB) can be instantiated as a Solution Building Block (SBB): ePrescription: &quot;Generation, transmission, and filling of a medical prescription through digital channels. ePrescribing allows a physician, pharmacist, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant to use digital prescription software to electronically transmit a new prescription or renewal authorization to a community or mail-order pharmacy&quot;."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Digital Exchange Digital Business Capability (DBC) is a comprehensive framework established to facilitate and enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies within the European Union (EU). It aims to create a seamless digital environment that enables the exchange of data, information, and services across borders, fostering collaboration and innovation in the digital economy.&#xA;&#xA;The DBC recognizes the importance of interoperability in enabling efficient and effective communication, cooperation, and integration of digital systems and services. It seeks to address the challenges posed by the diverse IT landscapes, differing technical standards, and varying legal and regulatory frameworks across member states.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the DBC focuses on establishing a common set of technical specifications, standards, and protocols that ensure seamless connectivity and data exchange between different digital systems. It promotes the use of open standards and open interfaces, enabling interoperability between various IT systems, platforms, and applications.&#xA;&#xA;The DBC also emphasizes the importance of data sharing and accessibility. It encourages the development of common data models, formats, and APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) that enable the secure and standardized exchange of data across different systems. This facilitates the integration of data from various sources, enabling the creation of new digital services and applications.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the DBC recognizes the need for trust and security in digital exchanges. It promotes the use of secure authentication mechanisms, encryption techniques, and privacy-enhancing technologies to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of exchanged data. It also emphasizes compliance with relevant data protection and privacy regulations, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) within the EU.&#xA;&#xA;The DBC is not limited to the public sector but also extends its scope to private companies operating within the EU. It encourages the adoption of interoperability principles and standards by private enterprises, enabling them to seamlessly collaborate and integrate their digital systems with those of other organizations. This promotes cross-sectoral cooperation and innovation, leading to the development of new digital products, services, and business models.&#xA;&#xA;To support the implementation of the DBC, the EU provides various tools and resources. These include technical guidelines, reference architectures, best practices, and interoperability frameworks that assist member states and private companies in adopting and implementing interoperability solutions. The EU also facilitates knowledge sharing and collaboration through workshops, conferences, and communities of practice.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Digital Exchange Digital Business Capability is a comprehensive framework that aims to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies within the EU. It promotes the use of common technical specifications, standards, and protocols, facilitates data sharing and accessibility, ensures trust and security, and encourages collaboration and innovation in the digital economy. By fostering interoperability, the DBC enables the seamless exchange of data, information, and services, driving the digital transformation and integration of the European IT landscape."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Fred Turner"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://books.google.it/books?id=2SNFpgX_WigC&amp;pg=PA131&amp;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DigitalExchangeCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
