<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Security"
    id="id-34bc3528d3d84ece8e48e17dee41bd4d"
    documentation="Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: The Data Security Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to protect its digital assets and sensitive information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction. This capability encompasses the implementation of robust security measures, such as encryption, access controls, firewalls, intrusion detection systems, and security policies, to safeguard data and ensure compliance with regulatory requirements. It also involves the establishment of incident response plans and continuous monitoring to detect and mitigate potential security threats. By effectively managing data security, organizations can maintain the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of their digital assets, build trust with customers, and mitigate the risks associated with cyber threats.&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Data Security Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to protect its data assets from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction. It encompasses the processes, technologies, and practices employed to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of data throughout its lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;This capability involves the implementation of various security measures, controls, and safeguards to mitigate risks associated with data breaches, cyber threats, and compliance requirements. It aims to establish a secure environment that instills trust and confidence in stakeholders, including customers, partners, and employees.&#xA;&#xA;Key components of the Data Security Digital Business Capability include:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Classification and Governance: This involves the identification and categorization of data based on its sensitivity, value, and regulatory requirements. It includes defining data ownership, access controls, and data retention policies.&#xA;&#xA;2. Access Control and Authentication: This capability ensures that only authorized individuals or systems can access specific data. It involves implementing strong authentication mechanisms, such as multi-factor authentication, and role-based access controls to limit access to sensitive data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Encryption and Data Protection: Data encryption is a crucial aspect of data security. This capability involves encrypting data at rest, in transit, and in use to prevent unauthorized access. It also includes implementing data loss prevention (DLP) solutions and data masking techniques to protect sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;4. Threat Detection and Incident Response: This capability focuses on monitoring and detecting potential security threats and incidents. It involves implementing intrusion detection and prevention systems, security information and event management (SIEM) tools, and conducting regular security audits. Incident response plans and procedures are also established to effectively respond to and mitigate security incidents.&#xA;&#xA;5. Security Awareness and Training: This capability emphasizes educating employees and stakeholders about data security best practices, policies, and procedures. It includes conducting regular security awareness training sessions, phishing simulations, and promoting a culture of security awareness and responsibility.&#xA;&#xA;6. Compliance and Regulatory Requirements: Organizations must comply with various data protection regulations and industry standards. This capability involves understanding and adhering to relevant regulations, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).&#xA;&#xA;7. Security Incident Management and Reporting: This capability focuses on establishing processes and procedures for managing and reporting security incidents. It includes incident response planning, incident investigation, and reporting to relevant stakeholders, regulatory bodies, and law enforcement agencies, if required.&#xA;&#xA;By developing and maintaining a robust Data Security Digital Business Capability, organizations can safeguard their data assets, maintain customer trust, comply with regulations, and mitigate the risks associated with data breaches and cyber threats.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Data Security Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to the ability to protect sensitive information and ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of data. Here are some real examples of this capability in action:&#xA;&#xA;1. Secure Data Storage and Encryption: Public sector organizations often deal with large volumes of sensitive data, such as citizen records, financial information, and national security data. Implementing secure data storage solutions with encryption ensures that this information is protected from unauthorized access or breaches.&#xA;&#xA;2. Access Control and Authentication: Public sector entities need to control access to their systems and data to prevent unauthorized use. Implementing robust access control mechanisms, such as multi-factor authentication and role-based access control, helps ensure that only authorized personnel can access sensitive data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Incident Response and Threat Management: Public sector organizations face various cyber threats, including hacking attempts, malware, and phishing attacks. Having a well-defined incident response plan and a dedicated team to handle security incidents is crucial. This capability involves monitoring systems for potential threats, promptly responding to incidents, and implementing measures to mitigate risks.&#xA;&#xA;4. Compliance and Regulatory Requirements: Public sector entities must comply with various data protection regulations and standards, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) or the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). The Data Security Digital Business Capability involves establishing processes and controls to ensure compliance with these regulations, including data privacy, consent management, and data breach notification.&#xA;&#xA;5. Security Awareness and Training: Ensuring that employees are aware of data security best practices is essential in the public sector. This capability involves providing regular training and awareness programs to educate staff about potential risks, phishing attacks, social engineering, and other security threats. By promoting a security-conscious culture, organizations can reduce the likelihood of data breaches caused by human error.&#xA;&#xA;6. Secure Data Sharing and Collaboration: Public sector organizations often need to share data securely with external stakeholders, such as other government agencies, law enforcement, or international partners. Implementing secure data sharing platforms and protocols, such as secure file transfer protocols (SFTP) or encrypted communication channels, enables secure collaboration while protecting sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;These examples demonstrate how the Data Security Digital Business Capability is crucial in the public sector to safeguard sensitive data, maintain public trust, and comply with regulatory requirements.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSecurityCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DataSecurityCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSecurityCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Security Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSecurityCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataSecurityCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Security Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="The Data Security Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to protect its digital assets and sensitive information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction. This capability encompasses the implementation of robust security measures, such as encryption, access controls, firewalls, intrusion detection systems, and security policies, to safeguard data and ensure compliance with regulatory requirements. It also involves the establishment of incident response plans and continuous monitoring to detect and mitigate potential security threats. By effectively managing data security, organizations can maintain the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of their digital assets, build trust with customers, and mitigate the risks associated with cyber threats."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Data Security Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to the ability to protect sensitive information and ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of data. Here are some real examples of this capability in action:&#xA;&#xA;1. Secure Data Storage and Encryption: Public sector organizations often deal with large volumes of sensitive data, such as citizen records, financial information, and national security data. Implementing secure data storage solutions with encryption ensures that this information is protected from unauthorized access or breaches.&#xA;&#xA;2. Access Control and Authentication: Public sector entities need to control access to their systems and data to prevent unauthorized use. Implementing robust access control mechanisms, such as multi-factor authentication and role-based access control, helps ensure that only authorized personnel can access sensitive data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Incident Response and Threat Management: Public sector organizations face various cyber threats, including hacking attempts, malware, and phishing attacks. Having a well-defined incident response plan and a dedicated team to handle security incidents is crucial. This capability involves monitoring systems for potential threats, promptly responding to incidents, and implementing measures to mitigate risks.&#xA;&#xA;4. Compliance and Regulatory Requirements: Public sector entities must comply with various data protection regulations and standards, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) or the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). The Data Security Digital Business Capability involves establishing processes and controls to ensure compliance with these regulations, including data privacy, consent management, and data breach notification.&#xA;&#xA;5. Security Awareness and Training: Ensuring that employees are aware of data security best practices is essential in the public sector. This capability involves providing regular training and awareness programs to educate staff about potential risks, phishing attacks, social engineering, and other security threats. By promoting a security-conscious culture, organizations can reduce the likelihood of data breaches caused by human error.&#xA;&#xA;6. Secure Data Sharing and Collaboration: Public sector organizations often need to share data securely with external stakeholders, such as other government agencies, law enforcement, or international partners. Implementing secure data sharing platforms and protocols, such as secure file transfer protocols (SFTP) or encrypted communication channels, enables secure collaboration while protecting sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;These examples demonstrate how the Data Security Digital Business Capability is crucial in the public sector to safeguard sensitive data, maintain public trust, and comply with regulatory requirements."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Data Security Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to protect its data assets from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction. It encompasses the processes, technologies, and practices employed to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of data throughout its lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;This capability involves the implementation of various security measures, controls, and safeguards to mitigate risks associated with data breaches, cyber threats, and compliance requirements. It aims to establish a secure environment that instills trust and confidence in stakeholders, including customers, partners, and employees.&#xA;&#xA;Key components of the Data Security Digital Business Capability include:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Classification and Governance: This involves the identification and categorization of data based on its sensitivity, value, and regulatory requirements. It includes defining data ownership, access controls, and data retention policies.&#xA;&#xA;2. Access Control and Authentication: This capability ensures that only authorized individuals or systems can access specific data. It involves implementing strong authentication mechanisms, such as multi-factor authentication, and role-based access controls to limit access to sensitive data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Encryption and Data Protection: Data encryption is a crucial aspect of data security. This capability involves encrypting data at rest, in transit, and in use to prevent unauthorized access. It also includes implementing data loss prevention (DLP) solutions and data masking techniques to protect sensitive information.&#xA;&#xA;4. Threat Detection and Incident Response: This capability focuses on monitoring and detecting potential security threats and incidents. It involves implementing intrusion detection and prevention systems, security information and event management (SIEM) tools, and conducting regular security audits. Incident response plans and procedures are also established to effectively respond to and mitigate security incidents.&#xA;&#xA;5. Security Awareness and Training: This capability emphasizes educating employees and stakeholders about data security best practices, policies, and procedures. It includes conducting regular security awareness training sessions, phishing simulations, and promoting a culture of security awareness and responsibility.&#xA;&#xA;6. Compliance and Regulatory Requirements: Organizations must comply with various data protection regulations and industry standards. This capability involves understanding and adhering to relevant regulations, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).&#xA;&#xA;7. Security Incident Management and Reporting: This capability focuses on establishing processes and procedures for managing and reporting security incidents. It includes incident response planning, incident investigation, and reporting to relevant stakeholders, regulatory bodies, and law enforcement agencies, if required.&#xA;&#xA;By developing and maintaining a robust Data Security Digital Business Capability, organizations can safeguard their data assets, maintain customer trust, comply with regulations, and mitigate the risks associated with data breaches and cyber threats."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DataSecurityCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
