<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Digital Communication"
    id="id-45d6b5f230a74810b5e7d8db0a4eb1fa"
    documentation="Definition: Digital Communication enables the virtual collaboration of a group of people engaged in common tasks, using information and communication technologies.&#xA;&#xA;Source: John G. Proakis&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://books.google.it/books/about/Digital_Communications.html?id=ABSmAQAACAAJ&amp;redir_esc=y&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Digital Communication Digital Business Capability is a crucial aspect of the European IT interoperability framework that aims to facilitate seamless communication and collaboration between member states and private companies within the European Union. It encompasses a wide range of digital communication technologies, standards, and protocols that enable efficient and secure exchange of information and data across different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability focuses on establishing a common set of rules, guidelines, and technical specifications to ensure interoperability and compatibility among various digital communication systems used by member states and private companies. This capability plays a vital role in promoting digital transformation, enhancing cross-border trade, and fostering innovation and economic growth across the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key objectives of the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability is to enable seamless electronic communication between public administrations, businesses, and citizens. This involves the development and implementation of standardized electronic messaging formats, such as XML or EDI, which allow for the exchange of structured data and documents in a machine-readable format. By adopting these common formats, member states and private companies can streamline their communication processes, reduce administrative burdens, and improve overall efficiency.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability encompasses the establishment of secure and reliable communication channels, including secure email, virtual private networks (VPNs), and encrypted data transmission protocols. These measures ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of exchanged information, protecting sensitive data from unauthorized access or tampering.&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability is a key aspect of the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability, as it enables different systems and platforms to seamlessly communicate and exchange data. To achieve this, the capability promotes the use of open standards and specifications, such as those developed by international organizations like the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) or the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI). By adhering to these standards, member states and private companies can ensure that their digital communication systems are compatible with each other, regardless of the underlying technologies or vendors involved.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability also addresses the need for multilingual and multicultural communication within the European Union. It promotes the development and adoption of language technologies, such as machine translation or natural language processing, to facilitate communication and understanding across different languages and cultures. This capability plays a crucial role in enabling cross-border collaboration, trade, and the provision of digital services to citizens and businesses across the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability is a comprehensive framework that aims to enhance European IT interoperability by establishing common rules, standards, and technologies for digital communication among member states and private companies. It encompasses various aspects, including the adoption of standardized messaging formats, secure communication channels, open standards, and multilingual/multicultural communication technologies. By promoting interoperability, this capability facilitates seamless collaboration, trade, and innovation within the European Union, ultimately driving economic growth and digital transformation.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The application of Digital Communication Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can be seen in various areas. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. eIDAS Regulation: The eIDAS (electronic Identification, Authentication and Trust Services) Regulation aims to facilitate secure cross-border electronic transactions within the European Union. It establishes a framework for recognizing and accepting electronic identification and trust services across member states. Digital Communication Digital Business Capability enables the implementation of interoperable electronic identification and authentication mechanisms, ensuring seamless communication and trust between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;2. European Single Digital Gateway: The European Single Digital Gateway initiative aims to provide citizens and businesses with easy access to information, procedures, and assistance services across the EU. Digital Communication Digital Business Capability plays a crucial role in enabling the development of a user-friendly and interoperable digital platform that allows seamless communication between member states and private companies, ensuring efficient access to information and services.&#xA;&#xA;3. Cross-border e-commerce: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability facilitates cross-border e-commerce activities by enabling interoperable digital communication channels between member states and private companies. This includes standardized electronic data interchange (EDI) protocols, electronic invoicing, and secure online payment systems. These capabilities ensure smooth and efficient communication between businesses and consumers across different member states, promoting cross-border trade.&#xA;&#xA;4. Interoperable data exchange: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability enables the exchange of data and information between member states and private companies in a standardized and interoperable manner. This includes the use of common data formats, protocols, and APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) to ensure seamless data exchange and integration between different systems and platforms. This capability is essential for efficient collaboration and information sharing among member states and private companies in areas such as public administration, healthcare, and transportation.&#xA;&#xA;5. Harmonized cybersecurity standards: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability supports the development and implementation of harmonized cybersecurity standards across member states and private companies. This includes the establishment of common cybersecurity frameworks, protocols, and best practices to ensure the secure exchange of digital information and protect critical infrastructure. Interoperability in cybersecurity measures enhances trust and confidence in digital communication and business transactions among member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Digital Communication Digital Business Capability in European IT interoperability among member states and private companies aims to foster seamless communication, efficient information exchange, and trust in digital transactions, ultimately promoting the growth of the digital economy within the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalCommunicationCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DigitalCommunicationCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalCommunicationCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalCommunicationCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalCommunicationCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Digital Communication Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Digital Communication enables the virtual collaboration of a group of people engaged in common tasks, using information and communication technologies."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The application of Digital Communication Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can be seen in various areas. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. eIDAS Regulation: The eIDAS (electronic Identification, Authentication and Trust Services) Regulation aims to facilitate secure cross-border electronic transactions within the European Union. It establishes a framework for recognizing and accepting electronic identification and trust services across member states. Digital Communication Digital Business Capability enables the implementation of interoperable electronic identification and authentication mechanisms, ensuring seamless communication and trust between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;2. European Single Digital Gateway: The European Single Digital Gateway initiative aims to provide citizens and businesses with easy access to information, procedures, and assistance services across the EU. Digital Communication Digital Business Capability plays a crucial role in enabling the development of a user-friendly and interoperable digital platform that allows seamless communication between member states and private companies, ensuring efficient access to information and services.&#xA;&#xA;3. Cross-border e-commerce: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability facilitates cross-border e-commerce activities by enabling interoperable digital communication channels between member states and private companies. This includes standardized electronic data interchange (EDI) protocols, electronic invoicing, and secure online payment systems. These capabilities ensure smooth and efficient communication between businesses and consumers across different member states, promoting cross-border trade.&#xA;&#xA;4. Interoperable data exchange: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability enables the exchange of data and information between member states and private companies in a standardized and interoperable manner. This includes the use of common data formats, protocols, and APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) to ensure seamless data exchange and integration between different systems and platforms. This capability is essential for efficient collaboration and information sharing among member states and private companies in areas such as public administration, healthcare, and transportation.&#xA;&#xA;5. Harmonized cybersecurity standards: Digital Communication Digital Business Capability supports the development and implementation of harmonized cybersecurity standards across member states and private companies. This includes the establishment of common cybersecurity frameworks, protocols, and best practices to ensure the secure exchange of digital information and protect critical infrastructure. Interoperability in cybersecurity measures enhances trust and confidence in digital communication and business transactions among member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Digital Communication Digital Business Capability in European IT interoperability among member states and private companies aims to foster seamless communication, efficient information exchange, and trust in digital transactions, ultimately promoting the growth of the digital economy within the European Union."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Digital Communication Digital Business Capability is a crucial aspect of the European IT interoperability framework that aims to facilitate seamless communication and collaboration between member states and private companies within the European Union. It encompasses a wide range of digital communication technologies, standards, and protocols that enable efficient and secure exchange of information and data across different systems and platforms.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability focuses on establishing a common set of rules, guidelines, and technical specifications to ensure interoperability and compatibility among various digital communication systems used by member states and private companies. This capability plays a vital role in promoting digital transformation, enhancing cross-border trade, and fostering innovation and economic growth across the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key objectives of the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability is to enable seamless electronic communication between public administrations, businesses, and citizens. This involves the development and implementation of standardized electronic messaging formats, such as XML or EDI, which allow for the exchange of structured data and documents in a machine-readable format. By adopting these common formats, member states and private companies can streamline their communication processes, reduce administrative burdens, and improve overall efficiency.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability encompasses the establishment of secure and reliable communication channels, including secure email, virtual private networks (VPNs), and encrypted data transmission protocols. These measures ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of exchanged information, protecting sensitive data from unauthorized access or tampering.&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability is a key aspect of the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability, as it enables different systems and platforms to seamlessly communicate and exchange data. To achieve this, the capability promotes the use of open standards and specifications, such as those developed by international organizations like the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) or the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI). By adhering to these standards, member states and private companies can ensure that their digital communication systems are compatible with each other, regardless of the underlying technologies or vendors involved.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability also addresses the need for multilingual and multicultural communication within the European Union. It promotes the development and adoption of language technologies, such as machine translation or natural language processing, to facilitate communication and understanding across different languages and cultures. This capability plays a crucial role in enabling cross-border collaboration, trade, and the provision of digital services to citizens and businesses across the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Digital Communication Digital Business Capability is a comprehensive framework that aims to enhance European IT interoperability by establishing common rules, standards, and technologies for digital communication among member states and private companies. It encompasses various aspects, including the adoption of standardized messaging formats, secure communication channels, open standards, and multilingual/multicultural communication technologies. By promoting interoperability, this capability facilitates seamless collaboration, trade, and innovation within the European Union, ultimately driving economic growth and digital transformation."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="John G. Proakis"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://books.google.it/books/about/Digital_Communications.html?id=ABSmAQAACAAJ&amp;redir_esc=y"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DigitalCommunicationCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
