<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Artificial Intelligence"
    id="id-eb71c828b34e408cb828307c9113c630"
    documentation="Definition: The capability to connect physical devices, sensors, and objects to the internet, enabling data collection, remote monitoring, and control of devices, and facilitating automation and integration within business processes.&#xA;&#xA;Source: Gartner&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4008663/hype-cycle-for-artificial-intelligence-2021&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Artificial Intelligence (AI) Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies refers to the integration and utilization of AI technologies to enhance the efficiency, effectiveness, and collaboration in various business processes across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;AI, as a field of computer science, focuses on developing intelligent machines that can perform tasks that typically require human intelligence. It encompasses various subfields such as machine learning, natural language processing, computer vision, and robotics. The application of AI in the digital business realm aims to automate and augment decision-making processes, improve customer experiences, optimize operations, and enable data-driven insights.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Union (EU), IT interoperability refers to the ability of different systems, applications, and devices to seamlessly exchange and use information. It is crucial for member states and private companies to ensure interoperability to facilitate smooth communication, data sharing, and collaboration across borders. The AI Digital Business Capability plays a significant role in achieving this interoperability by leveraging AI technologies to address challenges and unlock opportunities.&#xA;&#xA;One aspect of AI Digital Business Capability is the development and deployment of AI-powered applications and services that can be used by member states and private companies. These applications can range from chatbots and virtual assistants for customer support to predictive analytics tools for business forecasting. By adopting AI-powered solutions, organizations can streamline their operations, improve decision-making processes, and enhance customer experiences.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, AI can contribute to the standardization and harmonization of data formats, protocols, and interfaces, which are essential for interoperability. AI algorithms can be employed to analyze and transform data from different sources into a common format, enabling seamless data exchange and integration. This facilitates collaboration and information sharing among member states and private companies, leading to improved efficiency and effectiveness in various domains such as healthcare, transportation, finance, and public administration.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, AI Digital Business Capability can support the development of AI ecosystems and innovation networks across Europe. By fostering collaboration between member states, research institutions, and private companies, it encourages the exchange of knowledge, expertise, and best practices in AI. This collaboration can lead to the development of AI technologies and solutions that are tailored to the specific needs and challenges of the European context.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the ethical and responsible use of AI in the European IT interoperability landscape, the EU has also been actively working on establishing guidelines and regulations. The European Commission has proposed the creation of a European AI regulatory framework that promotes transparency, accountability, and human-centric AI. This framework aims to address concerns related to privacy, bias, and fairness in AI systems, ensuring that AI technologies are developed and deployed in a manner that aligns with European values and principles.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the AI Digital Business Capability in the European IT interoperability context encompasses the integration and utilization of AI technologies to enhance collaboration, efficiency, and effectiveness among member states and private companies. It involves the development of AI-powered applications, the standardization of data formats and interfaces, the fostering of AI ecosystems, and the establishment of ethical guidelines and regulations. By leveraging AI, Europe can unlock the potential of digital transformation, drive innovation, and achieve seamless interoperability in the digital business landscape.&#xA;&#xA;Example: There are several examples of how Artificial Intelligence (AI) can be applied to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies in Europe. Here are a few:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Integration and Standardization: AI can be used to automate the integration and standardization of data across different systems and formats. This helps in achieving seamless interoperability between member states and private companies by ensuring that data can be easily exchanged and understood by all parties involved.&#xA;&#xA;2. Natural Language Processing (NLP): NLP techniques can be employed to enable multilingual communication and understanding between different systems and stakeholders. This facilitates efficient collaboration and information exchange, overcoming language barriers and promoting interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;3. Intelligent Data Mapping: AI algorithms can be utilized to map and align data elements from different systems, enabling interoperability by ensuring that data from various sources can be accurately interpreted and utilized by different entities. This helps in achieving a common understanding of data across member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Intelligent Decision Support Systems: AI-powered decision support systems can assist in making complex decisions related to IT interoperability. These systems can analyze vast amounts of data, identify patterns, and provide recommendations for improving interoperability, thereby enhancing efficiency and effectiveness in cross-border collaborations.&#xA;&#xA;5. Predictive Analytics: AI techniques, such as machine learning, can be applied to analyze historical data and predict future trends and patterns. This can help member states and private companies anticipate interoperability challenges and proactively address them, ensuring smooth operations and minimizing disruptions.&#xA;&#xA;6. Intelligent Automation: AI-driven automation can streamline and optimize interoperability processes by automating repetitive tasks, reducing manual effort, and minimizing errors. This can include tasks like data validation, data transformation, and data exchange, enabling efficient and reliable interoperability among different systems.&#xA;&#xA;These are just a few examples of how AI can be applied to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies in Europe. The potential applications of AI in this domain are vast and continually evolving as technology advances.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ArtificialIntelligenceCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:ArtificialIntelligenceCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ArtificialIntelligenceCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Artificial Intelligence Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ArtificialIntelligenceCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ArtificialIntelligenceCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Artificial Intelligence Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="The capability to connect physical devices, sensors, and objects to the internet, enabling data collection, remote monitoring, and control of devices, and facilitating automation and integration within business processes."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="There are several examples of how Artificial Intelligence (AI) can be applied to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies in Europe. Here are a few:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Integration and Standardization: AI can be used to automate the integration and standardization of data across different systems and formats. This helps in achieving seamless interoperability between member states and private companies by ensuring that data can be easily exchanged and understood by all parties involved.&#xA;&#xA;2. Natural Language Processing (NLP): NLP techniques can be employed to enable multilingual communication and understanding between different systems and stakeholders. This facilitates efficient collaboration and information exchange, overcoming language barriers and promoting interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;3. Intelligent Data Mapping: AI algorithms can be utilized to map and align data elements from different systems, enabling interoperability by ensuring that data from various sources can be accurately interpreted and utilized by different entities. This helps in achieving a common understanding of data across member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Intelligent Decision Support Systems: AI-powered decision support systems can assist in making complex decisions related to IT interoperability. These systems can analyze vast amounts of data, identify patterns, and provide recommendations for improving interoperability, thereby enhancing efficiency and effectiveness in cross-border collaborations.&#xA;&#xA;5. Predictive Analytics: AI techniques, such as machine learning, can be applied to analyze historical data and predict future trends and patterns. This can help member states and private companies anticipate interoperability challenges and proactively address them, ensuring smooth operations and minimizing disruptions.&#xA;&#xA;6. Intelligent Automation: AI-driven automation can streamline and optimize interoperability processes by automating repetitive tasks, reducing manual effort, and minimizing errors. This can include tasks like data validation, data transformation, and data exchange, enabling efficient and reliable interoperability among different systems.&#xA;&#xA;These are just a few examples of how AI can be applied to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies in Europe. The potential applications of AI in this domain are vast and continually evolving as technology advances."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Artificial Intelligence (AI) Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies refers to the integration and utilization of AI technologies to enhance the efficiency, effectiveness, and collaboration in various business processes across Europe.&#xA;&#xA;AI, as a field of computer science, focuses on developing intelligent machines that can perform tasks that typically require human intelligence. It encompasses various subfields such as machine learning, natural language processing, computer vision, and robotics. The application of AI in the digital business realm aims to automate and augment decision-making processes, improve customer experiences, optimize operations, and enable data-driven insights.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Union (EU), IT interoperability refers to the ability of different systems, applications, and devices to seamlessly exchange and use information. It is crucial for member states and private companies to ensure interoperability to facilitate smooth communication, data sharing, and collaboration across borders. The AI Digital Business Capability plays a significant role in achieving this interoperability by leveraging AI technologies to address challenges and unlock opportunities.&#xA;&#xA;One aspect of AI Digital Business Capability is the development and deployment of AI-powered applications and services that can be used by member states and private companies. These applications can range from chatbots and virtual assistants for customer support to predictive analytics tools for business forecasting. By adopting AI-powered solutions, organizations can streamline their operations, improve decision-making processes, and enhance customer experiences.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, AI can contribute to the standardization and harmonization of data formats, protocols, and interfaces, which are essential for interoperability. AI algorithms can be employed to analyze and transform data from different sources into a common format, enabling seamless data exchange and integration. This facilitates collaboration and information sharing among member states and private companies, leading to improved efficiency and effectiveness in various domains such as healthcare, transportation, finance, and public administration.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, AI Digital Business Capability can support the development of AI ecosystems and innovation networks across Europe. By fostering collaboration between member states, research institutions, and private companies, it encourages the exchange of knowledge, expertise, and best practices in AI. This collaboration can lead to the development of AI technologies and solutions that are tailored to the specific needs and challenges of the European context.&#xA;&#xA;To ensure the ethical and responsible use of AI in the European IT interoperability landscape, the EU has also been actively working on establishing guidelines and regulations. The European Commission has proposed the creation of a European AI regulatory framework that promotes transparency, accountability, and human-centric AI. This framework aims to address concerns related to privacy, bias, and fairness in AI systems, ensuring that AI technologies are developed and deployed in a manner that aligns with European values and principles.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the AI Digital Business Capability in the European IT interoperability context encompasses the integration and utilization of AI technologies to enhance collaboration, efficiency, and effectiveness among member states and private companies. It involves the development of AI-powered applications, the standardization of data formats and interfaces, the fostering of AI ecosystems, and the establishment of ethical guidelines and regulations. By leveraging AI, Europe can unlock the potential of digital transformation, drive innovation, and achieve seamless interoperability in the digital business landscape."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Gartner"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4008663/hype-cycle-for-artificial-intelligence-2021"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:ArtificialIntelligenceCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
