<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Qualification Management"
    id="id-95c5757fa6a84bf4a20d05fb368b3f32"
    documentation="Definition: Qualification Management enables the electronic validation and verification of the qualifications (any information linked to an individual with respect to the education and employment status) of the professionals against specific requirements defined by relevant legislations.&#xA;&#xA;Source: Oracle&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.oracle.com/a/ocom/docs/applications/erp/oracle-supplier-qualification-management-cloud-ds.pdf&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Qualification Management Digital Business Capability (QMDBC) is a comprehensive framework and set of digital tools designed to facilitate and enhance the interoperability of IT systems and processes related to qualifications management among member states and private companies in Europe. It aims to streamline and harmonize the exchange of qualification-related information, ensuring consistency, efficiency, and transparency across borders.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the QMDBC encompasses a range of digital solutions and standards that enable the seamless sharing, recognition, and validation of qualifications across different countries and organizations. It provides a common platform for member states and private companies to collaborate and exchange information on qualifications, enabling individuals to have their qualifications recognized and valued in various contexts.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key components of the QMDBC is a centralized database or repository that stores and manages qualification-related data. This database serves as a single source of truth, containing information on qualifications, competencies, skills, and other relevant attributes. It allows member states and private companies to access and verify qualifications, ensuring accuracy and reliability in the recognition process.&#xA;&#xA;The QMDBC also incorporates standardized data formats and protocols to ensure compatibility and interoperability among different IT systems. This includes the use of common data models, metadata standards, and communication protocols, enabling seamless integration and exchange of qualification data between member states and private companies. These standards facilitate the automated processing and validation of qualifications, reducing administrative burdens and improving the efficiency of recognition procedures.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the QMDBC includes digital tools and services that support the management and assessment of qualifications. These tools enable member states and private companies to evaluate and compare qualifications, assess their relevance and equivalence, and make informed decisions regarding recognition and validation. They may include online assessment platforms, qualification frameworks, competency mapping tools, and other digital resources that enhance the transparency and objectivity of the qualification recognition process.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to the technical aspects, the QMDBC also encompasses governance and policy frameworks that guide the implementation and operation of the interoperability infrastructure. This includes the establishment of common rules, procedures, and quality assurance mechanisms to ensure the reliability and trustworthiness of qualification information. It also involves the collaboration and coordination among member states, private companies, and relevant stakeholders to address legal, regulatory, and ethical considerations associated with qualification recognition and interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Qualification Management Digital Business Capability plays a crucial role in promoting the harmonization and interoperability of qualification management systems across Europe. By providing a standardized and efficient framework for exchanging qualification-related information, it facilitates the recognition and validation of qualifications, enhances labor mobility, and supports the development of a skilled and competitive workforce in the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Qualification Management Digital Business Capability can be applied in various ways to enhance European IT interoperability among member states and private companies. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Digital Credentialing: The capability can be used to establish a standardized system for issuing and managing digital credentials, such as diplomas, certifications, and licenses. This would enable seamless recognition of qualifications across member states and private companies, reducing administrative burden and facilitating mobility of IT professionals.&#xA;&#xA;2. Cross-border Recognition: The capability can support the development of a common framework for recognizing qualifications across European countries. By digitizing and harmonizing qualification management processes, member states and private companies can easily verify and accept qualifications obtained in other jurisdictions, promoting workforce mobility and facilitating cross-border collaborations.&#xA;&#xA;3. Competency Mapping: The capability can enable the creation of a comprehensive competency mapping system, which aligns IT qualifications with specific job roles and skills required in the industry. This would help member states and private companies in identifying and matching the right talent for specific IT projects or job vacancies, ensuring a better fit between qualifications and job requirements.&#xA;&#xA;4. Interoperable Learning Management Systems: The capability can facilitate the integration of different learning management systems used by member states and private companies. This would enable seamless exchange of training and educational resources, fostering collaboration and knowledge sharing among European IT stakeholders.&#xA;&#xA;5. Quality Assurance and Accreditation: The capability can support the establishment of a unified quality assurance and accreditation framework for IT qualifications. By digitizing and automating the accreditation processes, member states and private companies can ensure consistent quality standards across Europe, enhancing trust and reliability in the IT workforce.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Qualification Management Digital Business Capability can play a crucial role in promoting harmonization, standardization, and interoperability of IT qualifications among member states and private companies in Europe.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationManagementCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:QualificationManagementCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationManagementCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Qualification Management Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationManagementCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/QualificationManagementCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Qualification Management Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Qualification Management enables the electronic validation and verification of the qualifications (any information linked to an individual with respect to the education and employment status) of the professionals against specific requirements defined by relevant legislations."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Qualification Management Digital Business Capability can be applied in various ways to enhance European IT interoperability among member states and private companies. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Digital Credentialing: The capability can be used to establish a standardized system for issuing and managing digital credentials, such as diplomas, certifications, and licenses. This would enable seamless recognition of qualifications across member states and private companies, reducing administrative burden and facilitating mobility of IT professionals.&#xA;&#xA;2. Cross-border Recognition: The capability can support the development of a common framework for recognizing qualifications across European countries. By digitizing and harmonizing qualification management processes, member states and private companies can easily verify and accept qualifications obtained in other jurisdictions, promoting workforce mobility and facilitating cross-border collaborations.&#xA;&#xA;3. Competency Mapping: The capability can enable the creation of a comprehensive competency mapping system, which aligns IT qualifications with specific job roles and skills required in the industry. This would help member states and private companies in identifying and matching the right talent for specific IT projects or job vacancies, ensuring a better fit between qualifications and job requirements.&#xA;&#xA;4. Interoperable Learning Management Systems: The capability can facilitate the integration of different learning management systems used by member states and private companies. This would enable seamless exchange of training and educational resources, fostering collaboration and knowledge sharing among European IT stakeholders.&#xA;&#xA;5. Quality Assurance and Accreditation: The capability can support the establishment of a unified quality assurance and accreditation framework for IT qualifications. By digitizing and automating the accreditation processes, member states and private companies can ensure consistent quality standards across Europe, enhancing trust and reliability in the IT workforce.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Qualification Management Digital Business Capability can play a crucial role in promoting harmonization, standardization, and interoperability of IT qualifications among member states and private companies in Europe."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Qualification Management Digital Business Capability (QMDBC) is a comprehensive framework and set of digital tools designed to facilitate and enhance the interoperability of IT systems and processes related to qualifications management among member states and private companies in Europe. It aims to streamline and harmonize the exchange of qualification-related information, ensuring consistency, efficiency, and transparency across borders.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the QMDBC encompasses a range of digital solutions and standards that enable the seamless sharing, recognition, and validation of qualifications across different countries and organizations. It provides a common platform for member states and private companies to collaborate and exchange information on qualifications, enabling individuals to have their qualifications recognized and valued in various contexts.&#xA;&#xA;One of the key components of the QMDBC is a centralized database or repository that stores and manages qualification-related data. This database serves as a single source of truth, containing information on qualifications, competencies, skills, and other relevant attributes. It allows member states and private companies to access and verify qualifications, ensuring accuracy and reliability in the recognition process.&#xA;&#xA;The QMDBC also incorporates standardized data formats and protocols to ensure compatibility and interoperability among different IT systems. This includes the use of common data models, metadata standards, and communication protocols, enabling seamless integration and exchange of qualification data between member states and private companies. These standards facilitate the automated processing and validation of qualifications, reducing administrative burdens and improving the efficiency of recognition procedures.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the QMDBC includes digital tools and services that support the management and assessment of qualifications. These tools enable member states and private companies to evaluate and compare qualifications, assess their relevance and equivalence, and make informed decisions regarding recognition and validation. They may include online assessment platforms, qualification frameworks, competency mapping tools, and other digital resources that enhance the transparency and objectivity of the qualification recognition process.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to the technical aspects, the QMDBC also encompasses governance and policy frameworks that guide the implementation and operation of the interoperability infrastructure. This includes the establishment of common rules, procedures, and quality assurance mechanisms to ensure the reliability and trustworthiness of qualification information. It also involves the collaboration and coordination among member states, private companies, and relevant stakeholders to address legal, regulatory, and ethical considerations associated with qualification recognition and interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Qualification Management Digital Business Capability plays a crucial role in promoting the harmonization and interoperability of qualification management systems across Europe. By providing a standardized and efficient framework for exchanging qualification-related information, it facilitates the recognition and validation of qualifications, enhances labor mobility, and supports the development of a skilled and competitive workforce in the European Union."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="Oracle"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.oracle.com/a/ocom/docs/applications/erp/oracle-supplier-qualification-management-cloud-ds.pdf"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:QualificationManagementCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
