<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Ethics"
    id="id-0f97b875ae78486ab6f051d14f198590"
    documentation="Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: The Data Ethics Digital Business Capability refers to an organization's ability to ensure ethical practices and responsible use of data in its digital operations. It involves establishing policies, guidelines, and frameworks that govern the collection, storage, processing, and sharing of data, with a focus on maintaining privacy, security, and compliance with legal and regulatory requirements. This capability also encompasses the development of ethical data practices, such as transparency, consent, and accountability, to build trust with customers, partners, and stakeholders. By prioritizing data ethics, organizations can mitigate risks, protect individuals' rights, and foster a culture of responsible data management in the digital era.&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Data Ethics Digital Business Capability refers to the organization's ability to establish and maintain ethical practices and principles related to the collection, storage, processing, and usage of data. It encompasses the policies, procedures, and frameworks that ensure the responsible and ethical handling of data throughout its lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;This capability involves understanding and adhering to legal and regulatory requirements, industry standards, and best practices concerning data privacy, security, consent, transparency, and accountability. It aims to protect individuals' rights and interests while enabling the organization to leverage data effectively for business purposes.&#xA;&#xA;Key components of the Data Ethics Digital Business Capability include:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Governance: This involves establishing a framework for data management, including defining roles, responsibilities, and processes for data handling. It ensures that data is collected, stored, and used in compliance with applicable laws and regulations.&#xA;&#xA;2. Privacy and Consent Management: This component focuses on obtaining appropriate consent from individuals for data collection and processing activities. It includes implementing mechanisms to manage and respect individuals' privacy rights, such as providing clear and transparent privacy notices and enabling individuals to exercise their rights over their data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Data Security: This component encompasses measures to protect data from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. It involves implementing robust security controls, encryption, access controls, and monitoring mechanisms to safeguard data against potential threats and breaches.&#xA;&#xA;4. Ethical Data Use: This component emphasizes the responsible and ethical use of data. It involves establishing guidelines and policies for data usage, ensuring that data is used only for legitimate business purposes and in a manner that respects individuals' rights and interests.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Transparency and Accountability: This component focuses on promoting transparency and accountability in data practices. It includes providing individuals with clear information about how their data is being used, enabling them to make informed choices. It also involves establishing mechanisms for individuals to access, rectify, or delete their data and addressing any concerns or complaints related to data handling.&#xA;&#xA;6. Training and Awareness: This component emphasizes the importance of educating employees about data ethics and their responsibilities in handling data. It includes providing training programs, awareness campaigns, and resources to ensure that employees understand and adhere to ethical data practices.&#xA;&#xA;7. Continuous Improvement: This component involves regularly reviewing and updating data ethics practices to align with evolving legal, regulatory, and industry requirements. It includes conducting audits, assessments, and risk evaluations to identify areas for improvement and implementing necessary changes to enhance data ethics capabilities.&#xA;&#xA;By developing and maintaining the Data Ethics Digital Business Capability, organizations can build trust with their customers, partners, and stakeholders. It helps them mitigate risks associated with data breaches, regulatory non-compliance, and reputational damage while fostering a culture of responsible data handling and ethical decision-making.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Data Ethics Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to an organization's ability to ensure ethical practices and compliance with data protection regulations while leveraging digital technologies. Here are some real examples of this capability in action:&#xA;&#xA;1. Privacy Impact Assessments (PIAs): Public sector organizations conduct PIAs to assess the potential privacy risks associated with new digital initiatives. For instance, when implementing a citizen-facing online service, a government agency may evaluate the data collection, storage, and usage practices to ensure compliance with privacy regulations and ethical standards.&#xA;&#xA;2. Data anonymization and de-identification: Public sector entities often deal with sensitive citizen data. To protect privacy, they employ techniques like data anonymization and de-identification. For example, a health department might remove personally identifiable information from medical records before sharing them with researchers, ensuring privacy while enabling valuable data analysis.&#xA;&#xA;3. Ethical AI and algorithmic governance: Public sector organizations increasingly employ artificial intelligence (AI) and algorithms to improve decision-making processes. The Data Ethics capability ensures that these technologies are used ethically and fairly. For instance, an employment agency may implement algorithmic governance frameworks to prevent bias in AI-driven hiring processes, ensuring equal opportunities for all candidates.&#xA;&#xA;4. Consent management and data transparency: Public sector entities prioritize obtaining informed consent from citizens for data collection and usage. They also focus on providing transparent information about how data is handled. For instance, a tax authority may allow citizens to manage their consent preferences for sharing tax-related data with other government agencies, ensuring control and transparency over personal information.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data breach response and incident management: Public sector organizations need to be prepared for data breaches and incidents. The Data Ethics capability includes establishing protocols for timely response, notification, and mitigation of such events. For example, a local government may have a well-defined incident response plan to handle a cybersecurity breach, ensuring minimal impact on citizen data and privacy.&#xA;&#xA;These examples demonstrate how the Data Ethics Digital Business Capability in the public sector ensures responsible and ethical handling of data while leveraging digital technologies to deliver efficient and citizen-centric services.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataEthicsCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DataEthicsCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataEthicsCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Ethics Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataEthicsCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataEthicsCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Ethics Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="The Data Ethics Digital Business Capability refers to an organization's ability to ensure ethical practices and responsible use of data in its digital operations. It involves establishing policies, guidelines, and frameworks that govern the collection, storage, processing, and sharing of data, with a focus on maintaining privacy, security, and compliance with legal and regulatory requirements. This capability also encompasses the development of ethical data practices, such as transparency, consent, and accountability, to build trust with customers, partners, and stakeholders. By prioritizing data ethics, organizations can mitigate risks, protect individuals' rights, and foster a culture of responsible data management in the digital era."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Data Ethics Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to an organization's ability to ensure ethical practices and compliance with data protection regulations while leveraging digital technologies. Here are some real examples of this capability in action:&#xA;&#xA;1. Privacy Impact Assessments (PIAs): Public sector organizations conduct PIAs to assess the potential privacy risks associated with new digital initiatives. For instance, when implementing a citizen-facing online service, a government agency may evaluate the data collection, storage, and usage practices to ensure compliance with privacy regulations and ethical standards.&#xA;&#xA;2. Data anonymization and de-identification: Public sector entities often deal with sensitive citizen data. To protect privacy, they employ techniques like data anonymization and de-identification. For example, a health department might remove personally identifiable information from medical records before sharing them with researchers, ensuring privacy while enabling valuable data analysis.&#xA;&#xA;3. Ethical AI and algorithmic governance: Public sector organizations increasingly employ artificial intelligence (AI) and algorithms to improve decision-making processes. The Data Ethics capability ensures that these technologies are used ethically and fairly. For instance, an employment agency may implement algorithmic governance frameworks to prevent bias in AI-driven hiring processes, ensuring equal opportunities for all candidates.&#xA;&#xA;4. Consent management and data transparency: Public sector entities prioritize obtaining informed consent from citizens for data collection and usage. They also focus on providing transparent information about how data is handled. For instance, a tax authority may allow citizens to manage their consent preferences for sharing tax-related data with other government agencies, ensuring control and transparency over personal information.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data breach response and incident management: Public sector organizations need to be prepared for data breaches and incidents. The Data Ethics capability includes establishing protocols for timely response, notification, and mitigation of such events. For example, a local government may have a well-defined incident response plan to handle a cybersecurity breach, ensuring minimal impact on citizen data and privacy.&#xA;&#xA;These examples demonstrate how the Data Ethics Digital Business Capability in the public sector ensures responsible and ethical handling of data while leveraging digital technologies to deliver efficient and citizen-centric services."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Data Ethics Digital Business Capability refers to the organization's ability to establish and maintain ethical practices and principles related to the collection, storage, processing, and usage of data. It encompasses the policies, procedures, and frameworks that ensure the responsible and ethical handling of data throughout its lifecycle.&#xA;&#xA;This capability involves understanding and adhering to legal and regulatory requirements, industry standards, and best practices concerning data privacy, security, consent, transparency, and accountability. It aims to protect individuals' rights and interests while enabling the organization to leverage data effectively for business purposes.&#xA;&#xA;Key components of the Data Ethics Digital Business Capability include:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Governance: This involves establishing a framework for data management, including defining roles, responsibilities, and processes for data handling. It ensures that data is collected, stored, and used in compliance with applicable laws and regulations.&#xA;&#xA;2. Privacy and Consent Management: This component focuses on obtaining appropriate consent from individuals for data collection and processing activities. It includes implementing mechanisms to manage and respect individuals' privacy rights, such as providing clear and transparent privacy notices and enabling individuals to exercise their rights over their data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Data Security: This component encompasses measures to protect data from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. It involves implementing robust security controls, encryption, access controls, and monitoring mechanisms to safeguard data against potential threats and breaches.&#xA;&#xA;4. Ethical Data Use: This component emphasizes the responsible and ethical use of data. It involves establishing guidelines and policies for data usage, ensuring that data is used only for legitimate business purposes and in a manner that respects individuals' rights and interests.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Transparency and Accountability: This component focuses on promoting transparency and accountability in data practices. It includes providing individuals with clear information about how their data is being used, enabling them to make informed choices. It also involves establishing mechanisms for individuals to access, rectify, or delete their data and addressing any concerns or complaints related to data handling.&#xA;&#xA;6. Training and Awareness: This component emphasizes the importance of educating employees about data ethics and their responsibilities in handling data. It includes providing training programs, awareness campaigns, and resources to ensure that employees understand and adhere to ethical data practices.&#xA;&#xA;7. Continuous Improvement: This component involves regularly reviewing and updating data ethics practices to align with evolving legal, regulatory, and industry requirements. It includes conducting audits, assessments, and risk evaluations to identify areas for improvement and implementing necessary changes to enhance data ethics capabilities.&#xA;&#xA;By developing and maintaining the Data Ethics Digital Business Capability, organizations can build trust with their customers, partners, and stakeholders. It helps them mitigate risks associated with data breaches, regulatory non-compliance, and reputational damage while fostering a culture of responsible data handling and ethical decision-making."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DataEthicsCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
