<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Lineage"
    id="id-965a3905e22649459330ee9366f3a78b"
    documentation="Source: EIRA Team&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to track and trace the origin, movement, and transformation of data throughout its lifecycle. It involves capturing and documenting the lineage of data elements, including their sources, transformations, and destinations. This capability enables organizations to understand the data flow across systems, processes, and applications, ensuring data quality, compliance, and effective decision-making. It also helps in identifying data dependencies, impact analysis, and troubleshooting data-related issues. Overall, the Data Lineage Digital Business Capability provides transparency and visibility into the data ecosystem, facilitating effective data governance and management.&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to track and trace the origin, movement, and transformation of data throughout its lifecycle. It involves capturing and documenting the lineage of data elements, including their sources, transformations, and destinations, to ensure data quality, compliance, and understanding.&#xA;&#xA;Data lineage provides a comprehensive view of how data flows through various systems, processes, and applications within an organization. It helps in understanding the data's journey, identifying potential bottlenecks, and ensuring data integrity and accuracy. This capability enables organizations to answer critical questions about data, such as where it comes from, how it is transformed, and where it goes.&#xA;&#xA;The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability encompasses several key components and activities:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Source Identification: This involves identifying the original sources of data, whether it is internal or external to the organization. It includes understanding the systems, databases, files, or APIs that generate or provide data.&#xA;&#xA;2. Data Transformation Mapping: This component focuses on documenting the transformations applied to data as it moves through different processes, systems, or applications. It includes capturing the rules, algorithms, or logic used to modify or manipulate the data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Data Destination Tracking: This aspect involves tracking the final destinations of data, such as databases, reports, dashboards, or other systems. It ensures that data reaches the intended targets and helps in identifying any potential gaps or inconsistencies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Metadata Management: Metadata, which provides additional context and information about data, plays a crucial role in data lineage. This component involves managing and maintaining metadata repositories, including data dictionaries, data catalogs, and data models.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Lineage Visualization: Visualizing data lineage helps stakeholders understand the flow of data across systems and processes. It may include graphical representations, diagrams, or interactive tools that depict the relationships and dependencies between data elements.&#xA;&#xA;6. Impact Analysis: Data lineage enables impact analysis by identifying the potential consequences of changes to data sources, transformations, or destinations. It helps in assessing the impact on downstream systems, processes, and reports, facilitating effective change management.&#xA;&#xA;7. Compliance and Audit: Data lineage is essential for regulatory compliance and audit purposes. It enables organizations to demonstrate data lineage to regulatory bodies, ensuring data governance, privacy, and security requirements are met.&#xA;&#xA;8. Data Quality Monitoring: Data lineage supports data quality initiatives by providing insights into the data's journey and identifying potential quality issues. It helps in establishing data quality metrics, monitoring data quality, and implementing corrective actions.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Data Lineage Digital Business Capability is a critical aspect of data management and governance. It enables organizations to have a holistic view of their data assets, understand data flows, ensure data integrity, comply with regulations, and make informed decisions based on trustworthy and reliable data.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to the ability to track and understand the origin, movement, and transformation of data throughout its lifecycle. This capability is crucial for ensuring data quality, compliance, and decision-making. Here are some real examples of how this capability is applied in the public sector:&#xA;&#xA;1. Tax Compliance: In tax administration, data lineage is used to trace the flow of financial data from taxpayers' records to tax returns and subsequent reports. This capability helps auditors and tax authorities verify the accuracy and integrity of the data, ensuring compliance with tax regulations.&#xA;&#xA;2. Fraud Detection: Government agencies responsible for detecting and preventing fraud, such as social welfare fraud or tax evasion, utilize data lineage to track the flow of data across various systems and processes. By analyzing the lineage, anomalies or suspicious patterns can be identified, leading to the detection of fraudulent activities.&#xA;&#xA;3. Public Health Monitoring: Data lineage is crucial in public health monitoring, especially during disease outbreaks or pandemics. It helps track the origin and movement of patient data, test results, and contact tracing information. This capability enables health authorities to identify the source of infection, track the spread of the disease, and make informed decisions for containment and mitigation.&#xA;&#xA;4. Government Performance Reporting: Data lineage is used to ensure the accuracy and reliability of performance reports generated by government agencies. By tracing the data sources, transformations, and calculations involved in generating these reports, data lineage helps maintain transparency, accountability, and trust in the reported performance metrics.&#xA;&#xA;5. Freedom of Information Requests: Public sector organizations often receive requests for information under the Freedom of Information Act or similar legislation. Data lineage helps track the data sources, systems, and processes involved in generating the requested information. This capability ensures that the information provided is accurate, complete, and can be audited if necessary.&#xA;&#xA;These examples demonstrate how the Data Lineage Digital Business Capability is applied in the public sector to ensure data quality, compliance, and informed decision-making.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataLineageCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DataLineageCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataLineageCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Lineage Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataLineageCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataLineageCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Lineage Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to track and trace the origin, movement, and transformation of data throughout its lifecycle. It involves capturing and documenting the lineage of data elements, including their sources, transformations, and destinations. This capability enables organizations to understand the data flow across systems, processes, and applications, ensuring data quality, compliance, and effective decision-making. It also helps in identifying data dependencies, impact analysis, and troubleshooting data-related issues. Overall, the Data Lineage Digital Business Capability provides transparency and visibility into the data ecosystem, facilitating effective data governance and management."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability in the public sector refers to the ability to track and understand the origin, movement, and transformation of data throughout its lifecycle. This capability is crucial for ensuring data quality, compliance, and decision-making. Here are some real examples of how this capability is applied in the public sector:&#xA;&#xA;1. Tax Compliance: In tax administration, data lineage is used to trace the flow of financial data from taxpayers' records to tax returns and subsequent reports. This capability helps auditors and tax authorities verify the accuracy and integrity of the data, ensuring compliance with tax regulations.&#xA;&#xA;2. Fraud Detection: Government agencies responsible for detecting and preventing fraud, such as social welfare fraud or tax evasion, utilize data lineage to track the flow of data across various systems and processes. By analyzing the lineage, anomalies or suspicious patterns can be identified, leading to the detection of fraudulent activities.&#xA;&#xA;3. Public Health Monitoring: Data lineage is crucial in public health monitoring, especially during disease outbreaks or pandemics. It helps track the origin and movement of patient data, test results, and contact tracing information. This capability enables health authorities to identify the source of infection, track the spread of the disease, and make informed decisions for containment and mitigation.&#xA;&#xA;4. Government Performance Reporting: Data lineage is used to ensure the accuracy and reliability of performance reports generated by government agencies. By tracing the data sources, transformations, and calculations involved in generating these reports, data lineage helps maintain transparency, accountability, and trust in the reported performance metrics.&#xA;&#xA;5. Freedom of Information Requests: Public sector organizations often receive requests for information under the Freedom of Information Act or similar legislation. Data lineage helps track the data sources, systems, and processes involved in generating the requested information. This capability ensures that the information provided is accurate, complete, and can be audited if necessary.&#xA;&#xA;These examples demonstrate how the Data Lineage Digital Business Capability is applied in the public sector to ensure data quality, compliance, and informed decision-making."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability refers to the ability of an organization to track and trace the origin, movement, and transformation of data throughout its lifecycle. It involves capturing and documenting the lineage of data elements, including their sources, transformations, and destinations, to ensure data quality, compliance, and understanding.&#xA;&#xA;Data lineage provides a comprehensive view of how data flows through various systems, processes, and applications within an organization. It helps in understanding the data's journey, identifying potential bottlenecks, and ensuring data integrity and accuracy. This capability enables organizations to answer critical questions about data, such as where it comes from, how it is transformed, and where it goes.&#xA;&#xA;The Data Lineage Digital Business Capability encompasses several key components and activities:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Source Identification: This involves identifying the original sources of data, whether it is internal or external to the organization. It includes understanding the systems, databases, files, or APIs that generate or provide data.&#xA;&#xA;2. Data Transformation Mapping: This component focuses on documenting the transformations applied to data as it moves through different processes, systems, or applications. It includes capturing the rules, algorithms, or logic used to modify or manipulate the data.&#xA;&#xA;3. Data Destination Tracking: This aspect involves tracking the final destinations of data, such as databases, reports, dashboards, or other systems. It ensures that data reaches the intended targets and helps in identifying any potential gaps or inconsistencies.&#xA;&#xA;4. Metadata Management: Metadata, which provides additional context and information about data, plays a crucial role in data lineage. This component involves managing and maintaining metadata repositories, including data dictionaries, data catalogs, and data models.&#xA;&#xA;5. Data Lineage Visualization: Visualizing data lineage helps stakeholders understand the flow of data across systems and processes. It may include graphical representations, diagrams, or interactive tools that depict the relationships and dependencies between data elements.&#xA;&#xA;6. Impact Analysis: Data lineage enables impact analysis by identifying the potential consequences of changes to data sources, transformations, or destinations. It helps in assessing the impact on downstream systems, processes, and reports, facilitating effective change management.&#xA;&#xA;7. Compliance and Audit: Data lineage is essential for regulatory compliance and audit purposes. It enables organizations to demonstrate data lineage to regulatory bodies, ensuring data governance, privacy, and security requirements are met.&#xA;&#xA;8. Data Quality Monitoring: Data lineage supports data quality initiatives by providing insights into the data's journey and identifying potential quality issues. It helps in establishing data quality metrics, monitoring data quality, and implementing corrective actions.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the Data Lineage Digital Business Capability is a critical aspect of data management and governance. It enables organizations to have a holistic view of their data assets, understand data flows, ensure data integrity, comply with regulations, and make informed decisions based on trustworthy and reliable data."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="EIRA Team"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DataLineageCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
