<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Digital Invoicing"
    id="id-0686a2e0fdc341529fb19d916c4edad8"
    documentation="Definition: Digital Invoicing enables the issuing, transmission and delivery of electronic invoice documents in a structured data format between a public administration and its providers/suppliers. Digital Invoicing ensures data security and privacy, and automatic and electronic processing of invoices.&#xA;&#xA;Source: VISMA&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwirzIiIoN71AhXUNuwKHdm0CPQQFnoECCcQAw&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.visma.com%2Fcloud-adoption%2Fdigital-invoicing%2F%23%3A~%3Atext%3DDigital%2520invoicing%2520is%2520a%2520modernised%2Cwith%2520sending%2520and%2520receiving%2520invoices.%26text%3DIf%2520the%2520customer%2520is%2520set%2Cbank%252C%2520it%2520will%2520go%2520there.&amp;usg=AOvVaw23medh_UhBwEQRubS8azep&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability (DIDBC) is a crucial component of the European Union's efforts to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies in the context of invoicing processes. It aims to streamline and digitize the invoicing procedures, promoting efficiency, cost-effectiveness, and environmental sustainability.&#xA;&#xA;The DIDBC encompasses a set of standardized electronic invoicing practices, protocols, and technologies that facilitate the exchange of invoices between businesses, public administrations, and consumers across the European Union. It provides a common framework for the creation, transmission, receipt, and archiving of digital invoices, ensuring their authenticity, integrity, and legal compliance.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the DIDBC promotes the use of structured electronic invoice formats, such as the Universal Business Language (UBL) or the Cross-Industry Invoice (CII), which enable the seamless exchange of invoice data between different software systems. These formats ensure that invoices can be easily processed, validated, and integrated into the recipient's financial management systems, eliminating the need for manual data entry and reducing errors.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the DIDBC encourages the adoption of electronic signatures and electronic identification methods, such as the European eIDAS regulation, to ensure the authenticity and integrity of digital invoices. These mechanisms provide legal certainty and enable cross-border recognition of electronic invoices, eliminating the need for paper-based documentation and physical signatures.&#xA;&#xA;To facilitate the implementation of the DIDBC, the European Union has established a set of technical specifications, guidelines, and best practices. These resources assist member states and private companies in aligning their invoicing processes with the European standard, ensuring interoperability and seamless cross-border exchange of invoices.&#xA;&#xA;The benefits of the DIDBC are manifold. Firstly, it significantly reduces the administrative burden associated with traditional paper-based invoicing, leading to cost savings for businesses and public administrations. It also enhances the speed and accuracy of invoice processing, enabling faster payment cycles and improving cash flow management.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the DIDBC promotes environmental sustainability by reducing paper consumption and the associated carbon footprint. It also fosters a more transparent and accountable business environment, as digital invoices leave a clear audit trail and are less prone to manipulation or fraud.&#xA;&#xA;The European Union has been actively promoting the adoption of the DIDBC among member states and private companies. It has provided financial support, technical assistance, and capacity-building programs to facilitate the transition from paper-based to digital invoicing. Additionally, the EU has established a European eInvoicing Service Providers List, which serves as a trusted directory of service providers offering compliant e-invoicing solutions.&#xA;&#xA;In conclusion, the Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability plays a vital role in enhancing IT interoperability within the European Union. By promoting standardized electronic invoicing practices, it streamlines invoicing processes, reduces costs, improves efficiency, and contributes to a more sustainable and transparent business environment.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The application of Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can have several examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Cross-border e-invoicing: Digital invoicing enables seamless cross-border transactions between member states and private companies. It allows businesses to send and receive invoices electronically, eliminating the need for paper-based processes. This streamlines the invoicing process, reduces errors, and improves efficiency in cross-border trade.&#xA;&#xA;2. Standardization of invoice formats: Digital invoicing promotes the use of standardized invoice formats, such as the European standard EN16931. This ensures that invoices are structured uniformly across member states and private companies, facilitating interoperability and enabling automated processing of invoices.&#xA;&#xA;3. Integration with accounting systems: Digital invoicing capabilities can be integrated with accounting systems used by member states and private companies. This integration enables automatic transfer of invoice data into accounting software, reducing manual data entry and improving accuracy. It also enables real-time tracking of invoices, payment status, and financial reporting.&#xA;&#xA;4. Compliance with legal and regulatory requirements: Digital invoicing capabilities ensure compliance with legal and regulatory requirements across member states. For example, the European Directive on e-invoicing (2014/55/EU) mandates the use of electronic invoicing in public procurement. Digital invoicing solutions help businesses adhere to these requirements, ensuring smooth interoperability between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;5. Interoperability platforms: Digital invoicing capabilities can be facilitated through interoperability platforms that connect member states and private companies. These platforms act as intermediaries, enabling seamless exchange of electronic invoices, regardless of the technical systems used by different entities. They provide a common framework for interoperability, ensuring smooth communication and data exchange.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability in European IT interoperability among member states and private companies enhances efficiency, reduces costs, and promotes seamless cross-border trade.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInvoicingCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DigitalInvoicingCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInvoicingCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInvoicingCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DigitalInvoicingCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Digital Invoicing enables the issuing, transmission and delivery of electronic invoice documents in a structured data format between a public administration and its providers/suppliers. Digital Invoicing ensures data security and privacy, and automatic and electronic processing of invoices."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The application of Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can have several examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Cross-border e-invoicing: Digital invoicing enables seamless cross-border transactions between member states and private companies. It allows businesses to send and receive invoices electronically, eliminating the need for paper-based processes. This streamlines the invoicing process, reduces errors, and improves efficiency in cross-border trade.&#xA;&#xA;2. Standardization of invoice formats: Digital invoicing promotes the use of standardized invoice formats, such as the European standard EN16931. This ensures that invoices are structured uniformly across member states and private companies, facilitating interoperability and enabling automated processing of invoices.&#xA;&#xA;3. Integration with accounting systems: Digital invoicing capabilities can be integrated with accounting systems used by member states and private companies. This integration enables automatic transfer of invoice data into accounting software, reducing manual data entry and improving accuracy. It also enables real-time tracking of invoices, payment status, and financial reporting.&#xA;&#xA;4. Compliance with legal and regulatory requirements: Digital invoicing capabilities ensure compliance with legal and regulatory requirements across member states. For example, the European Directive on e-invoicing (2014/55/EU) mandates the use of electronic invoicing in public procurement. Digital invoicing solutions help businesses adhere to these requirements, ensuring smooth interoperability between member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;5. Interoperability platforms: Digital invoicing capabilities can be facilitated through interoperability platforms that connect member states and private companies. These platforms act as intermediaries, enabling seamless exchange of electronic invoices, regardless of the technical systems used by different entities. They provide a common framework for interoperability, ensuring smooth communication and data exchange.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability in European IT interoperability among member states and private companies enhances efficiency, reduces costs, and promotes seamless cross-border trade."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability (DIDBC) is a crucial component of the European Union's efforts to enhance IT interoperability among member states and private companies in the context of invoicing processes. It aims to streamline and digitize the invoicing procedures, promoting efficiency, cost-effectiveness, and environmental sustainability.&#xA;&#xA;The DIDBC encompasses a set of standardized electronic invoicing practices, protocols, and technologies that facilitate the exchange of invoices between businesses, public administrations, and consumers across the European Union. It provides a common framework for the creation, transmission, receipt, and archiving of digital invoices, ensuring their authenticity, integrity, and legal compliance.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the DIDBC promotes the use of structured electronic invoice formats, such as the Universal Business Language (UBL) or the Cross-Industry Invoice (CII), which enable the seamless exchange of invoice data between different software systems. These formats ensure that invoices can be easily processed, validated, and integrated into the recipient's financial management systems, eliminating the need for manual data entry and reducing errors.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the DIDBC encourages the adoption of electronic signatures and electronic identification methods, such as the European eIDAS regulation, to ensure the authenticity and integrity of digital invoices. These mechanisms provide legal certainty and enable cross-border recognition of electronic invoices, eliminating the need for paper-based documentation and physical signatures.&#xA;&#xA;To facilitate the implementation of the DIDBC, the European Union has established a set of technical specifications, guidelines, and best practices. These resources assist member states and private companies in aligning their invoicing processes with the European standard, ensuring interoperability and seamless cross-border exchange of invoices.&#xA;&#xA;The benefits of the DIDBC are manifold. Firstly, it significantly reduces the administrative burden associated with traditional paper-based invoicing, leading to cost savings for businesses and public administrations. It also enhances the speed and accuracy of invoice processing, enabling faster payment cycles and improving cash flow management.&#xA;&#xA;Moreover, the DIDBC promotes environmental sustainability by reducing paper consumption and the associated carbon footprint. It also fosters a more transparent and accountable business environment, as digital invoices leave a clear audit trail and are less prone to manipulation or fraud.&#xA;&#xA;The European Union has been actively promoting the adoption of the DIDBC among member states and private companies. It has provided financial support, technical assistance, and capacity-building programs to facilitate the transition from paper-based to digital invoicing. Additionally, the EU has established a European eInvoicing Service Providers List, which serves as a trusted directory of service providers offering compliant e-invoicing solutions.&#xA;&#xA;In conclusion, the Digital Invoicing Digital Business Capability plays a vital role in enhancing IT interoperability within the European Union. By promoting standardized electronic invoicing practices, it streamlines invoicing processes, reduces costs, improves efficiency, and contributes to a more sustainable and transparent business environment."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="VISMA"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwirzIiIoN71AhXUNuwKHdm0CPQQFnoECCcQAw&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.visma.com%2Fcloud-adoption%2Fdigital-invoicing%2F%23%3A~%3Atext%3DDigital%2520invoicing%2520is%2520a%2520modernised%2Cwith%2520sending%2520and%2520receiving%2520invoices.%26text%3DIf%2520the%2520customer%2520is%2520set%2Cbank%252C%2520it%2520will%2520go%2520there.&amp;usg=AOvVaw23medh_UhBwEQRubS8azep"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DigitalInvoicingCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
