<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Electronic Identification"
    id="id-ee99cfb9b35e4ceba67458ad9e82bca8"
    documentation="Definition: Electronic Identification ensures secure access to online services and to carry out electronic transactions in a safer way to citizens or organizations (i.e. public administrations and businesses). Via digital modes, electronic identification can guarantee the unambiguous identification of a person or business and ensures the right service is delivered to the person or business entitled to it. (e.g. government authorities services, digital payments services, ...).&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/electronic-identification&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Electronic Identification (eID) Digital Business Capability is a crucial component of the European Union's efforts to establish seamless interoperability among member states and private companies in the field of information technology. It aims to provide a standardized and secure framework for electronic identification and authentication across borders, enabling individuals and businesses to access digital services and conduct transactions in a trusted and efficient manner.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the eID Digital Business Capability revolves around the concept of a digital identity, which serves as a virtual representation of an individual or organization. This digital identity is securely stored and managed by trusted entities, such as government agencies or private service providers, and can be used to establish the identity of the user in various online interactions.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of the eID Digital Business Capability is to enable individuals and businesses to use their digital identities to access a wide range of services, both public and private, across different member states. This includes services such as e-government platforms, online banking, e-commerce, healthcare systems, and more. By providing a standardized and interoperable framework, the capability ensures that users can seamlessly authenticate themselves and access these services regardless of their location within the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve this interoperability, the eID Digital Business Capability relies on a set of technical standards and protocols that enable the secure exchange of identity information between different systems and entities. These standards ensure that digital identities issued by one member state or private entity can be recognized and accepted by others, thereby facilitating cross-border transactions and interactions.&#xA;&#xA;The capability also encompasses the establishment of a network of trust among member states and private entities. This network ensures that the digital identities issued by one entity are trusted and accepted by others, thereby enhancing the overall security and reliability of the system. This trust network is built upon the principles of mutual recognition, where member states and private entities agree to accept and recognize each other's digital identities based on predefined criteria and standards.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the eID Digital Business Capability places a strong emphasis on privacy and data protection. It ensures that individuals have control over their personal data and can consent to its use for specific purposes. The capability also incorporates mechanisms for secure authentication, such as two-factor authentication or biometric verification, to enhance the overall security of digital transactions.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the eID Digital Business Capability is a comprehensive framework that aims to establish seamless interoperability among member states and private companies in the European Union. It enables individuals and businesses to use their digital identities to access a wide range of services across borders, while ensuring privacy, security, and trust in the digital ecosystem.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The Electronic Identification (eID) Digital Business Capability has several applications in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies. Here are some examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Cross-border authentication: eID enables individuals to use their national electronic identification credentials to access online services in other member states. This allows for seamless authentication and access to various services, such as e-government portals, banking, healthcare, and more.&#xA;&#xA;2. Digital signatures and document exchange: eID facilitates the use of digital signatures for secure and legally binding transactions across borders. It enables individuals and businesses to digitally sign documents, contracts, and forms, eliminating the need for physical paperwork and enabling efficient cross-border document exchange.&#xA;&#xA;3. Trusted e-commerce: eID can be used to establish trust in online transactions between businesses and consumers across different member states. It allows for secure identification and authentication of individuals, reducing the risk of fraud and enhancing consumer confidence in cross-border e-commerce.&#xA;&#xA;4. Seamless access to public services: eID enables citizens to access public services in other member states without the need for additional identification procedures. For example, a citizen from one member state can use their eID to access healthcare services or file taxes in another member state, simplifying administrative processes and enhancing cross-border service delivery.&#xA;&#xA;5. Interoperable electronic invoicing: eID can be integrated with electronic invoicing systems to ensure secure and interoperable exchange of invoices between businesses across member states. This streamlines cross-border invoicing processes, reduces administrative burdens, and enhances efficiency in business transactions.&#xA;&#xA;6. Secure data sharing: eID can facilitate secure and controlled sharing of personal data between member states and private companies. It ensures that data is accessed only by authorized individuals or organizations, maintaining privacy and data protection standards while enabling efficient cross-border data exchange for various purposes, such as research, public administration, or business collaborations.&#xA;&#xA;These examples highlight how the application of eID as a digital business capability contributes to European IT interoperability, enabling seamless cross-border transactions, secure data exchange, and efficient access to services across member states and private companies.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ElectronicIdentificationCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:ElectronicIdentificationCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ElectronicIdentificationCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Electronic Identification Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ElectronicIdentificationCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/ElectronicIdentificationCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Electronic Identification Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Electronic Identification ensures secure access to online services and to carry out electronic transactions in a safer way to citizens or organizations (i.e. public administrations and businesses). Via digital modes, electronic identification can guarantee the unambiguous identification of a person or business and ensures the right service is delivered to the person or business entitled to it. (e.g. government authorities services, digital payments services, ...)."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The Electronic Identification (eID) Digital Business Capability has several applications in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies. Here are some examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Cross-border authentication: eID enables individuals to use their national electronic identification credentials to access online services in other member states. This allows for seamless authentication and access to various services, such as e-government portals, banking, healthcare, and more.&#xA;&#xA;2. Digital signatures and document exchange: eID facilitates the use of digital signatures for secure and legally binding transactions across borders. It enables individuals and businesses to digitally sign documents, contracts, and forms, eliminating the need for physical paperwork and enabling efficient cross-border document exchange.&#xA;&#xA;3. Trusted e-commerce: eID can be used to establish trust in online transactions between businesses and consumers across different member states. It allows for secure identification and authentication of individuals, reducing the risk of fraud and enhancing consumer confidence in cross-border e-commerce.&#xA;&#xA;4. Seamless access to public services: eID enables citizens to access public services in other member states without the need for additional identification procedures. For example, a citizen from one member state can use their eID to access healthcare services or file taxes in another member state, simplifying administrative processes and enhancing cross-border service delivery.&#xA;&#xA;5. Interoperable electronic invoicing: eID can be integrated with electronic invoicing systems to ensure secure and interoperable exchange of invoices between businesses across member states. This streamlines cross-border invoicing processes, reduces administrative burdens, and enhances efficiency in business transactions.&#xA;&#xA;6. Secure data sharing: eID can facilitate secure and controlled sharing of personal data between member states and private companies. It ensures that data is accessed only by authorized individuals or organizations, maintaining privacy and data protection standards while enabling efficient cross-border data exchange for various purposes, such as research, public administration, or business collaborations.&#xA;&#xA;These examples highlight how the application of eID as a digital business capability contributes to European IT interoperability, enabling seamless cross-border transactions, secure data exchange, and efficient access to services across member states and private companies."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Electronic Identification (eID) Digital Business Capability is a crucial component of the European Union's efforts to establish seamless interoperability among member states and private companies in the field of information technology. It aims to provide a standardized and secure framework for electronic identification and authentication across borders, enabling individuals and businesses to access digital services and conduct transactions in a trusted and efficient manner.&#xA;&#xA;At its core, the eID Digital Business Capability revolves around the concept of a digital identity, which serves as a virtual representation of an individual or organization. This digital identity is securely stored and managed by trusted entities, such as government agencies or private service providers, and can be used to establish the identity of the user in various online interactions.&#xA;&#xA;The primary objective of the eID Digital Business Capability is to enable individuals and businesses to use their digital identities to access a wide range of services, both public and private, across different member states. This includes services such as e-government platforms, online banking, e-commerce, healthcare systems, and more. By providing a standardized and interoperable framework, the capability ensures that users can seamlessly authenticate themselves and access these services regardless of their location within the European Union.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve this interoperability, the eID Digital Business Capability relies on a set of technical standards and protocols that enable the secure exchange of identity information between different systems and entities. These standards ensure that digital identities issued by one member state or private entity can be recognized and accepted by others, thereby facilitating cross-border transactions and interactions.&#xA;&#xA;The capability also encompasses the establishment of a network of trust among member states and private entities. This network ensures that the digital identities issued by one entity are trusted and accepted by others, thereby enhancing the overall security and reliability of the system. This trust network is built upon the principles of mutual recognition, where member states and private entities agree to accept and recognize each other's digital identities based on predefined criteria and standards.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, the eID Digital Business Capability places a strong emphasis on privacy and data protection. It ensures that individuals have control over their personal data and can consent to its use for specific purposes. The capability also incorporates mechanisms for secure authentication, such as two-factor authentication or biometric verification, to enhance the overall security of digital transactions.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the eID Digital Business Capability is a comprehensive framework that aims to establish seamless interoperability among member states and private companies in the European Union. It enables individuals and businesses to use their digital identities to access a wide range of services across borders, while ensuring privacy, security, and trust in the digital ecosystem."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/electronic-identification"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:ElectronicIdentificationCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
