<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Management"
    id="id-74e2831bba4c4619882a006f3f514210"
    documentation="Definition: Data Management is the development, execution, and supervision of plans, policies, prograns, and practices that deliver, control, protect, and enhance the value of data and information assets throughout their lifecycles.&#xA;&#xA;Source: DAMA&#xA;&#xA;Source reference: https://damadach.org/dmbok2-dama-dmbok-version-2/&#xA;&#xA;Additional information: The Data Management Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies refers to the ability to effectively and efficiently handle data in a digital environment while ensuring seamless communication, collaboration, and integration between various entities.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Union, where multiple member states and private companies operate, it is crucial to establish a robust data management capability to facilitate interoperability. This capability encompasses various aspects, including data governance, data quality, data integration, data security, and data analytics.&#xA;&#xA;Data governance involves defining policies, procedures, and guidelines for managing data across different entities. It includes establishing data standards, ensuring compliance with regulations such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and defining roles and responsibilities for data management.&#xA;&#xA;Data quality focuses on ensuring that data is accurate, complete, consistent, and reliable. It involves implementing data validation processes, data cleansing techniques, and data profiling to identify and rectify any inconsistencies or errors in the data.&#xA;&#xA;Data integration is a critical aspect of interoperability, as it involves combining data from different sources and formats to provide a unified view. This capability enables seamless data exchange between member states and private companies, allowing them to share information and collaborate effectively. It may involve implementing data integration technologies such as application programming interfaces (APIs), data warehouses, or data lakes.&#xA;&#xA;Data security is of paramount importance in the digital business environment, especially when dealing with sensitive information. It involves implementing robust security measures, such as encryption, access controls, and data masking, to protect data from unauthorized access, breaches, or misuse. Compliance with data protection regulations, such as GDPR, is essential to ensure the privacy and security of personal data.&#xA;&#xA;Data analytics plays a crucial role in extracting valuable insights from the vast amount of data generated. It involves using advanced analytics techniques, such as data mining, machine learning, and artificial intelligence, to analyze data and derive meaningful patterns, trends, and predictions. This capability enables member states and private companies to make informed decisions, optimize processes, and drive innovation.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve effective data management digital business capability for European IT interoperability, collaboration and standardization are key. Member states and private companies need to establish common data models, formats, and protocols to ensure seamless data exchange. They should also promote the use of interoperability frameworks, such as the European Interoperability Framework (EIF), which provides guidelines and best practices for achieving interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, investing in modern technologies and infrastructure, such as cloud computing, big data platforms, and data governance tools, can significantly enhance the data management capability. Training and upskilling the workforce in data management and analytics are also crucial to ensure the successful implementation and utilization of the capability.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Data Management Digital Business Capability for European IT interoperability among member states and private companies encompasses various aspects of data governance, data quality, data integration, data security, and data analytics. It aims to establish a robust and standardized approach to managing data, enabling seamless communication, collaboration, and integration in the digital business environment.&#xA;&#xA;Example: The application of Data Management Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can be seen in various ways. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Sharing and Exchange: The capability enables member states and private companies to securely share and exchange data across borders. For instance, in the healthcare sector, interoperability allows patient data to be seamlessly shared between different healthcare providers, ensuring continuity of care for patients who may seek treatment in different countries.&#xA;&#xA;2. Harmonization of Data Standards: Data Management Digital Business Capability helps in establishing common data standards and formats, ensuring consistency and compatibility between different IT systems used by member states and private companies. This harmonization facilitates smooth data exchange and integration, reducing barriers to interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;3. Cross-Border Data Governance: The capability assists in defining and implementing cross-border data governance frameworks, including data protection and privacy regulations. This ensures that data is managed and protected in a consistent and compliant manner across member states and private companies, fostering trust and confidence in data sharing.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data Integration and Analytics: Interoperability allows for the integration of data from various sources, enabling advanced analytics and insights. For example, in the transportation sector, interoperability enables the integration of data from different transport systems, leading to better traffic management, optimized routes, and improved passenger experience.&#xA;&#xA;5. Cross-Domain Collaboration: Data Management Digital Business Capability facilitates collaboration between member states and private companies across different domains. For instance, in the energy sector, interoperability enables the integration of data from renewable energy sources, grid operators, and consumers, supporting efficient energy management and promoting the use of sustainable energy.&#xA;&#xA;6. Real-time Data Exchange: Interoperability enables real-time data exchange between member states and private companies, allowing for timely decision-making and response. This is particularly crucial in emergency situations, where quick access to accurate data can help in coordinating response efforts and minimizing the impact of disasters.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Data Management Digital Business Capability in European IT interoperability among member states and private companies enhances data sharing, standardization, governance, integration, and collaboration, leading to improved efficiency, innovation, and cross-border cooperation.&#xA;&#xA;LOST view: Organisational view&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataManagementCapability&#xA;&#xA;ABB name: eira:DataManagementCapability&#xA;&#xA;EIRA concept: eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock&#xA;&#xA;Last modification: 2024-01-28&#xA;&#xA;Identifier: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataManagementCapability&#xA;&#xA;Name: Data Management Digital Business Capability&#xA;&#xA;Interoperability Layer: Organisational&#xA;&#xA;Specialises: http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability&#xA;&#xA;">
  <properties
      key="eira:PURI"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataManagementCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:modified"
      value="2024-01-28"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:identifier"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/egovera/DataManagementCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:title"
      value="Data Management Digital Business Capability"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:definition"
      value="Data Management is the development, execution, and supervision of plans, policies, prograns, and practices that deliver, control, protect, and enhance the value of data and information assets throughout their lifecycles."/>
  <properties
      key="skos:example"
      value="The application of Data Management Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies can be seen in various ways. Here are a few examples:&#xA;&#xA;1. Data Sharing and Exchange: The capability enables member states and private companies to securely share and exchange data across borders. For instance, in the healthcare sector, interoperability allows patient data to be seamlessly shared between different healthcare providers, ensuring continuity of care for patients who may seek treatment in different countries.&#xA;&#xA;2. Harmonization of Data Standards: Data Management Digital Business Capability helps in establishing common data standards and formats, ensuring consistency and compatibility between different IT systems used by member states and private companies. This harmonization facilitates smooth data exchange and integration, reducing barriers to interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;3. Cross-Border Data Governance: The capability assists in defining and implementing cross-border data governance frameworks, including data protection and privacy regulations. This ensures that data is managed and protected in a consistent and compliant manner across member states and private companies, fostering trust and confidence in data sharing.&#xA;&#xA;4. Data Integration and Analytics: Interoperability allows for the integration of data from various sources, enabling advanced analytics and insights. For example, in the transportation sector, interoperability enables the integration of data from different transport systems, leading to better traffic management, optimized routes, and improved passenger experience.&#xA;&#xA;5. Cross-Domain Collaboration: Data Management Digital Business Capability facilitates collaboration between member states and private companies across different domains. For instance, in the energy sector, interoperability enables the integration of data from renewable energy sources, grid operators, and consumers, supporting efficient energy management and promoting the use of sustainable energy.&#xA;&#xA;6. Real-time Data Exchange: Interoperability enables real-time data exchange between member states and private companies, allowing for timely decision-making and response. This is particularly crucial in emergency situations, where quick access to accurate data can help in coordinating response efforts and minimizing the impact of disasters.&#xA;&#xA;Overall, the application of Data Management Digital Business Capability in European IT interoperability among member states and private companies enhances data sharing, standardization, governance, integration, and collaboration, leading to improved efficiency, innovation, and cross-border cooperation."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:concept"
      value="eira:ArchitectureBuildingBlock"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:note"
      value="The Data Management Digital Business Capability in the context of European IT interoperability among member states and private companies refers to the ability to effectively and efficiently handle data in a digital environment while ensuring seamless communication, collaboration, and integration between various entities.&#xA;&#xA;In the European Union, where multiple member states and private companies operate, it is crucial to establish a robust data management capability to facilitate interoperability. This capability encompasses various aspects, including data governance, data quality, data integration, data security, and data analytics.&#xA;&#xA;Data governance involves defining policies, procedures, and guidelines for managing data across different entities. It includes establishing data standards, ensuring compliance with regulations such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and defining roles and responsibilities for data management.&#xA;&#xA;Data quality focuses on ensuring that data is accurate, complete, consistent, and reliable. It involves implementing data validation processes, data cleansing techniques, and data profiling to identify and rectify any inconsistencies or errors in the data.&#xA;&#xA;Data integration is a critical aspect of interoperability, as it involves combining data from different sources and formats to provide a unified view. This capability enables seamless data exchange between member states and private companies, allowing them to share information and collaborate effectively. It may involve implementing data integration technologies such as application programming interfaces (APIs), data warehouses, or data lakes.&#xA;&#xA;Data security is of paramount importance in the digital business environment, especially when dealing with sensitive information. It involves implementing robust security measures, such as encryption, access controls, and data masking, to protect data from unauthorized access, breaches, or misuse. Compliance with data protection regulations, such as GDPR, is essential to ensure the privacy and security of personal data.&#xA;&#xA;Data analytics plays a crucial role in extracting valuable insights from the vast amount of data generated. It involves using advanced analytics techniques, such as data mining, machine learning, and artificial intelligence, to analyze data and derive meaningful patterns, trends, and predictions. This capability enables member states and private companies to make informed decisions, optimize processes, and drive innovation.&#xA;&#xA;To achieve effective data management digital business capability for European IT interoperability, collaboration and standardization are key. Member states and private companies need to establish common data models, formats, and protocols to ensure seamless data exchange. They should also promote the use of interoperability frameworks, such as the European Interoperability Framework (EIF), which provides guidelines and best practices for achieving interoperability.&#xA;&#xA;Furthermore, investing in modern technologies and infrastructure, such as cloud computing, big data platforms, and data governance tools, can significantly enhance the data management capability. Training and upskilling the workforce in data management and analytics are also crucial to ensure the successful implementation and utilization of the capability.&#xA;&#xA;In summary, the Data Management Digital Business Capability for European IT interoperability among member states and private companies encompasses various aspects of data governance, data quality, data integration, data security, and data analytics. It aims to establish a robust and standardized approach to managing data, enabling seamless communication, collaboration, and integration in the digital business environment."/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSource"
      value="DAMA"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:definitionSourceReference"
      value="https://damadach.org/dmbok2-dama-dmbok-version-2/"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:view"
      value="Organisational view"/>
  <properties
      key="eira:eifLayer"
      value="Organisational"/>
  <properties
      key="skos:broader"
      value="http://data.europa.eu/dr8/DigitalBusinessCapability"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="eira:DataManagementCapability"/>
</archimate:Capability>
